<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <query keywords="conference call for papers" position="4" lang="en" date="2011-10-12"/>
  <url>http://sibresearch.org/sibr-conference-call-for-paper.html</url>
  <title>SIBR Conference Call for Paper - Society of Interdisciplinary ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>The Society of Interdisciplinary Business Research (SIBR) Conference on Interdisciplinary Business Research invites submission of academic and professional </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Society of Interdisciplinary Business Research</s>
    <s>Honorary Advisor</s>
    <s>SIBR Working Papers</s>
    <s>SIBR Conference</s>
    <s>2012 Bangkok Conference</s>
    <s>Past Conference</s>
    <s>Online Submission</s>
    <s>Bangkok Venue</s>
    <s>Society of</s>
    <s>Business Research</s>
    <s>SIBR-Thammasat 2012 CONFERENCE</s>
    <s>BUSINESS &amp; ECONOMICS RESEARCH</s>
    <s>June 7th - 9th, 2012, Bangkok</s>
    <s>CALL FOR PAPERS</s>
    <s>Deadline of full paper/abstract submission: March 22nd, 2012</s>
    <s>*Click here for Tentative Program</s>
    <s>The SIBR 2012 Conference on Interdisciplinary Business &amp; Economics Research will be held from June 7th (Thursday) to June 9th (Saturday), 2012 at the Ambassador Hotel in Bangkok, Thailand. The conference theme is &quot;Implementing Interdisciplinarity Beyond Disciplinary Imperialism: Borrowing From Other Disciplines&quot;. The SIBR conference brings together academicians and professionals from various business and economics disciplines to share latest research findings and brainstorm new research ideas across disciplines. The SIBR Conference is a unique forum for academicians and professionals with cross-disciplinary interests to meet and interact with each other. Research papers using theoretical, quantitative, qualitative, or mixed-methods approaches are encouraged as are those using interdisciplinary approaches.</s>
    <s>Society of Interdisciplinary Business Research (SIBR) and Faculty of Economics, Thammasat University.</s>
    <s>CONFERENCE SCOPE</s>
    <s>(1) The SIBR Conference invites submission of academic and professional research papers/abstracts from the full range of business and economics disciplines, including Microeconomics, Macroeconomics, Financial Economics, Accounting and Economics, Organizational Behaviour, Marketing, Business Ethics, General Management, Strategic Management, Operations Management, Public Sector Management, and other related topics. Research papers/abstracts cutting across business and non-business disciplines (e.g., education, engineering, law, politics, psychology, sociology, etc.) are also welcome.</s>
    <s>(2) The SIBR Conference encourages discussion on the latest research-in-progress. For those authors who cannot submit full papers, they can present their latest findings at the SIBR Conference if their abstracts are accepted. In these cases only the peer reviewed abstracts will be included in the conference proceedings.</s>
    <s>(3) Interested parties without papers/abstracts for presentation are also invited to participate as attendees at the SIBR Conference.</s>
    <s>SUBMISSION GUIDELINES</s>
    <s>(1) Please use the following standardized format for your full paper/abstract:</s>
    <s>Click to download the format for full paper</s>
    <s>Click to download the format for abstract</s>
    <s>(2) Submit full paper/abstract (in MS Word) via the Online Submission System [click to enter].</s>
    <s>(3) Full papers/abstracts received by the deadline will be immediately peer-reviewed by an internal panel on a rolling basis, with the notification of acceptance/rejection being issued within 14 days of receiving the submission.</s>
    <s>(4) In case your paper/abstract is multi-authored, the submitting author will serve as the corresponding author, who has the responsibility to forward all correspondences to his/her co-authors (e.g., acceptance/rejection emails).</s>
    <s>PUBLICATION OPPORTUNITIES</s>
    <s>(1) Publication at SIBR Conference Proceedings:</s>
    <s>Full papers/abstracts accepted for the SIBR Conference will be published at the SIBR Conference Proceedings (ISSN: 2223-5078). Authors DO NOT need to transfer copyrights to SIBR.</s>
    <s>(2) The following refereed journals edited by SIBR Committee Members will publish a SIBR special issue featuring selected full papers from the SIBR Conference:</s>
    <s>International Journal of Trade and Global Markets , edited by Professor Bruno S. Sergi.</s>
    <s>International Journal of Business Environment , edited by Professor Antonio J. Verdu.</s>
    <s>International Journal of Mixed Methods for Applied Business and Policy Research, edited by Dr. Roslyn Cameron.</s>
    <s>Interdisciplinary Journal of Economics and Business Law, edited by Professor Ruth Taplin.</s>
    <s>Authors will be invited to choose one of the above as a possible publication outlet for their papers. Final acceptance for publication in the chosen journal is subject to further editorial review.</s>
    <s>(3) Submission to other refereed journals edited by SIBR Committee Members:</s>
    <s>Authors of papers accepted for the SIBR Conference are highly recommended to self-submit their papers to other refereed journals edited by the SIBR committee members (as listed below, or click here for submission details) for further review. The authors should indicate in their cover letter to the journal Editors that the paper has been presented at the SIBR conference. The acceptance of papers for publication in these journals will be subject to the journal editors' final decision. Moreover, the authors are responsible for any charges levied by the journals for publication.</s>
    <s>International Journal of Business Research and Management , edited by Dr. Miquel Àngel Piera i Eroles.</s>
    <s>Indian Journal of Economics and Business , edited by Professor Kishore G. Kulkarni.</s>
    <s>International Journal of Banking, Accounting and Finance , edited by Professor Fotios Pasiouras (Co-Editors: Philip Molyneux &amp; Andrea Resti).</s>
    <s>International Journal of Business Competition and Growth , edited by Professor Rajagopal.</s>
    <s>International Journal of Education Economics and Development , edited by Dr. Ravinder Rena.</s>
    <s>International Journal of Sustainable Strategic Management , edited by Professor John E. Spillan.</s>
    <s>International Journal of Engineering Management and Economics , edited by Professor Corrado lo Storto.</s>
    <s>BEST PAPER AWARDS</s>
    <s>Approximately 10% of the papers accepted for presentation at the conference will be selected as best papers for their outstanding contributions to interdisciplinary research. A certificate will be issued to the award-winning authors.</s>
    <s>TENTATIVE PROGRAM &amp; INSTRUCTIONS TO PRESENTERS</s>
    <s>Available at: click here to download</s>
    <s>IMPORTANT DATES</s>
    <s>Deadline for submission of paper/abstract: March 22nd, 2012</s>
    <s>Notification of acceptance/rejection: Within 14 days of receiving the paper/abstract</s>
    <s>Deadline for early-bird registration: April 26th, 2012</s>
    <s>Conference date: June 7th - June 9th, 2012</s>
    <s>REGISTRATION FEE</s>
    <s>All attending conference participants must pay the registration fee. For each paper/abstract, at least one author must attend and pay the registration fee. Each author can submit more than one abstract/paper and need to pay an additional registration fee for each additional paper/abstract. In case the paper/abstract is multi-authored and more than one author will attend the conference, each attending author needs to register separately. Unpaid abstracts/papers will be treated as withdraw. For all participants with or without papers/abstracts for presentation at the SIBR Conference, the registration fee is:</s>
    <s>Early-bird Registration Fee (on or before April 26th, 2012): USD 320</s>
    <s>Regular Registration Fee (after April 26th, 2012): USD 400</s>
    <s>The registration fee includes: conference attendance, daily tea breaks and luncheon, SIBR Conference Proceedings (CD-ROM), certificate of attendance, and official receipt.</s>
    <s>The registration fee does NOT include hotel accommodation and transport.</s>
    <s>CLICK HERE TO REGISTER</s>
    <s>Please contact the conference secretariat and events manager at secretary@sibresearch.org.</s>
    <s>HOME - SIBR CONFERENCE CALL - ONLINE SUBMISSION - REGISTRATION - CONFERENCE VENUE - JOURNALS - SIBR WORKING PAPERS</s>
    <s>number of visitors:</s>
    <s>Photos from (c) Tomo Yun (www.yunphoto.net/e/)</s>
    <s>Copyright © Society of Interdisciplinary Business Research 2008-2012</s>
  </text>
</page>
