<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <query keywords="conference call for papers" position="10" lang="en" date="2011-10-12"/>
  <url>http://www.ecoeco.org/content/2011/06/2012-isee-conference-call-for-papers/</url>
  <title>2012 ISEE Conference Call for Papers | The International Society for ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Jun 22, 2011 2012 ISEE Conference Call for Papers. image. 12th Biennial Conference of the International Society for Ecological Economics ISEE 2012: </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>!Not Logged In</s>
    <s>the ISEE</s>
    <s>regional societies</s>
    <s>president's letter</s>
    <s>officers &amp; committees</s>
    <s>cross discipline approach</s>
    <s>contact us</s>
    <s>join ISEE</s>
    <s>sponsorship dues</s>
    <s>ISEE latest news</s>
    <s>regional news</s>
    <s>other news</s>
    <s>blog notifications</s>
    <s>newsletter archive</s>
    <s>teaching opportunities</s>
    <s>teaching materials</s>
    <s>teaching links</s>
    <s>graduate opportunities</s>
    <s>post graduate</s>
    <s>research links</s>
    <s>short courses</s>
    <s>ISEE journal</s>
    <s>journal subscribers</s>
    <s>low cost journal</s>
    <s>ISEE sponsored books</s>
    <s>call for papers</s>
    <s>research institutes</s>
    <s>research projects</s>
    <s>research information</s>
    <s>blogs and discussion groups</s>
    <s>Members Only</s>
    <s>latest news</s>
    <s>join ISEE</s>
    <s>renew your membership</s>
    <s>Follow us on:</s>
    <s>and on the ISEE blog</s>
    <s>2012 ISEE Conference Call for Papers</s>
    <s>12th Biennial Conference of the International Society for Ecological Economics</s>
    <s>ISEE 2012: ECOLOGICAL ECONOMICS AND RIO +20</s>
    <s>CONTRIBUTIONS AND CHALLENGES FOR A GREEN ECONOMY</s>
    <s>29 May – 1 June, 2012 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil</s>
    <s>FIRST CALL FOR PAPERS</s>
    <s>ISEE is a nonprofit, member-governed organization dedicated to advancing understanding of the relationships between the economy, ecology and society, for the mutual well-being of people and nature. ISEE conferences are transdisciplinary and have been held biennially since 1990. ISEE 2012 has been conceived to dovetail with the Rio+20 UNCSD Earth Summit. The Earth Summit has been charged with developing a road map for international cooperation toward a “Green Economy” and for promoting institutions necessary for sustainable development. ISEE 2012 will address UNCSD themes as well as other key debates within ecological economics and environmental policy. It will promote dialogue with the Summit through a final ministerial panel and the participation of policy makers. The challenge for Ecological Economics at this Summit is to contribute to designing innovative alternatives, to address market and institutional failures, as well as to better understand ecological and economic systems. To download the complete flyer click here.</s>
    <s>CONFERENCE THEMES</s>
    <s>Greening the Economy</s>
    <s>Measuring green growth</s>
    <s>The energy question</s>
    <s>Sustainable consumption</s>
    <s>(Un)sustainable cities?</s>
    <s>The Political Economy of Green Development</s>
    <s>Food security: who sows? who reaps?</s>
    <s>The economics and politics of climate change</s>
    <s>Pollution and politics</s>
    <s>Challenges of community resource governance</s>
    <s>Environmental Justice, Ethics and Values</s>
    <s>Global agreements: is convergence possible?</s>
    <s>Balancing nature: people, biodiversity and resilience</s>
    <s>Governing environmental behaviour</s>
    <s>Mores and morals: toward an environmental ethic</s>
    <s>Political ecology and ecological conflicts</s>
    <s>Methodological Challenges</s>
    <s>Feminist economics and ecological economics: can the twain meet?</s>
    <s>Behavioural economics and economic behaviour: beyond homo economicus?</s>
    <s>Economics and Ecology: transdisciplinary conversations</s>
    <s>ABSTRACT SUBMISSION</s>
    <s>There will be three tracks for abstract submissions: Panels (for long presentations), Roundtables (for short interventions) and Posters. Submissions can be in the form of individual abstracts or as full Panels and Roundtables. Full Panels/Roundtables require a cogent theme, a brief introduction giving the rationale, names of session chair(s), and abstracts/papers of all contributors.  Alternative innovative formats, including performances, films and installations, would also be welcome for consideration.</s>
    <s>Abstracts should be a maximum of 700 words and must be submitted online via the conference website: www.isee2012.org.   All abstracts for Panels and Roundtables will be reviewed by an international review panel (see schedule below). Abstracts for poster presentations will be evaluated by the ISEE Local Organizing Committee.Acceptance of all abstracts will be based on relevance for ecological economics and the conference theme, originality, and overall quality.  Official notification of abstract acceptance or rejection, or optional poster presentation will be emailed to the corresponding author on 15 December 2011.</s>
    <s>Conference organisers will make every effort to seek funding to reimburse travel costs and participation fees of those from non-OECD countries and for student researchers (with proof of university attendance). Those needing funding must submit a full paper in advance.</s>
    <s>CONFERENCE DEADLINES</s>
    <s>15 November 2011 – Session, paper, poster abstract submissions</s>
    <s>15 December 2011 – Author notification</s>
    <s>2 March 2012 – Pay registration fee online to ensure inclusion of abstract in conference brochure</s>
    <s>29 May 2012 – Conference begins</s>
    <s>International Program and Scientific Committee</s>
    <s>Bina Agarwal, President ISEE, 2012-2013 (Chairperson)</s>
    <s>John Gowdy, President ISEE, 2010-2011</s>
    <s>Peter May, President ISEE, 2009-2010</s>
    <s>Maria Amélia Enriquez, President ECOECO</s>
    <s>Paulo Mibielli, Vice President ECOECO</s>
    <s>José Eli da Veiga, University of São Paulo</s>
    <s>José Feres, Vice-President ALEAR</s>
    <s>Joshua Farley, University of Vermont, USA</s>
    <s>Pushpam Kumar, UNEP, Kenya</s>
    <s>Bernardo Aguilar, President SMEE, Costa Rica</s>
    <s>Roldan Muradian, REDIBEC</s>
    <s>Sigrid Stagl, President, ESEE</s>
    <s>Begum Ozkaynak, Bogazici University, Turkey</s>
    <s>Kevin Urama, President, ASEE, Kenya</s>
    <s>Walter Pengue, President, AUSEE, Argentina</s>
    <s>Wendy Proctor, President, ANZEE</s>
    <s>Local Organizing Committee</s>
    <s>Peter May, Past President, ISEE (Chairperson)</s>
    <s>Frederico Cavadas, Board member, ECOECO</s>
    <s>Gina van Dijk, MCI-Group, Brazil (ex oficio)</s>
    <s>José Feres, Vice-President, ALEAR</s>
    <s>Liandra Caldasso, INCT-PPED, UFRJ</s>
    <s>Paulo Mibielli, Vice President, ECOECO</s>
    <s>Valeria Vinha, Institute of Economics-UFRJ</s>
    <s>To download the flyer click here.</s>
    <s>Tags: 12th Biennial Conference of ISEE, 12th Bienniel Conference for International Society for Ecological Economics, Ecological Economics and Rio, Green Economy, ISEE, ISEE Conference</s>
    <s>This entry was posted on Wednesday, June 22nd, 2011 at 7:47 pm and is filed under Call For Papers, Conferences - ISEE. You can follow any responses to this entry through the RSS 2.0 feed. You can leave a response, or trackback from your own site.</s>
    <s>9 Responses to &quot;2012 ISEE Conference Call for Papers&quot;</s>
    <s>1. International Society for Ecological Economics Call for Papers | Nourishing the Planet Says:</s>
    <s>August 2nd, 2011 at 4:30 am</s>
    <s> of green development, environmental justice and methodological challenges.For more information, see ISEE’s website, or download the .pdf flyer directly.Tags: Call for Papers • Dr. Bina Agarwal • International </s>
    <s>2. International Society for Ecological Economics Call for Papers Says:</s>
    <s>August 3rd, 2011 at 4:01 am</s>
    <s> more information, see ISEE’s website, or download the .pdf flyer </s>
    <s>3.Joseph Henry Vogel Says:</s>
    <s>August 18th, 2011 at 9:02 am</s>
    <s>I have read the Abstract Submission form and wish to enquire about conference funding &quot;Conference organisers will make every effort to seek funding to reimburse travel costs and participation fees of those from non-OECD countries.&quot; The Commonwealth of PR is a colony of the US with official poverty at about 50%, negative growth for the last six years, and a budgetary cut of 25% of the University. Our salaries have been significantly cut and workloads increased. Would the situation of my affiliation with the state university qualify as &quot;Conference organisers will make every effort to seek funding to reimburse travel costs and participation fees of those from non-OECD countries &quot; Cheers, Joseph.</s>
    <s>4. Breaking Alternative News Says:</s>
    <s>August 20th, 2011 at 6:09 am</s>
    <s>Latest in Alternative News…</s>
    <s>2012 ISEE Conference Call for Papers | The International Society for Ecological Economics…</s>
    <s>5. ISEE 2012: ECOLOGICAL ECONOMICS AND RIO +20: CONTRIBUTIONS AND CHALLENGES FOR A GREEN ECONOMY « The Social Science Informer Says:</s>
    <s>September 12th, 2011 at 11:40 am</s>
    <s> Peter May, past President ISEE is chair of the Local Organising Committee. For details see: http://www.ecoeco.org/content/2011/06/2012-isee-conference-call-for-papers/ Download the complete flyer: http://www.ecoeco.org/content/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/ISEE 2012 CF </s>
    <s>6.Mouchumi K.Borohain Says:</s>
    <s>September 16th, 2011 at 4:57 am</s>
    <s>I have started the membership process. Reimbursing the travel cost-if the abstract is selected, would be really a creditable job.</s>
    <s>7.Dr. R. Shashi Kumar Says:</s>
    <s>September 25th, 2011 at 10:59 am</s>
    <s>Very important themes selected for the conference.</s>
    <s>8.sudhakar patra Says:</s>
    <s>September 28th, 2011 at 11:33 pm</s>
    <s>The theme of conference, green economy is quite interesting and contemporary. I would like to participate and contribute a paper on global Energy crisis. Can you arrange funding for participants of developing countries, like India.</s>
    <s>9.vadivel Says:</s>
    <s>September 29th, 2011 at 2:14 am</s>
    <s>it will be useful for control the natural disorder on the earth. after the this conference we will identify the problems related to topics created by many thinker's contribution.</s>
    <s>Leave a Reply</s>
    <s>Name *</s>
    <s>Email Address (will not be published) *</s>
    <s>Comment: You can use these HTML tags:</s>
    <s>`&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;b&gt; &lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;cite&gt; &lt;code&gt; &lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;em&gt; &lt;i&gt; &lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;strike&gt; &lt;strong&gt; `</s>
    <s>ANZEE 2011 Conference »</s>
    <s>« ISEE Recommended Reading Available in Google Books</s>
    <s>!To promote understanding between economists and ecologists in the development of a sustainable world.</s>
  </text>
</page>
