<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <query keywords="conference call for papers" position="17" lang="en" date="2011-10-12"/>
  <url>http://www.ncbsonline.org/conference_call_for_papers</url>
  <title>NCBS Online - Conference Call for Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>NCBS is accepting abstracts for individual paper, poster, panel, session, roundtable discussion, workshop, town hall meeting that explore the Black experience </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>CLICK HERE!</s>
    <s>NCBS Statement on the International</s>
    <s>Year of People of African Descent</s>
    <s>Join Our Mailing List</s>
    <s>National Council for Black Studies</s>
    <s>Promote Your Page Too</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>NCBS is accepting abstracts for individual paper, poster, panel, session, roundtable discussion, workshop, town hall meeting that explore the Black experience locally, nationally, and/or globally from a variety perspective. Of particular interest are presentations that comparatively explore these experiences, as well as those that examine the discipline of Africana/Black Studies using multi-layered frameworks and methodologies. Papers that incorporate various combinations of race/nationality, class, gender, and sexuality, through the lens of but not limited to Afrocentric, cross and multicultural, diasporic, feminist, postcolonial, postmodernist or transnational interpretative schemes are welcomed. Send a 150-400 word abstract for a panel (one for the panel subject and one for each panelist), and/or individual paper and poster presentations. For roundtable discussions submit a 500 word abstract that explores the discussion topic. For town hall meetings submit a 500 word abstract specifying the roles of the facilitator(s) and recorder(s).</s>
    <s>Audio-visual needs (e.g. power,point, monitors, tv etc.)--presenters have to contract equipment from the hotel--NCBS &quot;will not&quot; be responsible for supplying presenters with equipment.</s>
    <s>* All conference presenters must pre-register for the conference.</s>
    <s>SUBMISSION DEADLINE October 14, 2011</s>
    <s>CLICK HERE TO SEE HOW YOU CAN GET FREE CONFERENCE REGISTRATION TICKETS.</s>
    <s>Abstract Submission Guidelines</s>
    <s>The following information is required for presentation consideration for the NCBS annual conference.</s>
    <s>Individual Abstracts</s>
    <s>Panel Proposals</s>
    <s>Roundtable Proposals</s>
    <s>Abstract (1-2 pages)</s>
    <s>Presentation Title</s>
    <s>Name, Address, Phone, Email</s>
    <s>Panel Abstract (1-2 pages)</s>
    <s>Abstract &amp; Presentation Title (each panelist)</s>
    <s>Name, Address, Phone, Email (each panelist)</s>
    <s>Institution/Affiliation (each panelist)</s>
    <s>Name of Primary Contact</s>
    <s>Roundtable Abstract (1-2 pages)</s>
    <s>Roundtable Title</s>
    <s>Name, Address, Phone, Email</s>
    <s>Institution/Affiliation (each panelist)</s>
    <s>Name of Primary Contact</s>
    <s>Submit Abstracts Here</s>
    <s>For questions and support on abstract submission please email kershamn@uc.edu.</s>
    <s>About NCBS</s>
    <s>Programs &amp; Services</s>
    <s>Conference &amp; Events</s>
    <s>Member Resources</s>
    <s>Student's Corner</s>
    <s>Contact Us</s>
    <s>National Council for Black Studies, Inc.</s>
    <s>Promoting Academic Excellence and Social Responsibility</s>
    <s>Site Powered By</s>
    <s>QuickBizBuilder Site Manager</s>
    <s>Online web site design</s>
    <s>What Can I Do With A Black Studies Major?</s>
    <s>What Can I Do With A Black Studies Major?</s>
    <s>222 Answers</s>
    <s>Robert Fikes, Jr., Librarian</s>
    <s>San Diego State University</s>
    <s>Third Edition</s>
    <s>The Voice of Black StudiesSubmit an article in our electronic newsletter</s>
    <s>Learn more on how to submit your article for an upcoming edition.</s>
    <s>List Your Position Announcements on NCBS Online</s>
    <s>Do you have a job position available?</s>
    <s>Now you can list your position announcements on NCBS Online. Our listing service is free to Institutional Members. There is a fee for non-Institutional Members. Just complete our online submission form, and your posting will be listed within 48 hours after approval.</s>
    <s>Position announcements are viewable to all NCBS Online visitors.</s>
    <s>Submit a Position Announcement now </s>
  </text>
</page>
