<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <query keywords="conference call for papers" position="19" lang="en" date="2011-10-12"/>
  <url>http://www.ametsoc.org/meet/ann/callforpapers.html</url>
  <title>AMS Call for Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Call for Papers. 30th Conference on Hurricanes and Tropical Meteorology, 15-20 April 2012, Ponte Vedra Beach, Florida The 30th Conference on Hurricanes </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>About | Affiliations | Contact | FAQ | Science, Service, Society | Search | Volunteer</s>
    <s>Boards and</s>
    <s>Career Center</s>
    <s>Member Services</s>
    <s>AMS Meetings</s>
    <s>Submit Abstract Online</s>
    <s>Meetings of Interest</s>
    <s>AMS Meetings</s>
    <s>Red announcement or call = new</s>
    <s>Blue announcement or call = revised</s>
    <s>Other links</s>
    <s>Calendar of Meetings</s>
    <s>Meetings Home</s>
    <s>AMS Call for Papers</s>
    <s>92nd Annual Meeting Call for Papers</s>
    <s>2011 AMS Meetings</s>
    <s>Ninth Symposium on Fire and Forest Meteorology, 18-20 October 2011, Palm Springs, CA area</s>
    <s>The Ninth Symposium on Fire and Forest Meteorology, sponsored by the American Meteorological Society and organized by the AMS Committee on Agricultural and Forest Meteorology, will be held 18-20 October 2011 at in the Palm Springs, CA area.</s>
    <s>The theme of the symposium will be to share experiences, new techniques and technologies and/or changes in the areas of: (1) impacts of weather and climate on wildfire; (2) operational forecasting (short to long term) of fire weather for wild, prescribed, and fire use fires; (3) model studies and development, including coupled fire-atmosphere models and mesoscale models; (4) use and assessment of climate forecasts in fire management planning; (5) smoke and fire decision support tool development; (6) techniques in smoke management and mitigation related to new NAAQS and haze standards; (7) improvements to fire danger and fire behavior systems related to meteorology; and (8) field studies of fire-atmosphere interactions.</s>
    <s>The deadline for abstracts has passed. Authors of accepted presentations will be notified (via e-mail) by mid June. Unlike at past conferences, no preprint CD-ROM will be prepared. However, authors of invited and accepted papers will still be asked to contribute to the web-based proceedings of the conference by submitting an extended abstract. All extended abstracts are to be submitted electronically and will be available on-line via the Web. Instructions for formatting extended manuscripts for the preprint CD-ROM will be posted on the AMS Web site. Manuscripts (up to 3MB) must be submitted electronically by 17 November 2011.</s>
    <s>For further program information contact either one of the Program Co-chairpersons: Tim Brown, Desert Research Institute, 2215 Raggio Parkway, Reno, NV 89512-1095 (tel: 775-674-7090; fax: 775-674-7016; e-mail: tbrown@dri.edu or Brian Potter, Forestry Sciences Lab, 400 N 34th St., Suite 201, Seattle, WA 98103 (tel: 206-732-7828; fax: 206¬-732-7801; e-mail: bpotter@fs.fed.us). (3/11)</s>
    <s>2012 AMS Meetings</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>30th Conference on Hurricanes and Tropical Meteorology, 15-20 April 2012, Ponte Vedra Beach, Florida</s>
    <s>The 30th Conference on Hurricanes and Tropical Meteorology sponsored by the American Meteorological Society and organized by the AMS Committee on Tropical Meteorology and Tropical Cyclones will be held 15-20 April 2012, at the Sawgrass Marriott, 1000 PGA Tour Boulevard, Ponte Vedra Beach, Florida. Preliminary programs and registration details will be posted on the AMS website in early November 2011. General information on hotel accommodations will soon be available on the AMS website.</s>
    <s>Papers are solicited on all aspects of tropical meteorology and oceanography, including convection, tropical cyclones, intraseasonal variability, monsoons, air-sea interaction, climate, observing systems, and prediction.</s>
    <s>Over recent years, several major programs have been conducted or are ongoing and new results continue to become available. Therefore, papers resulting from such programs as the NASA Genesis and Rapid Intensification Processes (GRIP) Experiment, the Pre- Depression Investigation of Cloud-Systems in the Tropics (PREDICT) Experiment, the Impact of Typhoons on the Ocean in the Pacific (ITOP) 2010 field experiment, the Cooperative Indian Ocean Experiment on Intraseasonal Variability (CINDY2011)/the Dynamics of the Madden-Julian Oscillation (DYNAMO), and the NOAA Intensity Forecast Experiment (IFEX) and Hurricane Forecast Improvement Project (HFIP), are all encouraged. Participants with additional suggestions for the program are encouraged to contact the program chairperson.</s>
    <s>Please submit your abstract electronically via the AMS website by 15 November 2011; see the website for instructions. An abstract fee of $95 (payable by credit card or purchase order) is charged at the time of submission (refundable only if abstract is not accepted). The $95 abstract fee includes the submission of your abstract, the posting of your extended abstract, and the uploading and recording of your presentation that will be archived on the AMS Web site. We will no longer be producing a CD-ROM, allowing us to extend the deadline date for extended abstracts.</s>
    <s>Authors of accepted presentations will be notified via e-mail by early-December 2011. Instructions for formatting extended abstracts will be posted on the AMS website. Extended manuscripts (file size up to 3 MB) must be submitted electronically by 21 May 2012. All abstracts, extended abstracts, and presentations will be made available on the AMS website.</s>
    <s>For further program information please contact the program chairperson, Robert Hart, Department of Earth, Ocean and Atmospheric Sciences, Florida State University, 404 Love Building, Tallahassee, FL, 32306-4520, rhart@fsu.edu. (8/11)</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>International Conference on Southern Hemisphere Meteorology and Oceanography, 23-27 April 2012, Noumea, New Caledonia</s>
    <s>The 10th International Conference on Southern Hemisphere Meteorology and Oceanography (ICSHMO), which is run under the auspices of the American Meteorological Society (AMS), will be held from 23-27 April 2012 in Noumea, New Caledonia, in collaboration with both the Institute of Research for Development and Meteo-France.</s>
    <s>Abstracts for papers and posters will be due by 15 September 2011 and the early registration deadline will be 1 February 2012. The conference web page is available at http://10icshmo.org and more details on abstract submission and registration is posted there, please consult the web page periodically as it evolves and more details become available.</s>
    <s>Since its first conference in 1983, the ICSHMO has provided a unique contribution to ocean and atmosphere sciences that are specific to the Southern Hemisphere. The ICSHMO takes place every 3rd year, and the previous one gathered 470 scientists in Melbourne in 2009 and was focussed on extreme events. Attracting both students and scientists from developing countries has always been a priority for ICSHMO. The objective of the 2012 conference, the 10th of the series, is to provide an interdisciplinary forum for presentations of our current state of knowledge, as well as in motivating new research and applications within the variety of disciplines related to weather and climate of the ocean and atmosphere. 10ICSHMO will focus on the unique aspects of atmospheric and oceanic sciences in the Southern Hemisphere. Particular attention will be given to the following theme areas, however it should be stressed that a broad range of submissions are encouraged and are NOT restricted just to the following areas of the Southern Hemisphere:</s>
    <s>• Monsoon Systems and Convergence Zones</s>
    <s>• Sea level Rise &amp; Vulnerability</s>
    <s>• Climate Predictability</s>
    <s>• Ocean Circulation and Climate</s>
    <s>• Climate Change in the Southern Hemisphere</s>
    <s>• Interdecadal Climate Variability and Impacts</s>
    <s>• Interannual Climate Variability and Teleconnections</s>
    <s>• Intraseasonal Climate Variability</s>
    <s>• Severe Weather Systems and Tropical Cyclones</s>
    <s>• Inter-ocean Exchanges</s>
    <s>• Ocean Observing Systems and Operational Oceanography</s>
    <s>• Island Weather, Climate ,and Oceanography</s>
    <s>• Cryospheric Studies</s>
    <s>• Paleoclimate Studies in the Ocean or Atmosphere</s>
    <s>• A Special Session on ACRE - Atmospheric Circulation Reconstructions over the Earth</s>
    <s>For additional information, please visit the conference Web site at: http://10icshmo.org. (1/11)</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>20th Symposium on Boundary Layers and Turbulence, 8-13 July 2012, Boston, Massachusetts</s>
    <s>The 20th Symposium on Boundary Layers and Turbulence, sponsored by the American Meteorological Society (AMS) and organized by the AMS Committee on Boundary Layers and Turbulence will be held in Boston, Massachusetts. The dates are 8-13 July 2012. Information including location, travel/flight information, abstract submission procedures, hotels, and other general information will be posted at the AMS Web site (www.ametsoc.org) starting April 2012.</s>
    <s>This symposium is being held in conjunction with the 18th Conference on Air-Sea Interaction. Joint sessions will be held on topics associated with coastal and marine boundary layer processes, observations and modeling. A special lecture will be given by a prominent scientist in the field.</s>
    <s>Papers and posters are invited on all subjects dealing with atmospheric boundary layers and turbulence including observational, modeling, theoretical, and applied studies.</s>
    <s>We anticipate and invite presentations and posters addressing any of the following themes:</s>
    <s>• Coastal and marine boundary layers</s>
    <s>• Boundary layer processes, observations and modeling</s>
    <s>• Renewable energy applications of boundary layer physics</s>
    <s>• Boundary layer clouds</s>
    <s>• Observations and modeling in complex and urban terrain</s>
    <s>• Boundary layer parameterizations in models at all scales</s>
    <s>• Theoretical and practical issues associated with multi-scale simulations</s>
    <s>• Morning and afternoon transitional behavior of the boundary layer</s>
    <s>• Recent field experiments, including BLLAST and DYNAMO</s>
    <s>Please submit your abstract electronically via the Web by 5 April 2012 (refer to the AMS Web page at http://ams.confex.com/ams/.) An abstract fee of $95 (payable by credit card or purchase order) is charged at the time of submission (refundable only if abstract is not accepted).</s>
    <s>Authors of accepted presentations will be notified (via e-mail) in early May 2012. All ex-tended abstracts are to be submitted electronically and will be available on-line via the Web. Instruc-tions for formatting extended abstracts will be posted on the AMS Web site. Manuscripts (up to 3MB) must be submitted electronically by 13 August 2012. All abstracts, extended abstracts and presenta-tions will be available on the AMS Web site at no cost to viewers.</s>
    <s>For further information, please contact the program co-chairs: Sharon Zhong (e-mail: zhongs@msu.edu), Wayne Angevine (Wayne.M.Angevine@noaa.gov), and Robert Conzemius (Bob.Conzemius@windlogics.com). (8/11)</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>18th Conference on Air-Sea Interaction, 8-13 July 2012, Boston, Massachusetts</s>
    <s>The 18th Conference on Air-Sea Interaction, sponsored by the American Meteorological Society and organized by the AMS Committee on Air-Sea Interaction (http://www.ametsoc.org/stacpges/seaatmos/index.html), will be held 8-13 July 2012 in Boston, Massachusetts. Preliminary programs, registration, hotel, and general information will be posted on the AMS Web site (http://www.ametsoc.org) in April 2012.</s>
    <s>The conference will be held in conjunction with the AMS 20th Symposium on Boundary Layers and Turbulence. Joint sessions will be held on topics associated with coastal and marine boundary layer processes, observations, and modeling.</s>
    <s>Papers and posters for this conference are solicited on all aspects of air-sea interaction across a wide spectrum of temporal and spatial scales. General sessions for the conference will be based on the number and topics of abstracts received. A plenary session will be held to introduce the Conference. Although not an exhaustive list, we welcome abstracts covering the following topics:</s>
    <s>1. High latitude air-sea interaction, including air-sea-ice interaction</s>
    <s>2. Air-sea flux measurements, estimation, and parameterization, including gas exchange</s>
    <s>3. Air-sea interaction under high wind speed conditions</s>
    <s>4. Sea surface processes, including waves, spray, bubbles, and aerosol</s>
    <s>5. Coastal and marine boundary layers in the atmosphere and ocean</s>
    <s>6. The role of air-sea interaction in climate variability</s>
    <s>7. Air-sea flux datasets: developments and applications</s>
    <s>8. The role of air-sea interaction in climate change</s>
    <s>9. Theoretical and practical issues associated with multi-scale simulations</s>
    <s>10. Renewable energy applications of boundary layer physics</s>
    <s>11. Recent field experiments, including Dynamics of the Madden-Julian Oscillation (DYNAMO)</s>
    <s>Participants with additional suggestions for general, special, or joint sessions are encouraged to contact the program chairpersons. To encourage interdisciplinary interaction among attendees, an invited talk as an introductory overview is planned for each session.</s>
    <s>The Air-Sea Interaction Conference will host a student paper competition and make awards for exemplary student poster and oral presentations. Every student who enters this competition will also receive a complimentary copy of the AMS Glossary of Meteorology or a comparable AMS book.</s>
    <s>Please submit your abstract electronically via the Web by 5 April 2012 (refer to the AMS Web page http://ams.confex.com/ams/). An abstract fee of $95 (payable by credit card or purchase order) is charged at the time of submission (refundable only if the abstract is not accepted). This $95 abstract fee will also cover the submission of your extended abstract and the uploading and recording of your presentation, both of which will be archived on the AMS Web site and available to all at no cost. There is also no cost for color graphics in the abstract or the extended abstract. Authors of accepted presentations will be notified (via e-mail) in early May 2012. Instructions for formatting extended abstracts will be posted on the AMS Web site. Manuscripts (up to 3MB) must be submitted electronically by 13 August 2012. All abstracts, extended abstracts, and presentations will be available on the AMS Web site at no cost to viewers. More information on poster presentations will be available once the program has been finalized.</s>
    <s>For additional information, please contact any of the following: R. Justin Small (meeting organizer, jsmall@ucar.edu, 303-497-1387); Huai-Min Zhang (meeting co-organizer, Huai-min.Zhang@noaa.gov); or Magdalena Anguelova (student competition organizer, maggie.anguelova@nrl.navy.mil) (8/11)</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>26th Conference on Severe Local Storms, 5-8 November 2012, Nashville, Tennessee</s>
    <s>The 26th Conference on Severe Local Storms, sponsored by the AMS and organized by the AMS Committee on Severe Local Storms, will be held 5-8 November 2012 at the Loews Vanderbilt Hotel in Nashville, Tennessee. A preliminary program, registration, hotel, and general information will appear on the AMS web site (http://www.ametsoc.org) by late July 2012.</s>
    <s>Oral and poster presentations are solicited on all topics related to severe local storms. Presentations on novel radar and in situ instrumentation, field studies using this instrumentation, assimilation of these data into numerical models for the analysis and prediction of severe convective weather, and studies of the societal impacts of severe local storms, are particularly encouraged. Further, a focus on results from the second field phase of the Verification of the Origins of Rotation in Tornadoes Experiment (VORTEX2) and on the many high-impact severe-weather events that occurred in 2011 is expected.</s>
    <s>Please submit your abstract electronically online at http://ams.confex.com/ams/ by the deadline date of 20 June 2012. An abstract fee of $95 (payable by credit card or purchase order) is charged at the time of submission. Authors are encouraged to submit an extended electronic manuscript (see below) to supplement their presentations at no extra cost. Authors may indicate their preference for an oral or poster presentation during abstract submission; those authors presenting more than one paper should clearly indicate which they prefer for a possible oral presentation. Please note that some abstracts may not be accepted, depending on program constraints, relevance and merit of subject matter. In any such cases the abstract fee will be refunded. Conference awards will be given for the best oral and poster presentations by first-time student presenters. Registrants should indicate their eligibility for student awards when submitting their abstracts.</s>
    <s>Authors of accepted presentations will be notified via e-mail by 20 July 2012. These authors are strongly encouraged to submit an extended manuscript electronically prior to the start of the conference, but manuscripts will be accepted through the electronic submission system through 7 December 2012. Instructions for formatting extended abstracts (PDF format, up to 3 MB in size) will be posted on the AMS web site. All abstracts, extended abstracts and presentations will be available on the AMS web site at no cost.</s>
    <s>A session for presenting photos and videos is planned for Monday evening. Participants who are interested in contributing their images or video should contact Mike Coniglio (Michael.Coniglio@noaa.gov).</s>
    <s>For additional information please contact either of the program chairs: Pam Heinselman, Pam.Heinselman@noaa.gov, NOAA National Severe Storms Laboratory, 120 David L. Boren Blvd., Norman, OK 73072, or Mike Coniglio, Michael.Coniglio@noaa.gov.</s>
    <s>(8/11; r9/11)</s>
    <s>2011 Meetings of Interest</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>International Symposium on Climatology (IV SIC), 16-19 October 2011, Joao Pessoa, Brazil</s>
    <s>The Fourth edition of the IV SIC will be held at Tropical Tambau Beach Resort in Joao Pessoa, State of Paraiba, Brazil 16-19 October 2011. It will be placed under the general topic of &quot;Impacts of Climate Change on Urban Areas&quot; aiming to discuss how the global climate change is affecting the Brazilian cities and possible solutions to mitigate this influence. In this context, the themes involve Climate Change Impacts and Environmental Sustainability and Health in Urban Areas, Extreme Events in Time, New Technologies in Weather Forecasting and Climate Vulnerability of Coastal Urban Areas and Regional Reliability Models and Future Climate Scenarios.</s>
    <s>The working languages of the IV SIC will be Portuguese and English. The organization will provide simultaneous translation (Portuguese/English or English/Portuguese) for the lectures of the invited speakers.</s>
    <s>The IV SIC will be attended by renowned researchers as Dr. Carlos Nobre (Secretary of Policy and Program Research and Development/Brazil), Dr. Jose Antonio Marengo (National Institute for Space Research/Brazil), Dr. Jason West (University of North Carolina/USA), Dr. Gregory R. Carmichael (University of Iowa/USA), Dr. Gustavo Carrio (Colorado State University/USA), Dr. Carlos Corvalan (World Health Organization/USA), etc.</s>
    <s>Papers can be submitted and presented in Portuguese, Spanish or English. The deadline for submission is 31 August 2011. For further information, please visit www.sic2011.com/eng. (9/11)</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Meteorological Technology World Expo, 18-20 October, Brussels, Belgium</s>
    <s>The Meteorological Technology World Expo, organized by the publishers of Meteorological Technology International magazine and taking place 18-20 October 2011 in Brussels, Belgium, has a unique opportunity for a select few to present papers at our free-to-attend Open Technology Forum which takes place on the exhibition floor itself.</s>
    <s>The World Expo, which is expected to attract over 100 exhibitors and around 2,000-2,500 visitors, will showcase next-generation weather prediction and analysis technologies as well as weather service providers to visitors from the following sectors: air traffic control, airlines, the military, energy companies, wind-farm operators, shipping companies, DoTs, harbours and ports, and of course national met offices and research institutes. Presentations will be no more than 25 minutes in length, and an abstract of 150 words is required for consideration. This is a forum about advancing prediction technologies and services, not about the weatherCase studies on advanced technologies, intelligent projects, or future possibilities for prediction are welcome. Send your submissions to j.taylor@ukipme.com.</s>
    <s>For additional information, please reference the conference Web site at: http://www.meteorologicaltechnologyworldexpo.com/. (7/11)</s>
    <s>World Climate Research Programme Open Science Conference, 24-28 October 2011, Denver, Colorado</s>
    <s>The World Climate Research Programme (http://wcrp.wmo.int) will host a major international Open Science Conference (OSC) on 24-28 October 2011 in Denver, Colorado, USA.</s>
    <s>WCRP is sponsored by the World Meteorological Organization (WMO), the International Council for Science (ICSU) and the Intergovernmental Oceanographic Commission (IOC) of the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO).</s>
    <s>A better understanding of the behaviour of the climate system and its interactions with other Earth system components is critical to predict its future evolution, reduce vulnerability to high impact weather and climate events, and sustain life. To prepare for meeting these challenges, the WCRP Open Science Conference provides a unique opportunity to bring together major disciplines and leaders of the Earth system research community to help identify opportunities to advance further understanding and prediction of variability and change in the Earth's climate system from seasons to centuries, and from regions to the entire globe.</s>
    <s>Through active dialogue among the international environmental change research experts, the OSC will: Appraise the current state of climate science, thereby making a measurable scientific contribution to the Fifth Assessment Report (AR5) of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC); Identify key opportunities and challenges in observations, modelling and analysis towards understanding and predicting the Earth's climate system; Facilitate discussion on interdisciplinary research required to understand and predict responses of the Earth as a system to climate variability and change, thus helping chart the path forward over the ensuing decades; and Highlight priority research in support of the Global Framework for Climate Services initiated at the World Climate Conference -3.</s>
    <s>By entraining early career scientists and students from across the world, especially less-developed and developing nations and regions, the OSC will facilitate growth of the diverse future workforce needed to meet the increasingly complex scientific challenges of the future.</s>
    <s>The conference aims to attract the world's experts to provide a unique synthesis of current research findings on climate variability and change, to identify the most urgent scientific issues and research challenges, and to ascertain how the WCRP can best facilitate research and develop partnerships critical for progress in the future.</s>
    <s>For more information, please visit the conference Webpage at: www.wcrp-climate.org/conference2011 or contact the Conference Secretariat at: info.conf2011@wcrp-climate.org. (6/10)</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Graduate Climate Conference, 28-30 October 2011, Woods Hole, Massachusetts</s>
    <s>The goal of the Graduate Climate Conference (GCC) is to provide a discussion forum for graduate students undertaking research on climate and climate change in an array of disciplines, including atmospheric, biological, earth and ocean sciences. The format is designed to encourage new climate scientists to become acquainted with the details of diverse areas of climate research and to place their own research in the broader context of the climate science community.</s>
    <s>From its beginning in 2006, the GCC has been organized by grad students from the University of Washington. The organizers' original hope was that the conference would rotate among different institutions. In that spirit, this year the conference is being run by students in the MIT Program in Atmospheres, Oceans and Climate, and will be held at Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution on Cape Cod.</s>
    <s>Possible sessions include: Paleoclimate, Atmosphere Dynamics, Oceanography, Biogeochemical Cycles, Cryosphere, Clouds/Aerosols, Biosphere, Climate Change Impacts, Hydrology, and Atmospheric Chemistry.</s>
    <s>You can reach the organizing committee by emailing gcc-2011@mit.edu or reference the conference Web site at: http://gcc2011.scripts.mit.edu/. (6/11)</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>15th Annual Great Divide Weather Workshop, 31 October-2 November 2011, Bozeman, Montana</s>
    <s>The National Weather Service Forecast Offices in Great Falls and Missoula invite you to participate in the 15th Annual Great Divide Weather Workshop. The workshop will be held 31 October-2 November 2011 in Bozeman, Montana, a transportation hub and gateway to the Yellowstone region.</s>
    <s>This year's workshop highlights &quot;Sharing Innovative Science and Service&quot; and will consist of a combination of invited speakers and submitted presentations. The Montana State University Civil Engineering Department and the Optical Technology Center will participate in the workshop. Participation is also encouraged for researchers and practitioners of Meteorology, Hydrology and related fields from across the Northern Rocky Mountains and High Plains, as well as the Pacific Northwest and Great Basin.</s>
    <s>More information, including the workshop agenda and banquet details will be available soon on our &quot;Agenda&quot; page. We hope you can join us for the 2011 workshop. Details at: http://www.wrh.noaa.gov/wrh/greatdivide/welcome.php. The deadline for abstracts is 15 September 2011. (7/11)</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Third Santa Fe Conference on Global and Regional Climate Change, 31 October-3 November 2011, Santa Fe, New Mexico</s>
    <s>The Third Santa Fe Conference on Global and Regional Climate Change is sponsored by Los Alamos National Laboratory Center for Nonlinear Studies, Energy Security Center, and Institute of Geophysics and Planetary Physics and co-sponsored by Brookhaven National Laboratory, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, University of Alaska International Arctic Research Institute, New Mexico Consortium, and American Meteorological Society.</s>
    <s>This conference will focus on climate change and variability from observational, theoretical, and modeling perspectives. Special emphasis will be on climate forcing and feedbacks on global and regional scale, including polar region. Contributions based on conventional as well as non- conventional views on climate change and variability are welcome. The Conference will consist of invited and contributed oral presentations and posters. Presented papers will be considered for publication in a special section of the Journal of Geophysical Research.</s>
    <s>This conference will be the third in a series of conferences held at five years intervals. The purpose of these conferences is to bring together researchers with varied interpretations of current and past global and regional climate change, to present the latest research results (observations, theory, modeling and analysis), and to provide discussion opportunity to top climate experts and students. The first Conference took place in Halifax, Nova Scotia, in 2001, the second in Santa Fe, NM, in 2006. Each Conference was attended by 100-130 researchers from over 15 countries.</s>
    <s>The deadline for abstract submissions is 12 September 2011 to be considered for oral or poster presentations and 17 October 2011 for poster presentation only. Submit abstracts (pdf or word) by email to chylek@lanl.gov with a copy to dubey@lanl.gov.</s>
    <s>For more information concerning the Santa Fe 2011 Conference and to register, please, visit our website at http://cnls.lanl.gov/climate. (8/11)</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>13th Northeast Regional Operational Workshop, 2-3 November 2011, Albany, NY</s>
    <s>The Thirteenth Northeast Regional Operational Workshop (NROW) will be held Wednesday and Thursday, 2-3 November 2011, at the CSTEM Auditorium, on the University at Albany Campus. The workshop will be co-sponsored by the National Weather Service Office at Albany, New York, and the Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences (DAES), University at Albany. The American Meteorological Society is a cooperating organization.</s>
    <s>Papers are welcome on all aspects of Northeast United States and Southeast Canadian operational weather forecasting and should focus on the topics listed. Sessions will focus on, northeast coastal storms, terrain effects, heavy precipitation forecasting, hydrology, northeast severe storms, lake effect, use of high-resolution model data, mesoscale modeling, enhancement of the digital forecast process, CSTAR funded research, and the integration of new technology into operations. Presentations will only be given in oral form. Presenters should submit a one page abstract in Microsoft Word, Times New Roman 12 point font. Abstracts that are in other fonts or formats will be returned. Presenters should either mail a CDROM with their presentation to the address for the Steering Committee below, or upload it to the designated website no later than 9am EDT Tuesday 1 November 2011. Website login will be provided to presenters in mid October 2011. Presentations must be in Microsoft Powerpoint. Conference presentations will be limited to 45. The Steering Committee reserves the right to decline abstracts that do not address conference foci.</s>
    <s>No registration fee will be charged, however registration is mandatory online at the conference website. Registration will open 7 September 2011, and must be completed by 4pm EDT, Monday 24 October 2011. The deadline for submission of abstracts is 4pm EDT Thursday, 20 October 2011. Abstracts should be submitted electronically as email attachments. Presentations should be sent to NROW Steering Committee, c/o Warren R. Snyder, National Weather Service Forecast Office, 251 Fuller Road, Suite B300, Albany, New York 12203, 518-435-9569; e-mail: warren.snyder@noaa.gov. An abstracts book will only be available online, and should be posted at the conference webpage no later than 28 October 2011.</s>
    <s>For additional information contact either Warren Snyder or Peggy Kelly, at the address above, or by fax at 518-435-9587; e-mail: peggy.kelly@noaa.gov. For conference information, online registration, hotel, general information refer to Internet address http://www.erh.noaa.gov/aly/NROW/nrow13.htm. A block of rooms will be reserved. You should check the conference webpage for particulars, and make your reservation. (11/11)</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>48th Oholo Conference: Emerging Remote Sensing Techniques and Associated Modeling for Air Pollution Applications, 6-10 November 2011, Eilat, Eila, Israel</s>
    <s>The 48th Oholo Conference entitled: &quot;Emerging Remote Sensing Techniques and Associated Modeling for Air Pollution Applications&quot; is scheduled to take place at the Hilton Queen of Sheba Hotel in Eilat, Israel on 6-10 November 2011.</s>
    <s>The Oholo Conferences are international meetings on selected topics in life sciences which have been organized by the Israel Institute for Biological Research, ever since 1956. These conferences are designed to bring together scientists from all over the world, whose expertise is in the subject matter of the conference and to provide a fertile medium for free exchange of data, ideas and viewpoints.</s>
    <s>The main focus of the conference will be on the following subjects: Detection and mapping of gaseous and aerosol plumes; Aerosol/droplets measurement and characterization; Wind, temperature and turbulence profiling and retrieval; Networks and sensor/data fusion; Field campaigns and test beds; Model development and validation using remote-sensed data; and Assimilation of remote-sensed observations in numerical models. The deadline for abstracts is 15 August 2011.</s>
    <s>For additional information on the conference, please reference the Web site at: http://www.oholoconference.com/index.ehtml. (8/11)</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Air &amp; Waste Management Association, Conference on Greenhouse Gas Strategies in a Changing Climate, 16-17 November 2011, San Francisco, CA</s>
    <s>The Air &amp; Waste Management Association (A&amp;WMA) will convene a conference on emerging GHG strategies, including regulation, mitigation, and adaptation, and focusing on how the political climate might alter the way climate change is addressed at all levels. The conference is designed to provide a forum for discussing local, state, regional, national, and international programs and initiatives, with a solutions-oriented focus on GHG emissions, reporting, policy, and regulatory issues; mitigation strategies and technologies; linkages to energy efficiency and conservation; and climate change impact assessment and adaptation. It will also examine a range of related topics, and take note of lessons learned from successful implementation strategies.</s>
    <s>The conference will feature a combination of invited panels and contributed technical papers in three main tracks: policy relevant strategies; technical information and tools, and emerging technological solutions. Presentations will cover the latest developments in regulatory and voluntary strategies from the U.S. EPA, state and local Air Pollution Control Agencies, industry, academia, NGOs, the National Labs, and international experts.</s>
    <s>Direct queries to Program Co-Chairs Dr. Miriam Lev-On (e-mail: miriam@levongroup.net, tel: 805-499-4833) or Prof. Bob Bornstein (e-mail: pblmodel@hotmail.com, tel: 415-308-1587) or to Lisa Breese (e-mail: lbreese@awma.org, tel: 412-904-6004). Visit the conference web site (http://www.awma.org/Public/eventlinks/ghgstrategies.aspx) to view an updated agenda or to register. (11/11)</s>
    <s>19th International Congress of Biometeorology, 5-9 December 2011 (ICB 2011), University of Auckland, New Zealand</s>
    <s>The International Society of Biometeorology, formed in 1956, is pleased to announce that its 19th International Congress of Biometeorology (ICB2011) will be held in December 2011 at The University of Auckland, Auckland, New Zealand. The Congress theme will be Climate and Society.</s>
    <s>The overall aim of ICB2011 is to explore the links between climate and society. This is because a central ethos of the interdisciplinary science of Biometeorology is the desire to understand interactions between atmospheric processes and living organisms - plants, animals and humans. Such interactions are fundamental to the well-being and sustainability of society at a range of geographical and time scales. Given this we anticipate the participation of scientists including social scientists and health scientists from a wide range of fields in ICB2011.</s>
    <s>At this stage of the planning process the general ICB2011 programme structure will include plenary sessions, parallel paper sessions, fieldtrips (optional), and social events such as an ice breaker and congress dinner.</s>
    <s>For further information on the conference, please reference the meeting Website at http://www.icb2011.com/. (4/11)</s>
    <s>2012 Meetings of Interest</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Second National Flood Workshop, 27 February-1 March 2012, Houston, Texas</s>
    <s>The Second National Flood Workshop is organized by Weather Research Center (a private, non-profit educational and research center based in Houston, Texas) and its partners. The purpose of this workshop is to bring together various agencies, emergency managers, academia, and professionals from across the nation to encourage dialogue on the various aspects of flooding. This includes the meteorological and hydrological conditions before, during, and after flood events, technological advancements being made in remote data acquisition, flood modeling, and regulations and requirements in flood mitigation and floodplain management. Coastal and offshore operations are also impacted by flood events especially storm surge and high tides from tropical storm and hurricane events which can cause flooding and damage. This year's conference will add a track where coastal and offshore facilities affected by tropical storm and hurricane events can come together and discuss flooding impacts on their operations.</s>
    <s>The goal is to establish a forum to discuss flooding topics, provide education and training, and most importantly to help reduce loss of life and property damage from floods.</s>
    <s>Abstracts are being sought for oral presentations and posters covering a wide range of topics. To be considered for placement in the program, please submit your abstract to wrc@wxresearch.org or upload at http://www.wxresearch.com/nfw/call.html on or before 15 August 2011. All conference presenters are required to pay the appropriate conference registration fee.</s>
    <s>For more information about the workshop, visit http://www.nationalfloodworkshop.net, call Weather Research Center at 713-539-3076 or email wrc@wxresearch.org. (6/11)</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Eighth International Conference on Air Quality--Science and Application, Athens, Greece, 19-23 March 2012</s>
    <s>The Eighth International Conference on Air Quality-Science and Application will be held 19-23 March 2012 in Athens, Greece. This meeting builds upon a long standing series that began at the University of Hertfordshire, UK in July 1996 with subsequent meetings at the Technical University of Madrid (1999), Loutraki, Greece (2001), Charles University, Prague (2003) and Valencia, Spain (2005), Cyprus (2007) and Istanbul, Turkey (2009). The 8th Conference will be hosted in the majestic and historic city of Athens.</s>
    <s>Air quality continues to be a key issue for achieving sustainable development and to reduce health impacts. Its impact spans multiple scales from street level to global including interactions with climate change. As always the conference is one of most prominent forums for discussing the latest scientific developments, applications and implications for policy and other users. An important feature of the conference is that it brings together scientists and other stakeholders from the air pollution, climate change, policy and health communities</s>
    <s>The revised deadline for abstract submissions is Monday 10 October 2011 due to large number of requests received. One page abstracts can be submitted through the AQ 2012 website: www.airqualityconference.org), If you are submitting the abstract for the special sessions, then please select topic &quot;special session ..&quot; while submitting your abstract.z</s>
    <s>For additional information, please send an e-mail to airquality@herts.ac.uk or reference the Conference Website: http://www.airqualityconference.org. (11/11)</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>10th Annual Climate Prediction Applications Science Workshop (CPASW), March, 2012, Miami, Florida</s>
    <s>NOAA's 10th annual Climate Prediction Application Science Workshop (CPASW) will bring together climate information users, tool developers, researchers, and providers to identify recommended state-of the-art science practices on the use of climate information and gaps in climate data and prediction services. The goals of 2012 CPASW are to build a community of climate practitioners, discover user needs, assess impacts of climate forecasts on environmental-societal interactions, identify the science potential for meeting these needs, and provide feedback to producers on the usability of existing climate products. The 10th CPASW will be held in Miami, Florida, during March 2012. The meeting details will be available online at http://www.rsmas.miami.edu/academics/divisions/marine-affairs-policy/cpasw/ and http://www.weather.gov/om/csd/index.php?section=meetings.</s>
    <s>The 2012 CPASW will feature broad discussions revolving around the integrated theme of &quot;Climate Services for National Security Challenges&quot;. The workshop will highlight national and global uses of data and outlooks from seasonal to decadal scales in applications for a broad array of the national security issues: food (including agriculture and fisheries), natural resources, transportation, health, energy, coastal communities, state stability (including border security), international treaties and environmental regulation.</s>
    <s>CPASW 2012 participants will include climate information providers, brokers, and users. We invite abstracts that address the use of climate predictions and projections in all of the focus areas listed above. We also encourage abstracts that identify additional applications of climate information for users in other relevant sectors.</s>
    <s>The abstract deadline is 31 October 2011. Please submit abstracts at http://www.rsmas.miami.edu/academics/divisions/marine-affairs-policy/cpasw/. Registration and logistics information will be available on November 15, 2011.</s>
    <s>For additional information please contact workshop organizers: David Letson (dletson@rsmas.miami.edu) 305-421-4083), Marina Timofeyeva (Marina.Timofeyeva@noaa.gov), 301-713-1970 ext. 131), or Jenna Meyers (Jenna.Meyers@noaa.gov), 301-713-1970 ext.123) (11/11)</s>
    <s>32nd NATO/SPS International Technical Meeting on Air Pollution Modelling and its Application, 7-11 May, 2012, Utrecht, The Netherlands</s>
    <s>In 1969 the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) established the Committee on Challenges of Modern Society (CCMS). The subject of air pollution was from the start, one of the priority problems under study within the framework of various pilot studies undertaken by this committee. The organization of a periodic conference, named NATO/CCMS International Technical Meeting (ITM) on Air Pollution Modelling and its Application has become one of its main activities, now under the new Committee on Science for Peace and Security (SPS). The present 32nd edition will continue the series and represents the high level confidence of both the scientific community and the several conference sponsors.</s>
    <s>For additional information, please contact the conference Web site at: http://www.int-tech-mtng.org/ITM32/index.html. (10/11)</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>46th Canadian Meteorological and Oceanographical Society (CMOS) Congress 2012 Jointly with the AMS 25th Conference on Weather and Forecasting (WAF) and 21st Conference on Numerical Weather Prediction (NWP), 29 May-1 June 2012, Montreal, Quebec, Canada</s>
    <s>The 46th CMOS Congress will be held jointly from 29 May to 1 June 2012 in Montreal (Quebec) with the 21st American Meteorological Society (AMS) Conference on Numerical Weather prediction (NWP) and the 25th AMS Conference on Weather Analysis and Forecasting (WAF). Preliminary programs, registration, hotel, and general information are posted on the CMOS Congress 2012 Web site (http://www.cmos.ca/congress2012/index.htm).</s>
    <s>Papers for the joint CMOS Congress and NWP-WAF conferences are solicited on advances in all aspects of Weather and Forecasting and Numerical Weather prediction, including operational weather forecasting, decision support meteorology, forecasting skill improvement, numerical modeling, data assimilation and predictability. We also welcome abstracts related to weather services, societal impacts and socio-economic research. As the theme of CMOS Congress 2012 is The changing environment and its impact on climate, ocean and weather services, particular emphasis will be placed on topics consistent with this theme. The CMOS congress includes as well general topics in oceanic and atmospheric, climate studies and geophysical fluid dynamics.</s>
    <s>These topics include, first, a broad categorization:</s>
    <s>1) AMS Weather and Forecasting</s>
    <s>2) AMS Numerical weather prediction</s>
    <s>3) CMOS general topics in atmospheric and oceanic sciences, climate, and geophysical fluid dynamics</s>
    <s>The second level of topics common to both the CMOS Congress and the NWP-WAF conferences focus upon themes related to each broader categorization:</s>
    <s>1) Impacts of land-surface processes on numerical weather prediction and weather forecasting</s>
    <s>2) Coupled atmospheric-ocean models and their applications in NWP</s>
    <s>3) Unified weather and climate models</s>
    <s>4) Use of new technology in weather service</s>
    <s>5) Estimating and communicating uncertainty in weather forecasting and NWP</s>
    <s>6) Operational weather forecasting</s>
    <s>7) Decision support meteorology</s>
    <s>8) Forecasting skill improvement</s>
    <s>9) Numerical modeling</s>
    <s>10) Data assimilation and predictability.</s>
    <s>Abstract submission will be open in early of January 2012. Please submit your abstract electronically via the Web by 15 February 2012 (refer to the CMOS Congress 2012 Web site http://www.cmos.ca/congress2012/index.htm). A non-refundable abstract fee of CAD $50 (payable by credit card) is charged at the time of submission. Authors of accepted presentations will be notified via e-mail by late-March 2012. No extended abstract is requested.</s>
    <s>For additional information please contact the program chairpersons, Prof Pierre Gauthier (Gauthier.pierre@ucam.ca) or Bruce Telfeyan (bruce.telfeyan@offutt.af.mil). (10/11)</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Eighth International Conference on Urban Climate (ICUC8) and AMS 10th Symposium on the Urban Environment, 6-10 August 2012, Dublin, Ireland</s>
    <s>The International Association for Urban Climate (IAUC) and the American Meteorological Society (AMS) Board of the Urban Environment (BUE) warmly invite you to the joint 8th International Conference on Urban Climate (ICUC8) and AMS 10th Symposium on the Urban Environment to be held in Dublin, Ireland from August 6-10, 2012. The aims of this AMS/IAUC joint conference are to provide an international forum where the world's urban climatologists can discuss modern developments in research, and the application</s>
    <s>of climatic knowledge to the design of better cities. The deadline for submission of abstract is 31 December 2011, and there will be a competition for student paper award. The conference registration will begin 1 February 2012.</s>
    <s>For more information about this joint conference, please visit http://www.icuc8.org/</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Third International Conference on Earth System Modelling, 17-21 September 2012, Hamburg, Germany</s>
    <s>The Max Planck Institute for Meteorology and the COMBINE project are pleased to announce the Third International Conference on Earth System Modelling (3ICESM). The Third ICESM will take place from 17-21 September 2012 in Hamburg, Germany, with the objective of advancing discourse on Earth system modelling prior to the 5th Assessment Report of the IPCC.</s>
    <s>Oral and poster contributions to the following sessions are invited: Seasonal to decadal climate predictability and prediction; Changing patterns: Shifting climate regimes and their extremes; Clouds, convection and the global energy balance; Carbon and beyond: coupled biogeochemical cycles in the Earth System; Cryospheric processes and changes; Stratospheric and solar influences on surface climate; Lessons from the past: Using and interpreting the paleo-record; and Imagining the future: Integrated assessment modelling and impacts.</s>
    <s>Each session will be introduced by two invited lectures. For submission of abstracts, registration and any other information of the 3ICESM, refer to the conference website: www.meetings.copernicus.org/3icesm. (11/11)</s>
    <s>Headquarters: 45 Beacon Street Boston, MA 02108-3693</s>
    <s>DC Office: 1120 G Street, NW, Suite 800 Washington DC, 20005-3826</s>
    <s>amsinfo@ametsoc.org Phone: 617-227-2425 Fax: 617-742-8718</s>
    <s>2006 American Meteorological Society Privacy Policy and Disclaimer</s>
  </text>
</page>
