<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <query keywords="conference call for papers" position="11" lang="en" date="2011-10-12"/>
  <url>http://www.ieee-security.org/CFP/Cipher-Call-for-Papers.html</url>
  <title>Cipher Call-for-papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Conference/Workshop Call-for Papers. Special Issues of Journals and Handbooks. Archival journals regularly specializing in security and privacy </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Calls for Papers</s>
    <s>IEEE Computer Society's Technical Committee on Security and Privacy</s>
    <s>Cipher Newsletter</s>
    <s>Cipher Calendar</s>
    <s>Calls for Papers</s>
    <s>Call-for-Papers Submission Guidelines</s>
    <s>Upcoming Conferences (submission date has passed)</s>
    <s>Past conferences and journal special issues</s>
    <s>Last Modified:10/10/11</s>
    <s>Note: Please send new calls to cipher-cfp@ieee-security.org and take a moment to read the submission guidelines. And please see the Cipher Calendar for events sorted in date order. For all other questions, please contact cipher-cfp@ieee-security.org by email.</s>
    <s>Conference/Workshop Call-for Papers</s>
    <s>Special Issues of Journals and Handbooks</s>
    <s>Archival journals regularly specializing in security and privacy</s>
    <s>Special Issues of Journals and Handbooks</s>
    <s>IEEE Internet Computing, Track Articles on Computer Crime, 2012, (Submission will be accepted for this track from 15 July 2011 to 15 July 2012) posted here 05/23/11</s>
    <s>Editors: Nasir Memon (New York University, USA) and Oliver Spatscheck (AT&amp;T;, USA)</s>
    <s>As the Internet has grown and extended its reach into every part of peoples lives, it shouldnt be surprising that criminals have seized the opportunity to expand their activities into this new realm. This has been fostered in particular by the fact that the Internet was designed as an open and trusting environment. Unfortunately many of these architectural choices are fundamental to the Internets success and current architecture and are therefore hard to overcome. Computer crime ranges from rather simple crimes such as theft of intellectual property or computer and network resources to complex cooperate espionage or even cyber terrorism. This special track for Internet Computing seeks original articles that cover computer crime as it relates to the Internet. Appropriate topics include:</s>
    <s>- trends and classification of criminal activities on the Internet;</s>
    <s>- computer crime prevention, including approaches implemented in user interfaces, end user systems, networks, or server infrastructure;</s>
    <s>- case studies of criminal activities;</s>
    <s>- computer forensics;</s>
    <s>- impact assessments of criminal activities on the Internet; and</s>
    <s>- new architectures to prevent Internet crime</s>
    <s>Track articles run one per issue for a single calendar year. Articles will be run in the order in which they are accepted for publication.</s>
    <s>For more information, please see http://www.computer.org/portal/web/computingnow/cfptrack.</s>
    <s>Elsevier Computer Networks, Special Issue on Botnet Activity: Analysis, Detection and Shutdown, 2012, (Submission Due 1 December 2011) posted here 09/12/11</s>
    <s>Editors: Ronaldo Salles (Military Institute of Engineering, Brazil), Guofei Gu (Texas A&amp;M; University, USA), Thorsten Holz (Ruhr-University Bochum, Germany), and Morton Swimmer (Trend Micro Deutschland, Germany)</s>
    <s>Large scale attacks and criminal activities experienced in recent years have exposed the Internet to serious security breaches, and alarmed the world regarding cyber crime. In the center of this problem are the so called botnets -- collections of infected zombie machines (bots) controlled by the botmaster to perpetrate malicious activities and massive attacks. Some recent botnets are composed of millions of infected machines, making use of this attack vector inevitably harmfully. Hence, it is paramount to detect, analyze and shutdown such overlay networks before they become active. This special issue of Computer Networks is intended to foster the dissemination of high quality research in all aspects regarding botnet activity, detection and countermeasures. The objective of this special issue is to publish papers presenting detection algorithms, traffic monitoring and identification, protocols and architectures, as well as botnet modeling, behavior, simulation, statistics, dissemination, analysis, preventive procedures and possible countermeasures. Only technical papers describing previously unpublished, original, state-of-the-art research, and not currently under review by a conference or journal will be considered. We solicit papers in a variety of topics related to botnet research including, but not limited to:</s>
    <s>- Traffic Monitoring and Detection Algorithms</s>
    <s>- Data Collection, Statistics and Analysis</s>
    <s>- Modeling Behavior and Simulation</s>
    <s>- Protocols and Architectures (IRC, HTTP, P2P, etc)</s>
    <s>- Firewalls and IDS</s>
    <s>- Cyber Crime Case Studies</s>
    <s>- Reverse Engineering and Automated Analysis of Bots</s>
    <s>- Honeypots and Honeynets</s>
    <s>- New Platforms: Cellular and Wireless networks, Mobile devices, TV, etc.</s>
    <s>- Legal Issues and Countermeasures</s>
    <s>- Underground Markets, Vulnerability Markets and Zero-day Economics</s>
    <s>- Mini-Botnets</s>
    <s>For more information, please see http://www.elsevierscitech.com/dronsite/CFP SIonBotnetActivity.pdf.</s>
    <s>Conference and Workshop Call-for-papers</s>
    <s>October 2011</s>
    <s>WECSR 2012 3rd Workshop on Ethics in Computer Security Research, Divi Flamingo Resort, Bonaire, March 2, 2012. (Submissions due 31 October 2011) posted here 09/01/11</s>
    <s>Computer security often leads to discovering interesting new problems and challenges. The challenge still remains to follow a path acceptable for Institutional Review Boards at academic institutions, as well as compatible with ethical guidelines for professional societies or government institutions. However, no exact guidelines exist for computer security research yet. This workshop will bring together computer security researchers, practitioners, policy makers, and legal experts. This workshop solicits submissions describing or suggesting ethical and responsible conduct in computer security research. While we focus on setting standards and sharing prior experiences and experiments in computer security research, successful or not, we tap into research behavior in network security, computer security, applied cryptography, privacy, anonymity, and security economics. This workshop will favor discussions among participants, in order to shape the future of ethical standards in the field. It will be co-located with the Sixteenth International Conference on Financial Cryptography and Data Security 2012. We solicit submissions in three categories: Position papers, Case studies, and Panel proposals.</s>
    <s>For more information, please see http://www.cs.stevens.edu/~spock/wecsr2012/cfp.html.</s>
    <s>November 2011</s>
    <s>PILATES 2012 Workshop on Physically-augmented Security for Wireless Networks, Kaiserslautern, Germany, March 1921, 2012. (Submissions due 1 November 2011) posted here 10/03/11</s>
    <s>The goal of the PILATES'12 workshop is to discuss &quot;workout plans&quot; in the discipline of physically-augmented wireless security. In particular, the focus lies on taking advantage of physical characteristics of wireless communications as well as of physical context in general or side-channels to increase the &quot;fitness&quot; of conventional security protocols. Both single-hop as well as multi-hop wireless networks are in scope of the workshop. The workshop accepts technical papers and extended abstracts with topics of interest that include but are not limited to:</s>
    <s>- Security primitives derived from wireless communication</s>
    <s>- Physically-augmented cryptographic protocols</s>
    <s>- Physically unclonable functions (PUF)</s>
    <s>- Wireless threat modeling and security analysis</s>
    <s>- Jamming &amp; anti-jamming security protocols</s>
    <s>- Secure localization and positioning</s>
    <s>- Quantitative evaluation of wireless system security</s>
    <s>- Cross-layer approaches to secure wireless communication</s>
    <s>- Utilizing multi-for security (multi-hop, multi-channel, multi-radio, etc.)</s>
    <s>For more information, please see http://mmb2012.de/pilates.</s>
    <s>SP 2012 33rd IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy , San Francisco Bay Area, California, USA, May 20-23, 2012. (Submissions due 16 November 2012) posted here 08/22/11</s>
    <s>Since 1980, the IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy has been the premier forum for computer security research, presenting the latest developments and bringing together researchers and practitioners. We solicit previously unpublished papers offering novel research contributions in any aspect of computer security or privacy. Papers may present advances in the theory, design, implementation, analysis, verification, or empirical evaluation of secure systems. Topics of interest include:</s>
    <s>- Access control</s>
    <s>- Accountability</s>
    <s>- Anonymity</s>
    <s>- Application security</s>
    <s>- Attacks and defenses</s>
    <s>- Authentication</s>
    <s>- Censorship and censorship-resistance</s>
    <s>- Distributed systems security</s>
    <s>- Embedded systems security</s>
    <s>- Forensics</s>
    <s>- Hardware security</s>
    <s>- Intrusion detection</s>
    <s>- Language-based security</s>
    <s>- Malware</s>
    <s>- Metrics</s>
    <s>- Network security</s>
    <s>- Privacy-preserving systems</s>
    <s>- Protocol security</s>
    <s>- Secure information flow</s>
    <s>- Security and privacy policies</s>
    <s>- Security architectures</s>
    <s>- System security</s>
    <s>- Usability and security</s>
    <s>- Web security</s>
    <s>SYSTEMATIZATION OF KNOWLEDGE PAPERS: Following the success of the previous year's conference, we are also soliciting papers focused on systematization of knowledge. The goal of this call is to encourage work that evaluates, systematizes, and contextualizes existing knowledge. These papers will provide a high value to our community but would otherwise not be accepted because they lack novel research contributions. Suitable papers include survey papers that provide useful perspectives on major research areas, papers that support or challenge long-held beliefs with compelling evidence, or papers that provide an extensive and realistic evaluation of competing approaches to solving specific problems. Submissions will be distinguished by a checkbox on the submission form. They will be reviewed by the full PC and held to the same standards as traditional research papers, except instead of emphasizing novel research contributions the emphasis will be on value to the community. Accepted papers will be presented at the symposium and included in the proceedings.</s>
    <s>For more information, please see http://www.ieee-security.org/TC/SP2012/cfp.html.</s>
    <s>USEC 2012 Workshop on Usable Security, Held in conjunction with the Financial Cryptography and Data Security (FC 2012), Divi Flamingo Beach Resort, Bonaire, March 2, 2012. (Submissions due 16 November 2011) posted here 09/15/11</s>
    <s>Many aspects of data security combine technical and human factors. If a highly secure system is unusable, users will move their data to less secure but more usable systems. Problems with usability are a major contributor to many high-profile security failures today. However, usable security is not well-aligned with traditional usability for three reasons. First, security is rarely the desired goal of the individual. In fact, security is usually orthogonal and often in opposition to the actual goal. Second, security information is about risk and threats. Such communication is most often unwelcome. Increasing unwelcome interaction is not a goal of usable design. Third, since individuals must trust their machines to implement their desired tasks, risk communication itself may undermine the value of the networked interaction. For the individual, discrete technical problems are all understood under the rubric of online security (e.g., privacy from third parties use of personally identifiable information, malware). A broader conception of both security and usability is therefore needed for usable security. The workshop on Usable Security invites submissions on all aspects of human factors and usability in the context of security. USEC'12 aims to bring together researchers already engaged in this interdisciplinary effort with other researchers in areas such as economics, intelligent interactions, artificial intelligence, theoretical computer science, and modeling. We encourage AI, HCI, security, psychologists, risk analysts, computer scientists, security specialists, business school faculty, and industry experts to submit original research. We particularly encourage collaborative research from authors in multiple fields.</s>
    <s>For more information, please see http://infosecon.net/usec12/index.php.</s>
    <s>WiSec 2012 ACM Conference on Wireless Network Security, Tucson, Arizona, USA, April 16-18, 2012. (Submissions due 22 November 2011) posted here 10/03/11</s>
    <s>As wireless and mobile networking becomes ubiquitous, security and privacy become increasingly critical. The focus of the ACM Conference on Wireless Network Security (ACM WiSec) is on exploring vulnerabilities, threats, and attacks in wireless communications and the techniques needed to address them. Settings of interest include cellular, metropolitan, mesh, local-area, personal-area, home, vehicular, sensor, ad hoc, satellite, cognitive radio, RFID, and underwater networks as well as systems using non-RF wireless communication. The conference is soliciting contributions to topics including but not limited to:</s>
    <s>- Key management in wireless/mobile environments</s>
    <s>- Secure services (neighbor discovery, localization, etc.)</s>
    <s>- Secure PHY and MAC protocols</s>
    <s>- Trust establishment</s>
    <s>- Intrusion, attack, and malicious behavior detection</s>
    <s>- Denial of service</s>
    <s>- User and location privacy</s>
    <s>- Anonymity, unobservability, prevention of traffic analysis</s>
    <s>- Identity theft and phishing in mobile networks</s>
    <s>- Charging &amp; secure payment</s>
    <s>- Cooperation and mitigating non?cooperative behavior</s>
    <s>- Economics of wireless security</s>
    <s>- Vulnerability and attack modeling</s>
    <s>- Incentive-aware secure protocol design</s>
    <s>- Jamming/Anti-jamming communication</s>
    <s>- Cross-layer design for security</s>
    <s>- Monitoring and surveillance</s>
    <s>- Cryptographic primitives for wireless communication</s>
    <s>- Theoretical foundations and formal methods for wireless security and privacy</s>
    <s>- Security and privacy of mobile OS and mobile applications</s>
    <s>- Secure delay- and disruption-tolerant networking</s>
    <s>- Secure non-RF wireless communication (e.g., ultrasound, vision, laser)</s>
    <s>- Security/privacy in wireless smart grid and smart metering applications</s>
    <s>- Security/privacy in wireless network coding</s>
    <s>- Security/privacy in wireless/ephemeral social networking</s>
    <s>- Security/privacy in mobile/wireless cloud services</s>
    <s>For more information, please see http://www.sigsac.org/wisec/WiSec2012/.</s>
    <s>SFCS 2012 1st IEEE International Workshop on Security and Forensics in Communication Systems, Held in conjunction with IEEE ICC 2012, Ottawa, Canada 10-15 June 2012. (Submissions due 30 November 2011) posted here 10/10/11</s>
    <s>Digital attacks are continuing to increase at an alarming rate. They target a wide variety of protocols and communication systems ranging from servers and end-user machines to wireless and mobile networks and devices. The absence of supporting evidence and technically sound methods may prevent administrators from: proving the identity of the guilty party, identifying the root vulnerability to prevent a future occurrence of a similar incident, and understanding the attackers motivation for an efficient design of security solutions. In this context, digital forensic engineering is emerging as a disciplined science in charge of developing novel scientific and theoretical methods, techniques, and approaches to collect, process, and analyze information retrieved from systems affected by security incidents and generate conclusive descriptions. The SFCS 2012 Workshop will bring together researchers, scientists, engineers and practitioners involved in research in the fields of communication systems security and forensics, to present their latest research findings, ideas, and developments. Topics of interest include, but are not limited to:</s>
    <s>- Formal aspects of network security</s>
    <s>- Theoretical techniques of digital forensics</s>
    <s>- Embedded and handled devices forensic</s>
    <s>- Evidence preservation, management, storage, reassembly, and analysis</s>
    <s>- Anti-forensics prevention detection and analysis</s>
    <s>- Development of Investigation processes and procedures</s>
    <s>- Automated analysis of evidence</s>
    <s>- Forensics in multimedia and communication protocols</s>
    <s>- Security and Investigation techniques in wireless and mobile communication systems</s>
    <s>- Risk analysis and management in communication systems</s>
    <s>- Social networks security and forensics</s>
    <s>- Collaborative and distributed digital investigation</s>
    <s>- Hypothetical reasoning in forensics and incident response</s>
    <s>- Legal and policy issues in digital forensics</s>
    <s>- Intrusion Detection, incident response, and evidence handling</s>
    <s>- Vulnerability analysis and assessment, and analysis of malware</s>
    <s>- Cryptography and forensics techniques in multimedia communication</s>
    <s>- Data hiding, extraction, and recovery techniques</s>
    <s>- Techniques for Tracking and traceback of attacks in systems and networks</s>
    <s>- Availability, privacy, authentication, and anonymity</s>
    <s>- Secure e-services, e-government, e-learning, e-voting, and m-commerce applications</s>
    <s>- File systems memory analysis</s>
    <s>- Infrastructure protection, and Virtual Private Networks security</s>
    <s>- Storage system protection and forensics</s>
    <s>- Physical and Biometric security</s>
    <s>For more information, please see http://sites.google.com/site/sfcs2012/.</s>
    <s>December 2011</s>
    <s>IFIP-CIP 2012 6th Annual IFIP WG 11.10 International Conference on Critical Infrastructure Protection, National Defense University, Fort McNair, Washington, DC, USA, March 1921, 2012. (Submissions due 1 December 2011) posted here 10/03/11</s>
    <s>The IFIP Working Group 11.10 on Critical Infrastructure Protection is an active international community of researchers, infrastructure operators and policy-makers dedicated to applying scientific principles, engineering techniques and public policy to address current and future problems in information infrastructure protection. Following the success of the first five conferences, the Sixth Annual IFIP WG 11.10 International Conference on Critical Infrastructure Protection will again provide a forum for presenting original, unpublished research results and innovative ideas related to all aspects of critical infrastructure protection. Papers and panel proposals are solicited. Submissions will be refereed by members of Working Group 11.10 and other internationally-recognized experts in critical infrastructure protection. Papers and panel submissions will be selected based on their technical merit and relevance to IFIP WG 11.10. The conference will be limited to seventy participants to facilitate interactions among researchers and intense discussions of research and implementation issues. Papers are solicited in all areas of critical infrastructure protection. Areas of interest include, but are not limited to:</s>
    <s>- Infrastructure vulnerabilities, threats and risks</s>
    <s>- Security challenges, solutions and implementation issues</s>
    <s>- Infrastructure sector interdependencies and security implications</s>
    <s>- Risk analysis and risk assessment methodologies</s>
    <s>- Modeling and simulation of critical infrastructures</s>
    <s>- Legal, economic and policy issues related to critical infrastructure protection</s>
    <s>- Secure information sharing</s>
    <s>- Infrastructure protection case studies</s>
    <s>- Distributed control systems/SCADA security</s>
    <s>- Telecommunications network security</s>
    <s>For more information, please see http://www.ifip1110.org.</s>
    <s>ASIACCS 2012 7th ACM Symposium on Information, Computer and Communications Security, Seoul, Republic of Korea, May 1-3, 2012. (Submissions due 8 December 2011) posted here 10/03/11</s>
    <s>ASIACCS is a major international forum for information security researchers, practitioners, developers, and users to explore and exchange the newest cyber security ideas, breakthroughs, findings, techniques, tools, and experiences. We invite submissions from academia, government, and industry presenting novel research on all theoretical and practical aspects of computer and network security. Areas of interest for ASIACCS 2012 include, but are not limited to:</s>
    <s>- anonymity</s>
    <s>- inference/controlled disclosure</s>
    <s>- cryptographic protocols</s>
    <s>- access control</s>
    <s>- intellectual-property protection</s>
    <s>- data/system integrity</s>
    <s>- secure networking</s>
    <s>- operating system security</s>
    <s>- hardware-based security</s>
    <s>- cloud security</s>
    <s>- digital-rights management</s>
    <s>- information warfare</s>
    <s>- accounting and audit</s>
    <s>- trusted computing</s>
    <s>- formal methods for security</s>
    <s>- key management</s>
    <s>- phishing and countermeasures</s>
    <s>- identity management</s>
    <s>- intrusion detection</s>
    <s>- commercial and industry security</s>
    <s>- security in ubiquitous computing, e.g., RFIDs</s>
    <s>- authentication</s>
    <s>- security management</s>
    <s>- smartcards</s>
    <s>- web security</s>
    <s>- security and privacy for emerging technologies, e.g., VoIP, peer-to-peer and overlay network systems, Web 2.0</s>
    <s>- data and application security</s>
    <s>- applied cryptography</s>
    <s>- malware and botnets</s>
    <s>- mobile-computing security</s>
    <s>- privacy-enhancing technology</s>
    <s>- software security</s>
    <s>- wireless security</s>
    <s>For more information, please see http://elec.sch.ac.kr/asiaccs/.</s>
    <s>COSADE 2012 3rd International Workshop on Constructive Side-Channel Analysis and Secure Design, Darmstadt, Germany, May 3-4, 2012. (Submissions due 12 December 2011) posted here 09/12/11</s>
    <s>Side-channel analysis (SCA) and implementation attacks have become an important field of research at universities and in the industry. In order to enhance the resistance of cryptographic and security critical implementations within the design phase, constructive attacks and analyzing techniques may serve as a quality metric to optimize the design- and development process. This workshop provides an international platform for researchers, academics, and industry participants to present their work and their current research topics. It is an excellent opportunity to meet experts and to initiate new collaborations and information exchange at a professional level. The workshop will feature both invited presentations and contributed talks.</s>
    <s>For more information, please see http://cosade2011.cased.de.</s>
    <s>January 2012</s>
    <s>SEC 2012 27th IFIP International Information Security and Privacy Conference, Creta Maris Hotel, Heraklion, Crete, Greece, June 4-6, 2012. (Submissions due 10 January 2012) posted here 08/22/11</s>
    <s>Papers offering novel research contributions in any aspect of computer security are solicited for submission to the 27th IFIP International Information Security and Privacy Conference. The focus is on original, high quality, unpublished research and implementation experiences. Submitted papers must not substantially overlap with papers that have been published or that are simultaneously submitted to a journal or a conference with proceedings. We encourage submissions of papers discussing industrial research and development. Papers should focus on topics which include, but are not limited to, the following:</s>
    <s>- Access control</s>
    <s>- Accountability</s>
    <s>- Anonymity</s>
    <s>- Applied Cryptography</s>
    <s>- Attacks &amp; Malicious Code</s>
    <s>- Authentication &amp; Delegation</s>
    <s>- Awareness &amp; Education</s>
    <s>- Data Integrity</s>
    <s>- Database Security</s>
    <s>- Identity Management</s>
    <s>- Information Security Culture</s>
    <s>- Formal Security Verification</s>
    <s>- Mobile Code Security</s>
    <s>- Policies &amp; Standards</s>
    <s>- Privacy Attitudes &amp; Practices</s>
    <s>- Risk Analysis &amp; Management</s>
    <s>- Security Architectures</s>
    <s>- Security Economics</s>
    <s>- Security in Location Services</s>
    <s>- Security in Social Networks</s>
    <s>- Security Models</s>
    <s>- Social Engineering &amp; other Human-related Risks</s>
    <s>- System Security</s>
    <s>- Usable Security</s>
    <s>- Trust Models &amp; Management</s>
    <s>- Trust Theories</s>
    <s>- Trustworthy User Devices</s>
    <s>For more information, please see http://www.sec2012.org.</s>
    <s>February 2012</s>
    <s>ACNS 2012 10th International Conference on Applied Cryptography and Network Security, Singapore, June 26-29, 2012. (Submissions due 5 February 2012) posted here 08/22/11</s>
    <s>The conference seeks submissions from academia, industry, and government presenting novel research on all aspects of applied cryptography as well as network security and privacy. Papers describing novel paradigms, original directions, or non-traditional perspectives are also encouraged. The conference has two tracks: a research track and an industry track. Topics of interest include, but are not limited to:</s>
    <s>- Access control</s>
    <s>- Applied cryptography</s>
    <s>- Automated protocols analysis</s>
    <s>- Biometric security and privacy</s>
    <s>- Complex systems security</s>
    <s>- Critical infrastructure protection</s>
    <s>- Cryptographic primitives and protocols</s>
    <s>- Database and system security</s>
    <s>- Data protection</s>
    <s>- Digital rights management</s>
    <s>- Email and web security</s>
    <s>- Identity management</s>
    <s>- Intellectual property protection</s>
    <s>- Internet fraud</s>
    <s>- Intrusion detection and prevention</s>
    <s>- Key management</s>
    <s>- Malware</s>
    <s>- Network security protocols</s>
    <s>- Privacy, anonymity, and untraceability</s>
    <s>- Privacy-enhancing technology</s>
    <s>- Policies</s>
    <s>- Protection for the future Internet</s>
    <s>- Security in P2P systems</s>
    <s>- Security and privacy in cloud and grid systems</s>
    <s>- Security in e-commerce</s>
    <s>- Security in pervasive/ubiquitous computing</s>
    <s>- Security and privacy in distributed systems</s>
    <s>- Security and privacy in smart grids</s>
    <s>- Security and privacy in wireless networks</s>
    <s>- Security and privacy metrics</s>
    <s>- Secure mobile agents and mobile code</s>
    <s>- Trust management</s>
    <s>- Usability and security</s>
    <s>For more information, please see http://icsd.i2r.a-star.edu.sg/acns2012.</s>
    <s>Archival Journals Regularly Specializing in Security and Privacy</s>
    <s>Journal of Privacy Technology (JOPT), Editor-in-Chief: Latanya Sweeney</s>
    <s>This online-only Journal, started in 2004 and operated by Carnegie Mellon University, is a forum for the publication of original current research in privacy technology. It encourages the submission of any material dealing primarily with the technological aspects of privacy or with the privacy aspects of technology, which may include analysis of the interaction between policy and technology or the technological implications of legal decisions. More information can be found at http://www.jopt.org/.</s>
    <s>IEEE Security and Privacy Magazine , Editor-in-Chief: Carl E. Landwehr</s>
    <s>IEEE Security &amp; Privacy provides a unique combination of research articles, case studies, tutorials, and regular departments covering diverse aspects of information assurance such as legal and ethical issues, privacy concerns, tools to help secure information, analysis of vulnerabilities and attacks, trends and new developments, pedagogical and curricular issues in educating the next generation of security professionals, secure operating systems and applications, security issues in wireless networks, design and test strategies for secure and survivable systems, and cryptology. More information can be found at http://computer.org/security/.</s>
    <s>ACM Transactions on Information and System Security , Editor-in-Chief: Gene Tsudik</s>
    <s>ACM invites submissions for its Transactions on Information and System Security, inaugurated in November 1998. TISSEC publishes original archival-quality research papers and technical notes in all areas of information and system security including technologies, systems, applications, and policies. Papers should have practical relevance to the construction, evaluation, application, or operation of secure systems. Theoretical papers will be accepted only if there is convincing argument for the practical significance of the results. Theory must be justified by convincing examples illustrating its application. More information is given on the journal web page at http://www.acm.org/tissec.</s>
    <s>IEEE Transactions on Dependable and Secure Computing , Editor-in-Chief: Virgil D. Gligor</s>
    <s>The IEEE Transactions on Dependable and Secure Computing publishes archival research results related to research into foundations, methodologies, and mechanisms that support the achievementthrough design, modeling, and evaluationof systems and networks that are dependable and secure to the desired degree without compromising performance. The focus will also include measurement, modeling, and simulation techniques, and foundations for jointly evaluating, verifying, and designing for performance, security, and dependability constraints. More information is given on the journal web page at http://www.computer.org/tdsc/.</s>
    <s>The Kluwer International Series on ADVANCES IN INFORMATION SECURITY .</s>
    <s>The purpose of the Advances in Information Security book series is to establish the state of the art and set the course for future research in information security. The scope of this series includes not only all aspects of computer and network security, but related areas such as fault tolerance and software assurance. The series will serve as a central source of reference for information security research and developments. The series aims to publish thorough and cohesive overviews on specific topics in Information Security, as well as works that are larger in scope than survey articles and that will contain more detailed background information. The series also provides a single point of coverage of advanced and timely topics and a forum for topics that may not have reached a level of maturity to warrant a comprehensive textbook. Prospective Authors or Editors: If you have an idea for a book that would fit in this series, we would welcome the opportunity to review your proposal. Should you wish to discuss any potential project further or receive specific information regarding book proposal requirements, please contact either Sushil Jajodia (jajodia@gmu.edu,703-993-1653) or Lance Wobus (lance.wobus@wkap.com, 781-681-0602)</s>
    <s>Journal of Computer Security , Editor-in-Chief: Sushil Jadodia and Jonathan Millen</s>
    <s>JCS is an archival research journal for significant advances in computer security. Subject areas include architecture, operating systems, database systems, networks, authentication, distributed systems, formal models, verification, algorithms, mechanisms, and policies. Submissions: send six copies to one of the editors in chief: Sushil Jadodia, CSIS, George Mason University, 440 University Drive, Fairfax, VA 22030, or Jonathan Millen, The MITRE Corporation, 202 Burlington Rd., Bedford, MA. Subscriptions: contact IOS Press, Niewe Hemweg 6B, 1013 BG Amsterdam, Netherlands, (e-mail: order@iospress.nl) for information about individual or institutional subscriptions or back issues. More information is given on the journal web page at http://www.mitre.org/jcs.</s>
    <s>Computers &amp; Security , Editor-in-Chief: Dimitris Gritzalis</s>
    <s>Computers &amp; Security aims to satisfy the needs of managers and experts involved in computer security by providing a blend of research developments, innovations, and practical management advice. Original submissions on all computer security topics are invited, particularly those of practical benefit to the practitioner. Four copies of papers from 5-10,000 words should be sent to the editor, N. Dudley, at Elsevier Advanced Technology, P.O. Box 150, Kidlington, Oxford, OX5 1AS, United Kingdom. Telephones: voice +44(0)1865 843848 / 843000; fax +44 (0) 1865 843971. More information can be found at http://www.elsevier.com/locate/issn/01674048.</s>
    <s>International Journal of Information Security , Editors-in-Chief: D. Gollmann; J. Lopez; E. Okamoto</s>
    <s>The International Journal of Information Security, IJIS, aims to provide prompt publication of important technical work in information security, attracting any person interested in communications, commerce, banking, medicine, or other areas of endeavor affected by information security. Any research submission on theory, applications, and implementations of information security is welcomed. This includes, but is not limited to, system security, network security, content protection, applications and foundations of information security. More information is given on the journal web page at http://link.springer.de/link/service/journals/10207/index.htm.</s>
    <s>International Journal of Network Security , Editors-in-Chief: Min-Shiang Hwang</s>
    <s>International Journal of Network Security is an international official journal of Science Publications, publishing original articles, reviews and short communications of a high scientific and technology in network security. Subjects covered include: access control, computer security, cryptography, communications security, data security, database security, electronic commerce security, information security, multimedia security, and network security. Authors are strongly encouraged to submit their papers electronically by using online manuscript submission at http://ijns.nchu.edu.tw/, or submit their Word, ps or pdf file to the editor-in-chief (via Email: mshwang@isrc.nchu.edu.tw): Min-Shiang Hwang, at the Department of Management Information Systems, National Chung Hsing University, Taiwan, R.O.C. More information can be found at http://ijns.nchu.edu.tw/.</s>
    <s>International Journal of Security and Networks , Editors-in-Chief: Yang Xiao</s>
    <s>International Journal of Security and Networks is an archival research journal for significant advances in network security. Subject areas include attack models, security mechanisms, security services, authentication, authorization, access control, multicast security, data confidentiality, data integrity, non-repudiation, forensics, privacy protection, secure protocols, formal analyses, intrusion detection, key management, trust establishment, revocation of malicious parties, security policies, fraudulent usage, dependability and reliability, prevention of traffic analysis, network security performance evaluation, tradeoff analysis between performance and security, security standards, etc. All papers must be submitted online at http://www.inderscience.com/ijsn/. More information is given on the journal web page at http://www.inderscience.com/ijsn/.</s>
    <s>International Journal of Critical Infrastructure Protection , Editors-in-Chief: Sujeet Shenoi</s>
    <s>International Journal of Critical Infrastructure Protection's primary aim is to publish high quality scientific and policy papers in all areas of critical infrastructure protection. Of particular interest are articles that weave science, technology and policy to craft sophisticated yet practical solutions that will secure information, computer and network assets in the various critical infrastructure sectors. All papers must be submitted online at http://www.elsevier.com/locate/ijcip. More information is given on the journal web page at http://www.elsevier.com/locate/ijcip.</s>
    <s>IEEE Transactions on Information Forensics and Security , Editors-in-Chief: Nasir D. Memon</s>
    <s>IEEE Transactions on Information Forensics and Security aims to provide a unified locus for archival research on the fundamental contributions and the mathematics behind information forensics, information security, surveillance, and systems applications that incorporate these features. Authors are strongly encouraged to submit their papers electronically to the online manuscript system, Manuscript Central, via sps-ieee.manuscriptcentral.com. More information can be found at http://www.ieee.org/organizations/society/sp/tifs.html.</s>
  </text>
</page>
