<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <query keywords="conference call for papers" position="5" lang="en" date="2011-10-12"/>
  <url>http://www.h-net.org/announce/show.cgi%3FID%3D188605</url>
  <title>Michigan Academy 2012 Conference - Call for Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Oct 5, 2011 Michigan Academy of Science, Arts &amp; Letters - Call for Papers for 2012 conference. Submit a 200 word abstract by 11/28/11. </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>about search site map people donate contact help</s>
    <s>Job Guide</s>
    <s>Discussion Networks</s>
    <s>Search Announcements</s>
    <s>Advanced Search</s>
    <s>Announcements Home</s>
    <s>Make an Announcement</s>
    <s>Announcements Policy</s>
    <s>Subscribe to H-Announce</s>
    <s>H-Announce Info.</s>
    <s>Advanced Search</s>
    <s>Events Locator</s>
    <s>See if there is an academic event in your area</s>
    <s>United States ArgentinaArmeniaAustraliaAustriaAzerbaijan RepublicBahrainBangladeshBarbadosBelgiumBrazilCanadaChinaColombiaCubaCyprusCzech RepublicDenmarkEstoniaFinlandFranceGeorgiaGermanyGhanaGreeceHong KongHungaryIndiaIndonesiaIrelandIsraelItalyJamaicaJapanKorea, SouthLebanonLithuaniaLuxembourgMalaysiaMaliMexicoMoroccoNetherlandsNew ZealandNigeriaPakistanPeruPhilippinesPolandPortugalPuerto RicoRomaniaRussiaSaudi ArabiaSingaporeSloveniaSouth AfricaSpainSurinameSwedenSwitzerlandTaiwanThailandTurkeyUkraineUnited Arab EmiratesUnited Kingdom</s>
    <s>Need to refer to an old announcement? Select a category of archives below</s>
    <s>-- Categories -- Conferences Calls for Papers Calls for Publications Programs Funding Websites</s>
    <s>!H-Net Announcement</s>
    <s>Michigan Academy 2012 Conference - Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Michigan, United States</s>
    <s>Call for Papers Date:</s>
    <s>Date Submitted:</s>
    <s>Announcement ID:</s>
    <s>Michigan Academy of Science, Arts &amp; Letters - Call for Papers for 2012 conference. Submit a 200 word abstract by 11/28/11. See themichiganacademy.org website for CfP and to submit your abstract. Conference location is Alma College, Alma, Michigan on Friday, March 2nd. This multi-disciplinary/interdisciplinary conference includes more than 30 sections (disciplines) in the sciences, humanities, and social sciences. College faculty, administrators, graduate students, and undergrads (must be sponsored by faculty members)are invited to submit abstracts. Also invited to submit abstracts are: researchers from non-profit and for-profit organizations, librarians, government employees, K-12 employees, and other professionals.</s>
    <s>Karen Gross, Director</s>
    <s>Michigan Academy of Science, Arts &amp; Letters</s>
    <s>Alma College, 614 W. Superior, Alma, MI 48801</s>
    <s>ph. (989)-463-7969</s>
    <s>fax (989)-463-7970</s>
    <s>Email: michiganacademy@alma.edu</s>
    <s>Visit the website at http://themichiganacademy.org</s>
    <s>Didn't find what you're looking for?</s>
    <s>Try our power search!</s>
    <s>Return to the top of this page</s>
    <s>Return to announcements home</s>
    <s>Send comments and questions to H-Net Webstaff. H-Net reproduces announcements that have been submitted to us as a free service to the academic community. If you are interested in an announcement listed here, please contact the organizers or patrons directly. Though we strive to provide accurate information, H-Net cannot accept responsibility for the text of announcements appearing in this service. (Administration)</s>
    <s>Humanities &amp; Social</s>
    <s>Sciences Online</s>
    <s>Copyright (C) 1995-2007 - Contact Us</s>
    <s>RSS | Validate: XHTML | CSS</s>
  </text>
</page>
