<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <query keywords="conference call for papers" position="1" lang="en" date="2011-10-12"/>
  <url>http://cfp.english.upenn.edu/</url>
  <title>Calls for Papers | cfp.english.upenn.edu</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>http://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/submit The Call for Papers website is provided by the Department of English at the University of Pennsylvania as a </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>a service provided by penn english</s>
    <s>subscribe to CFP</s>
    <s>search the archive</s>
    <s>all recent posts</s>
    <s>bibliography and history of the book</s>
    <s>childrens literature</s>
    <s>classical studies</s>
    <s>cultural studies and historical approaches</s>
    <s>ecocriticism and environmental studies</s>
    <s>eighteenth century</s>
    <s>ethnicity and national identity</s>
    <s>film and television</s>
    <s>gender studies and sexuality</s>
    <s>general announcements</s>
    <s>graduate conferences</s>
    <s>humanities computing and the internet</s>
    <s>international conferences</s>
    <s>journals and collections of essays</s>
    <s>modernist studies</s>
    <s>popular culture</s>
    <s>professional topics</s>
    <s>rhetoric and composition</s>
    <s>science and culture</s>
    <s>travel writing</s>
    <s>twentieth century and beyond</s>
    <s>administrative login</s>
    <s>Calls for Papers</s>
    <s>submit a new CFP</s>
    <s>When submitting a CFP, please choose only those categories related to your posting. Overuse of category tags dilutes search capability and detracts from the usefulness of this site.</s>
    <s>We no longer offer mass mailing functionality. Submissions will appear only in the web archives, sorted by category. Submissions must be reviewed by our staff before they are be published to the website. It will generally take about 24 hours for the submissions to appear live, although it can take longer on the weekends or near holidays. We appreciate your patience.</s>
    <s>Email subscriptions to the list have been halted. All list traffic now passes through our web interface. Email mass mailings have been replaced with RSS feeds.</s>
    <s>Alerts and updates about the list itself will be posted here to this front page.</s>
    <s>If you have any questions about a particular CFP, please contact the submitter. For technical questions, please contact</s>
    <s>The Call for Papers website is provided by the Department of English at the University of Pennsylvania as a courtesy to the academic community. We can not verify the validity of offers posted on this site. We encourage all participants to use caution when responding to solicitations from unfamiliar people or organizations, or visiting their websites. Specifically, we caution users against providing any of the following information to unknown parties:</s>
    <s>Social Security number</s>
    <s>Date of birth</s>
    <s>Passwords for any account or service</s>
    <s>Financial information</s>
    <s>Physical (postal) address</s>
    <s>Phone numbers</s>
    <s>Any intellectual property which you are not ready to make available to the public at large</s>
    <s>More information about how to protect yourself against fraudulent email messages or web sites is available at http://www.antiphishing.org/consumer recs.html.</s>
    <s>CFP Website maintained by</s>
    <s>The University of Pennsylvania Department of English</s>
  </text>
</page>
