<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://repeatingislands.com/2011/09/08/call-for-papers-fourth-international-maroon-conference/</url>
  <title>Call for Papers: Fourth International Maroon Conference ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Sep 8, 2011 Call for Papers: Fourth International Maroon Conference. Fourth International Maroon Conference, “Independence,” in Charles Town, Portland, </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Repeating Islands</s>
    <s>News and commentary on Caribbean culture, literature, and the arts</s>
    <s>About Us</s>
    <s>Our Blog</s>
    <s>Posted by: lisaparavisini | September 8, 2011</s>
    <s>Call for Papers: Fourth International Maroon Conference</s>
    <s>!Fourth International Maroon Conference, &quot;Independence,&quot; in Charles Town, Portland, Jamaica, June 20-24, 2012</s>
    <s>This multidisciplinary conference seeks papers that explore treatments of Maroon culture in history, literature, ethnography, anthropology, sociology, archeology, political theory, cultural studies, film, linguistics, art, music, and theatre.  It strives to examine the values and practices of maroons and marronage and the ways they have influenced and transformed the Caribbean, Canada, South America, Europe, the United States and Africa. With its theme of “Independence,” the conference links the Maroon defeat of the English in 1739 with the fiftieth anniversary of Jamaican independence from England in 1962 to celebrate both events. Offering a unique combination of scholarly panels and cultural performances, the Fourth International Maroon conference aims to increase awareness of Maroon contributions to contemporary societies, bringing together descendants of Maroons with scholars interested in Maroon heritage and indigenous cultures.</s>
    <s>Please send abstracts by 15 November or inquiries to fbotkin@towson.edu</s>
    <s>Share this:</s>
    <s>Like this:</s>
    <s>One blogger likes this post.</s>
    <s>Posted in Caribbean Culture, History | Tags: Call for Papers, Jamaica, maroons, marronage</s>
    <s>« Carribean Cultural Music Conference 2011</s>
    <s>BVI Named for Best Quality of Life in the Caribbean and Central America »</s>
    <s>1. !</s>
    <s> Fourth International Maroon Conference, &quot;The Return,&quot; in Charles Town, Portland, Jamaica, June 20-24, 2012 This multidisciplinary conference seeks papers that explore treatments of Maroon culture in history, literature, ethnography, anthropology, sociology, archeology, political theory, cultural studies, film, linguistics, art, music, and theatre.  It strives to examine the values and practices of maroons and marronage and the ways they have infl … Read More </s>
    <s>By: Call for Papers: Fourth International Maroon Conference (via Repeating Islands) « Diana Brydon on September 8, 2011</s>
    <s>at 12:04 pm</s>
    <s>2. !</s>
    <s> With its theme of “Independence,” the conference links the Maroon defeat of the English in 1739 with the fiftieth anniversary of Jamaican independence from England in 1962 to celebrate both events. Fourth International Maroon Conference, &quot;The Return,&quot; in Charles Town, Portland, Jamaica, June 20-24, 2012 This multidisciplinary conference seeks papers that explore treatments of Maroon culture in history, literature, ethnography, anthropology, sociology, archeology, political theory, cultural studies, film, linguistics, art, music, and theatre.  It strives to examine the values and practices of maroons and marronage and the ways they have infl … Read More </s>
    <s>By: Call for Papers: Fourth International Maroon Conference (via Repeating Islands) « Diana Brydon on September 8, 2011</s>
    <s>at 12:05 pm</s>
    <s>3. ACRAH reblogged this from THE GRAPEVINE.</s>
    <s>By: ACRAH on September 12, 2011</s>
    <s>at 11:11 am</s>
    <s>Leave a Reply Cancel reply</s>
    <s>Enter your comment here </s>
    <s>Log In</s>
    <s>Log In</s>
    <s>Log In</s>
    <s>Email (required) (Not published)</s>
    <s>Name (required)</s>
    <s>!WordPress.com Logo</s>
    <s>Please log in to WordPress.com to post a comment to your blog.</s>
    <s>!Twitter picture</s>
    <s>You are commenting using your Twitter account. (Log Out)</s>
    <s>!Facebook photo</s>
    <s>You are commenting using your Facebook account. (Log Out)</s>
    <s>Connecting to %s</s>
    <s>Notify me of follow-up comments via email.</s>
    <s>Notify me of new posts via email.</s>
    <s>Architecture/Urban Planning</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Call for Submissions</s>
    <s>Caribbean Culture</s>
    <s>New Books</s>
    <s>Upcoming Events</s>
    <s>September 2011</s>
    <s>M T W T F S S</s>
    <s>« Aug</s>
    <s>Oct »</s>
    <s>Recent Posts</s>
    <s>Franklin Knight: The art of Keith Morrison</s>
    <s>Celebrating the Centenary of Jamaica’s Calabar High (Part III)</s>
    <s>Former Miss World Wilnelia Merced now officially “Lady Forsyth”</s>
    <s>Lyn Di Iorio Speaks about Writing &quot;Outside the Bones&quot;</s>
    <s>Every Day is Columbus Day in the Port of Mayagüez, home to “that” statue</s>
    <s>Bahamian director wins first-ever Focus: Filmmakers’ Immersion</s>
    <s>St. Croix’s Fall Heritage Festival</s>
    <s>Yane Mareine and &quot;Chants Graffiti&quot; in Paris</s>
    <s>New Book: Lyn Di Iorio's “Outside the Bones”</s>
    <s>Bon Anniversaire, Île en île!</s>
    <s>Top Posts</s>
    <s>Turks and Caicos Islands Join Anguilla in Critiquing British Rule</s>
    <s>So White It’s Wrong: Vybz Kartel launches line of skin bleaching products</s>
    <s>Jamaican Dancehall Star Vybz Kartel Bleached Skin?</s>
    <s>Divali (Festival of Lights) in Trinidad &amp; Tobago</s>
    <s>Anya Ayoung Chee at Project Runway</s>
    <s>Another Royal Caribbean: Puerto Rico-born Lady Forsyth</s>
    <s>Vybz Kartel, Beyonce, Skin Lightening, and Racism: A Renewed/Old Obsession?</s>
    <s>Esquire dubs Rihanna 'Sexiest Woman Alive'</s>
    <s>Earl Lovelace: Written in the rhythm of the Caribbean</s>
    <s>About Us</s>
    <s>Amitava Kumar</s>
    <s>île en île</s>
    <s>Bel Peyi Mwen</s>
    <s>Caribbean Philosophical Association</s>
    <s>Caribbean Review of Books</s>
    <s>Caribbean Studies Association</s>
    <s>Centro de Estudios del Caribe-Casa de las Americas</s>
    <s>Centro de Estudios Puertorriqueños</s>
    <s>Gens de la Caraïbe</s>
    <s>Haitian Studies Association</s>
    <s>Instituto de Cultura Puertorriqueña</s>
    <s>La Ventana</s>
    <s>News from Caribbean Tales</s>
    <s>Ordinary Annointments</s>
    <s>Paramaribo SPAN</s>
    <s>Puerto Rican Studies Association</s>
    <s>October 2011 (109)</s>
    <s>September 2011 (264)</s>
    <s>August 2011 (249)</s>
    <s>July 2011 (249)</s>
    <s>June 2011 (257)</s>
    <s>May 2011 (240)</s>
    <s>April 2011 (265)</s>
    <s>March 2011 (199)</s>
    <s>February 2011 (233)</s>
    <s>January 2011 (254)</s>
    <s>December 2010 (257)</s>
    <s>November 2010 (246)</s>
    <s>October 2010 (251)</s>
    <s>September 2010 (250)</s>
    <s>August 2010 (202)</s>
    <s>July 2010 (212)</s>
    <s>June 2010 (196)</s>
    <s>May 2010 (236)</s>
    <s>April 2010 (254)</s>
    <s>March 2010 (275)</s>
    <s>February 2010 (234)</s>
    <s>January 2010 (244)</s>
    <s>December 2009 (211)</s>
    <s>November 2009 (237)</s>
    <s>October 2009 (221)</s>
    <s>September 2009 (213)</s>
    <s>August 2009 (220)</s>
    <s>July 2009 (159)</s>
    <s>June 2009 (184)</s>
    <s>May 2009 (216)</s>
    <s>April 2009 (169)</s>
    <s>March 2009 (84)</s>
    <s>February 2009 (3)</s>
    <s>About Us</s>
    <s>Our Blog</s>
    <s>Log in</s>
    <s>Entries RSS</s>
    <s>Comments RSS</s>
    <s>Email Subscription</s>
    <s>Enter your email address to subscribe to this blog and receive notifications of new posts by email.</s>
    <s>Join 449 other followers</s>
    <s>art exhibition Bahamas Barack Obama Barbados Belize bermuda Bob Marley Buju Banton Caribbean Caribbean art cholera outbreak climate change Colombia Cuba Curaçao Derek walcott Dominica Dominican Republic Earthquake earthquake relief Edwidge Danticat Environment Fidel Castro Guadeloupe Guyana Haiti Havana Jamaica Martinique Michel Martelly Montserrat photography Puerto Rico reggae Rene Preval Silvio Rodriguez St. Lucia Suriname the Bahamas Trinidad and Tobago U. S. Virgin Islands United Nations University of Puerto Rico V. S. Naipaul Wyclef Jean</s>
    <s>Blog at WordPress.com. | Theme: Ocean Mist by Ed Merritt. Fonts on this blog.</s>
    <s>Follow Repeating Islands</s>
    <s>Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.</s>
    <s>Join 449 other followers</s>
    <s>Powered by WordPress.com</s>
    <s>Send to Email Address Your Name Your Email Address</s>
    <s>!loading Cancel</s>
    <s>Post was not sent - check your email addresses</s>
    <s>Email check failed, please try again</s>
    <s>Sorry, your blog cannot share posts by email.</s>
    <s>*RSS: Really Simple Syndication</s>
  </text>
</page>
