<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.ap-ls.org/conferences/apls2011/Call.php</url>
  <title>Conference Call for Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>If you have any questions or comments regarding the call for papers, or about the conference, please feel free to contact one of the conference co-chairs: </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>HOME | CONTACT US | SITEMAP | MEMBERS</s>
    <s>About AP-LS</s>
    <s>Membership Information &gt;</s>
    <s>Membership Information</s>
    <s>Join AP-LS</s>
    <s>Existing Members Login</s>
    <s>AP-LS Officers</s>
    <s>AP-LS Committees &gt;</s>
    <s>Mentorship Committee</s>
    <s>Minority Affairs Committee</s>
    <s>Professional Development of Women Committee</s>
    <s>Help Wanted: Committee and Service Opportunities</s>
    <s>AP-LS Grants &gt;</s>
    <s>Student Grants in Aid</s>
    <s>Early Career Grants in Aid</s>
    <s>Diversity in Psychology &amp; Law Research Award</s>
    <s>Access Path to Psychology and Law Experience</s>
    <s>Interdisciplinary Research Grant</s>
    <s>AP-LS Awards &amp; Recognition &gt;</s>
    <s>Undergraduate Paper Award</s>
    <s>Dissertation Award</s>
    <s>Saleem Shah Early Career Award</s>
    <s>Teaching &amp; Mentoring Award</s>
    <s>Distinguished Contributions to Psychology &amp; Law</s>
    <s>Book Award</s>
    <s>Contributions to Correctional Psychology</s>
    <s>APA Fellows</s>
    <s>About Psychology &amp; Law</s>
    <s>Information about the Discipline</s>
    <s>Information for Practitioners</s>
    <s>Information &amp; Links</s>
    <s>Specialty Guidelines for Forensic Psychologists</s>
    <s>Information for Legal Professionals</s>
    <s>Information for Educators</s>
    <s>Information for Researchers</s>
    <s>Information for Students</s>
    <s>Education &amp; Training</s>
    <s>Graduate Training Programs &gt;</s>
    <s>Clinical Doctoral Programs</s>
    <s>Non-Clinical PhD Programs</s>
    <s>Masters Programs</s>
    <s>Pre-Doctoral Internship Training Programs</s>
    <s>Postdoctoral Training Programs &gt;</s>
    <s>Forensic Post-Doctoral Fellowship Training Programs</s>
    <s>Certificate Programs</s>
    <s>Teaching Resources &gt;</s>
    <s>Undergraduate Syllabus Collection</s>
    <s>Graduate Syllabus Collection</s>
    <s>Teaching Techniques</s>
    <s>Other Teaching Resources</s>
    <s>Grants &amp; Funding &gt;</s>
    <s>Student Grants in Aid</s>
    <s>Diversity in Psychology &amp; Law Research Award</s>
    <s>Access Path to Psychology and Law Experience</s>
    <s>Other Funding Resources</s>
    <s>Awards &amp; Recognition &gt;</s>
    <s>Teaching &amp; Mentoring Faculty Award</s>
    <s>Undergraduate Paper Award</s>
    <s>Dissertation Award</s>
    <s>Research &amp; Publications</s>
    <s>Conferences &gt;</s>
    <s>Joint 2011 International Conference</s>
    <s>APA 2011 Convention</s>
    <s>AP-LS 2012 Conference</s>
    <s>Other Conferences</s>
    <s>Research Activities &gt;</s>
    <s>Research Lab Web Sites</s>
    <s>Research in the News</s>
    <s>Research Topic Links</s>
    <s>Law and Human Behavior</s>
    <s>AP-LS Newsletter, Books &amp; Other Publications &gt;</s>
    <s>AP-LS Newsletter</s>
    <s>AP-LS Book Series</s>
    <s>Other Books &amp; Journals</s>
    <s>Calls for Papers</s>
    <s>Grants &amp; Funding &gt;</s>
    <s>Student Grants in Aid</s>
    <s>Early Career Grants in Aid</s>
    <s>Diversity in Psychology &amp; Law Research Award</s>
    <s>Access Path to Psychology and Law Experience</s>
    <s>Interdisciplinary Research Grant</s>
    <s>Other Funding Resources</s>
    <s>Grant Writing Resources</s>
    <s>Awards &amp; Recognition &gt;</s>
    <s>Undergraduate Paper Award</s>
    <s>Dissertation Award</s>
    <s>Other Awards</s>
    <s>Students &amp; Early Career</s>
    <s>AP-LS Student Section Web Site &gt;</s>
    <s>Information &amp; Links</s>
    <s>Current Campus Representatives</s>
    <s>Becoming a Campus Representative</s>
    <s>Interviews &amp; Advice</s>
    <s>Early Career Professional Resources &gt;</s>
    <s>Information &amp; Links</s>
    <s>Early Career Grants in Aid</s>
    <s>Saleem Shah Early Career Award</s>
    <s>Graduate Student Resources &gt;</s>
    <s>Information &amp; Links</s>
    <s>Mentorship Committee</s>
    <s>Student Grants in Aid</s>
    <s>Dissertation Award</s>
    <s>Undergradauate Student Resources &gt;</s>
    <s>Information &amp; Links</s>
    <s>Careers in Psychology and Law</s>
    <s>Graduate Program Listing</s>
    <s>Undergraduate Paper Award</s>
    <s>Employment Resources &gt;</s>
    <s>Job Listings</s>
    <s>Other Resources</s>
    <s>Quick Links</s>
    <s>Research &amp; Publications Section Page</s>
    <s>Joint 2011 International Conference</s>
    <s>APA 2011 Convention</s>
    <s>AP-LS 2012 Conference</s>
    <s>Other Conferences</s>
    <s>Research Activities &gt;</s>
    <s>Research Lab Web Sites</s>
    <s>Research in the News</s>
    <s>Research Topic Links</s>
    <s>AP-LS Official Journal: Law and Human Behavior</s>
    <s>AP-LS Newsletter, Books &amp; OtherPublications &gt;</s>
    <s>AP-LS Newsletter</s>
    <s>AP-LS Book Series</s>
    <s>Other Books &amp; Journals</s>
    <s>Calls for Papers</s>
    <s>Grants &amp; Funding &gt;</s>
    <s>AP-LS Grants in Aid</s>
    <s>Diversity in Psychology &amp; Law Research Award</s>
    <s>Access Path to Psychology and Law Experience</s>
    <s>Other Research Funding Resources</s>
    <s>Grant Writing</s>
    <s>Awards &amp; Recognition &gt;</s>
    <s>Undergraduate Paper Award</s>
    <s>Dissertation Award</s>
    <s>Other Awards</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>The 2011 AP-LS Annual Meeting will be held in conjunction with the 4th International Congress of Psychology and Law from March 2-6, 2011 at the Hyatt Regency Miami Hotel in Miami, Florida. Both the European Association of Psychology and Law (EAPL) and the Australian &amp; New Zealand Association of Psychiatry, Psychology, &amp; Law (ANZAPPL) will be partnering with the American Psychology-Law Society (AP-LS) for the International Congress.</s>
    <s>We invite proposals for symposia, papers, and posters addressing topics in all areas of psychology and law. We especially welcome proposals that are empirically based and those that involve new and emerging topics within psychology and law. Proposals will be evaluated through a blind review process focused on the following three criteria: (1) the intellectual merit of the proposal, (2) the innovative nature of the proposal, and (3) the proposal's integration of multiple aspects of the field of psychology and law.</s>
    <s>A symposium proposal is appropriate for a coordinated group of presentations that will focus on one topic. Symposium proposals must include a minimum of four presentations and a discussant. The discussant must be independent of the lab or research projects that are presented in the symposium. Each participant and the topics to be discussed should be outlined in the proposal. The participation of each presenter should be secured before submitting the proposal. (Each symposium session at the conference will be allotted up to 80 minutes.) In keeping with the international nature of this conference, higher priority will be given to proposals that have international representation among its panelists.</s>
    <s>Paper proposals are appropriate for presentations that will focus on an individual research topic or piece of legal scholarship. After acceptance/rejection of proposals has been determined, the conference co-chairs will group paper presentations into sessions consisting of 3-5 presentations. Every effort will be made to ensure international representation in each paper session. (Each paper session at the conference will be allotted up to 60 minutes. The amount of time allowed for each individual presentation will be determined by the total number of presentations involved).</s>
    <s>Poster presentations will be made at one of two poster sessions held Friday and Saturday evenings. Presentations will be made in a written format on display boards (size TBA).</s>
    <s>There will be a limit of TWO first-author presentation submissions (either individual papers or papers within a symposium) for each submitter. There is no limit on the number of poster submissions or appearances as a discussant or session chair.</s>
    <s>Please be aware of the Society's ongoing effort to increase the rigor of the review process and the quality of the presentations at the conference. As a result, we are likely to accept fewer paper and symposium presentations and to accept more poster presentations. Please be sure to indicate during submission if you would like your paper or symposium papers to be considered for inclusion as posters if they are not accepted as proposed. The deadline for submissions will be September 15th, 2010.</s>
    <s>All proposals should be submitted electronically via the conference website created for APLS by All Academic (link to be posted soon). Please check the APLS conference webpage (http://www.ap-ls.org/conferences/apls2011/index2011.php) for regular updates regarding the submission process, including information about when the website will be open for submissions.</s>
    <s>Paper and poster proposals should consist of an abstract that is no longer than 100 words and a summary that is no longer than 1000 words. Symposium proposals should consist of a 100-word abstract and 1000-word summary for each paper, plus an additional 200-word abstract for the symposium. Empirical research submissions that do not include data are discouraged.</s>
    <s>If you have any questions or comments regarding the call for papers, or about the conference, please feel free to contact one of the conference co-chairs:</s>
    <s>Margaret Bull Kovera, 1-212-484-1112; mkovera@jjay.cuny.edu</s>
    <s>Patricia Zapf, 1-212-866-0608, pzapf@jjay.cuny.edu</s>
    <s>Home Page | Members | Contact Webmaster</s>
    <s>Site last updated October 7th, 2011</s>
  </text>
</page>
