<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.acla.org/conferences.html</url>
  <title>ACLA - Conferences</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>The ACLA maintains a listing of conferences and calls for papers, aside from the Local, national and imperial languages in situations of contact and conflict </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>11about | annual meeting | acla prizes | graduate students | acla resources</s>
    <s>announcements || conferences || travel grants || journals || associations || research</s>
    <s>&gt; ACLA Conferences and Calls for Papers Listings</s>
    <s>&gt; The ACLA maintains a listing of conferences and calls for papers, aside from the ACLA's Annual Meeting. Please email the ACLA to post conference information.</s>
    <s>&gt; The ACLA also has links to other conference lists. This list is not meant to be exhaustive. Please email the ACLA with information and addresses of other websites that list conferences or calls for papers related to comparative literature.</s>
    <s>&gt; October 2011</s>
    <s>&gt; &quot;Gossip… so much more than hearsay&quot; An International, Interdisciplinary Conference May 9-12, 2012 University of Guelph Ontario, Canada</s>
    <s>&gt; Truthful and slanderous? Artistic and scientific? Ancient and modern? Good and bad? Building on the work begun in November 2007 by the Universite de Perpignan's Équipe de Recherche VECT - Voyages, Échanges, Confrontations, Transformations' &quot;Potins, cancans et literature&quot; colloquium, we now seek to enlarge the scope of this inquiry beyond literature and to include also all visual and media arts (including performance), sociology, anthropology, linguistics, psychology, zoology, philosophy, history and political science. In this age of social networking, internet blogging, electronic surveillance and the ability to instantly disseminate information across the street and across the globe, gossip can seem like a rampantly modern, almost exclusively trivial, phenomenon, but a moment of reflection on the topic proves the contrary. Scholars can all consider the contributions and multiple impacts of gossip - broadly or narrowly defined - to their respective field.</s>
    <s>&gt; One-page proposals (250 words) addressing gossip as it relates to any field of academic enquiry are invited for 20-minute papers, to be given in French or English. Proposals should include the submitter's name, email address, and affiliation, and be sent by Friday October 14, 2011 to 'gossip-potins@uoguelph.ca'.</s>
    <s>&gt; The Gossip-Potins Conference invites proposals from graduate students as well as established scholars.</s>
    <s>&quot;Anyone who has obeyed nature by transmitting a piece of gossip experiences the explosive relief that accompanies the satisfying of a primary need.&quot; ~Primo Levi</s>
    <s>&quot;While gossip among women is universally ridiculed as low and trivial, gossip among men, especially if it is about women, is called theory, or idea, or fact.&quot; ~Andrea Dworkin</s>
    <s>&quot;Quand les potins vieillissent, ils donnent des mythes.&quot; ~Stanislaw Jerzy Lec d.</s>
    <s>&gt; The 14th Annual University of South Carolina Comparative Literature Conference: &quot;Cultural and Linguistic Intersections of the Transatlantic&quot; (March 22nd-24th, 2012). Analyzing and understanding the historical and cultural processes unique to the transatlantic sphere requires a comparative perspective. To that end, transatlantic studies examine the circulation of goods, ideas and people across the Atlantic, while simultaneously probing the implications of these processes for the nations involved. In keeping with this simultaneous focus on transnational and national coordinates, this colloquium solicits papers with a transatlantic perspective on both the formation and the diasporic nature of Hispanic and Luso-Brazilian cultures. So as to further account for the centrality of African cultural contexts in transatlantic processes, papers dealing with French and Anglophone cultures are also welcome. Our common goal will be to examine how circum-Atlantic and cis-Atlantic processes frame the constitution of transnational and national identities, cultural production, discursive formations and ideas about language. As we aspire to delimit and define historical and cultural processes unique to the Atlantic, the colloquium will encompass both the Colonial period and the past two centuries of nationhood.</s>
    <s>&gt; The Conference will feature four plenary speakers:</s>
    <s>Fernando Arenas, University of Michigan</s>
    <s>Sibylle Fischer, New York University</s>
    <s>Gilvan Muller de Oliveira, Instituto Internacional da Lingua Portugues</s>
    <s>Joan Ramon Resina, Stanford University .</s>
    <s>&gt; Topics of particular interest include but are not limited to:</s>
    <s>- Discourses and practices of subordination, domination and discrimination (i.e. colonial period, neocolonial dynamics)</s>
    <s>- Transnational discourses on violence and human rights in film and literature/ cultural production</s>
    <s>- Transatlantic historical and cultural processes in film and visual culture</s>
    <s>- Postcolonial and Subaltern Studies Approaches to the Transatlantic</s>
    <s>- Performance Studies - Spaces and places linked to transatlantic processes</s>
    <s>- Genealogies and trajectories of Hispanism / Transfers of ideas and cultural forms across the Atlantic</s>
    <s>- Immigration, exile, diaspora, and transoceanic identities</s>
    <s>- Local, national and imperial languages in situations of contact and conflict (past, present and future)</s>
    <s>- Spanish as a world language - sociolinguistic and cultural perspectives</s>
    <s>- Language policy, multilingualism and multiculturalism in the Spanish, Portuguese, French and English-speaking world (past, present and future).</s>
    <s>&gt; Abstracts for twenty minute papers should be sent to TransatlanticSC2012@gmail.com by October 20th, 2011. Abstracts should be 250 words long. Panel proposals of 750 words are due by the same date. Panels should include three papers and a respondent.</s>
    <s>&gt; The Presence of &quot;America&quot; in India: Where and How Does &quot;America&quot; Appear and What Are The Effects? April 5-8, 2012. The International Forum for U.S. Studies and South Asian Studies at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</s>
    <s>During the last decade, the circulation of ideas, commodities, cultural practices, and cultural products perceived as coming from the U.S. and gaining traction in India has accelerated. We understand this process as a dialectical one, full of multiple transformations/translations/ and effects, and with a substantial history, where India is not merely a &quot;receiving&quot; region, but rather a complex set of national and subnational cultural and political groups actively involved in articulating relationships to &quot;America.&quot; We use the term &quot;America&quot; advisedly as it does not presume to reference all of the Americas but rather to capture the sense of the U.S. as both a geo-political entity and a cultural imaginary, that is, not only as a political actor, mediating between Pakistan and India, but also as a cultural influence in many of the contemporary changes in Indian daily life and institutional structures. These include shifting practices of food consumption, modes of fashion, notions of secular democratic politics, the restructuring of Indian higher education institutions, the emphasis on &quot;American&quot; accents in English speech, employment in U.S. corporation customer service &quot;call centers,&quot; the impact of the presence of the US business corporations (such as IBM), new developments in Indian agriculture and engineering, the migration of hip hop style dancing into Bollywood musicals, the much contested &quot;brain drain&quot; to the United States, and so on.</s>
    <s>We welcome paper proposals from a wide range of disciplines and topics that seek to understand the complexities of these processes and relations. These include but are not limited to: media studies, security issues, food, agriculture and ecology, diaspora studies, performance and the performing arts, fashion, business and economics, literatures and language, religion, engineering, architecture and landscape, travel and tourism, and social relations. Proposals should explicitly address the conference theme. Panels will be organized to give each speaker approximately 20 minutes each. Other formats beyond the usual paper presentation mode, such as posters and performances, will also be considered.</s>
    <s>Please submit via email a proposal detailing your research and how it addresses the conference theme in the form of a brief abstract of no more than 300 words. Please include your name, title, affiliation, and contact information (mailing address and email), as well as a brief C.V. of no more than two pages by October 15th to: Ms. Anita Kaiser, Conference Coordinator, International Forum for US Studies arkaiser@illinois.edu</s>
    <s>Partipants will be notified of acceptance no later than Dec. 31, 2011, and will be responsible for their own travel and accommodation expenses. A registration fee of $50 ($25 students) participants will cover special meal events. Registration fee waived for UIUC participants. www.ips.illinois.edu/ifuss</s>
    <s>&gt; Negative Cosmopolitanisms: Abjection, Power, and Biopolitics. University of Alberta, Edmonton, Canada, 11-13 October 2012</s>
    <s>Organizers: Terri Tomsky (University of Alberta), Eddy Kent (University of Alberta), Imre Szeman (University of Alberta) Keynote Speakers: Timothy Brennan (University of Minnesota) Pheng Cheah (University of California, Berkeley) Sneja Gunew (University of British Columbia) Peter Nyers (McMaster University)</s>
    <s>This interdisciplinary conference seeks to explore the array of negative cosmopolitanisms operating today--all those ways in which cosmopolitan subjects are still stigmatized, disempowered, excluded, and denied. Against the superficial liberal celebration of cosmopolitan diversity in the world today, negative cosmopolitanism instead reveals experiences of rupture, exile, oppression, and imperialism. The conference will bring researchers together to explore the histories and constitution of cosmopolitanism past and present, with the aim of better understanding the complex experience of power today.</s>
    <s>Though cosmopolitanism is often thought of as a positive form of &quot;world citizenship&quot;, this conference is interested in the way cosmopolitanism can signify disenfranchisement. Globalization's economic asymmetries and the biopolitical management of modern states create cosmopolitan abjections: in the circulation of outsourced prisoners, with the deportation of sick migrants, in the extraordinary rendition of enemy combatants, with the worldwide flows of migrant and trafficked workers, and so on. The conference will engage the invisible presence of this &quot;negative cosmopolitanism&quot; for the Western middle-class and its liberal pundits. It will open up considerations of negative cosmopolitanism, exploring ideas around an imperial cosmopolis, slum or ghetto cosmopolitanisms, finance capitalism, piracy as it pertains both to material and intellectual property, and so on.</s>
    <s>Despite its long history, the status of the negative cosmopolitan assumes a new importance in the aftermath of globalization, not only within discourses about universal human rights but also in the infrastructures built to shuttle people, things, and ideas around the world. We therefore aim to understand the role of the nation-state in refuting or resolving this problematic subjectivity. But we must also account for the influence of internationalism, workers' unions, women's movements, NGOs, and religious organizations. Some of this theorizing is obviously not new, but it needs to be rearticulated in a context in which idealistic misconceptions of cosmopolitanism still dominate.</s>
    <s>We invite theoretical and historical contributions to these and related topics. Themes you may wish to consider include (but are not limited to):</s>
    <s>*The history and/or representations of cosmopolitanism</s>
    <s>*Slum- or ghetto-based cosmopolitanisms</s>
    <s>*Imperial cosmopolitanism (e.g. the military complex, the War on Terror)</s>
    <s>*Labor and Internationalism</s>
    <s>*Community or the Commons</s>
    <s>*Trafficking, dislocation, border-crossing</s>
    <s>*State sovereignty/state vulnerability/ the penal state</s>
    <s>*Communication and information technologies, new media</s>
    <s>*Religious movements</s>
    <s>Proposals shall consist of an abstract of 350-500 words and a one-page CV. Please send your applications to Dr. Terri Tomsky &lt;tomsky@ualberta.ca&gt; DEADLINE: 21 October 2011.</s>
    <s>&gt; Spheres of Influence: Navigating World, Globe, and Planet, UCLA, Comparative Literature Graduate Student Conference. Thursday February 23rd and Friday February 24th, 2012. Keynote: Wai Chee Dimock.</s>
    <s>Graduate students in any discipline are invited to submit abstracts for &quot;Spheres of Influence: Navigating World, Globe, and Planet&quot; a conference hosted by the graduate students in the Department of Comparative Literature at the University of California Los Angeles. The conference will provide a forum for emerging scholars to investigate the disciplinary concepts of world, globe, and planet and to share their research on any topic relevant to this year's theme.</s>
    <s>World, globe, and planet refer to specific discourses with overlapping concerns. Phenomenology, for example, has frequently been concerned with theorizing the world. Husserl's notion of lifeworlds, Heidegger's concept of worlding, or Arendt's conception of worldliness in order to investigate how human beings inhabit, manifest, and create worlds through work, social relations, and perhaps most importantly, art and literature. World might also invoke Edward Said's concept of worldliness, or Emmanuel Wallerstein's world systems theory, or it might refer more generally to world literature, the term coined by Goethe in 1827 to invoke literature that envisions the intersection of literary practices across worlds, borderlands, and disciplinary boundaries. The term globe, on the other hand, conjures political and economic concerns specific to the late twentieth and early twenty-first century. It invokes the alleged opposition between local and global, as well as discourses surrounding globalization, the transnational circulation of capital and commodities, and the role of cultural products as they traverse the globe with increasing speed and in increasing quantities. Where world and globe refer to man-made discursive spheres, the term planet situates earth as material, as one sphere among others that orbit the sun. With this materiality in mind, Gayatri Chakravorty Spivak conceived the term planetarity, defined as the imagining of ourselves as planetary subjects rather than global agents. Planetarity calls for the formation of counter-collectivities against the transnational popular of global capitalism, and is also tied to the emerging field of Ecocritical Studies, which examines the environmental impact of an increasingly connected earth.</s>
    <s>This conference seeks to ask: What kind of world do literatures create? What kind of comparative projects do these worlds enable? What is the critical valence of the term world literature and what are its limitations? Indeed, how do we define world literature itself? How does literature participate in global economies? What is the role of translation in opening or stopping up the global flow of cultural products? Can there be a planetary literature, and what would it look like? What are the political and ethical implications of envisioning planetary literature over world literature or global literature? Finally, what are the intellectual stakes of differentiating between the world, the globe, and the planet, between globalization, worlding, and planetarity What are the virtues and limitations of these terms with regard to literature and literary practice?</s>
    <s>Further questions to consider include but are not limited to:</s>
    <s>How have notions of world, planet, and globe over changed time and what are the historical factors that may shift our perception of worldiness?</s>
    <s>What are the specific geographic, national, artistic, and literary affiliations of world, globe, and planet?How do world, globe, and planet help us account for alternate modes of relation and movement across the world (i.e. migration, diaspora, colonization, transnationalism, exile, the status of refugees and displaced indigenous populations)?</s>
    <s>How might the discourses of local versus global, colony versus postcolony, utopia versus dystopia versus heterotopia, worldly versus otherworldly, terrestrial versus extraterrestrial expand, limit, or modify the notions of world, globe, planet?</s>
    <s>What is the role of geography and cartography in conceiving of the world, the globe, or the planet?</s>
    <s>What is the role of the visuality or of media, for example in satellite imagining, photography, and the internet?</s>
    <s>What specific art and literary practices, styles, and movements engage with world, globe, and planet?</s>
    <s>What can the world, the globe, and the planet tell us about comparative literature and comparative practices in the humanities?</s>
    <s>What is the role of translation? What gets translated and why, and how are translations circulated across the globe?</s>
    <s>We are pleased to announce that this year's keynote speaker will be Wai Chee Dimock. Dimock is the William Lampson Professor of English and American Studies at Yale University. She earned her B.A. from Harvard and her Ph.D. from Yale. Dimock experiments with close readings across a range of geographical regions and time-scales. Her most recent work, Through Other Continents: American Literature Across Deep Time (2006), received Honorable Mention for both the James Russell Lowell Prize of the Modern Language Association and the Harry Levin Prize of the American Comparative Literature Association. A collaborative volume, Shades of the Planet: American Literature as World Literature (2007), further elaborates on arguments concerning the intersection between American literature and World literature. She is currently at work on two books: an anthology, American Literature and the World, and a critical work, Many Islams: American Literature and the Diversities of a Lived Religion. Dimock was also a consultant for &quot;Invitation to World Literature,&quot; a 13-part series funded by the Annenberg Foundation and produced by WGBH, that aired on PBS stations in the fall of 2010.</s>
    <s>Please submit an abstract of 300 words and a current curriculum vitae to spheresofinfluence2012@gmail.com or by mail to: UCLA Comparative Literature Department 350 Humanities Building 405 Hilgard Avenue Box 951536 Los Angeles, CA 90095-1536</s>
    <s>The EXTENDED deadline for submission is October 31st, 2011. Questions may be directed to spheresofinfluence2012@gmail.com.</s>
    <s>&gt; November 2011</s>
    <s>&gt; XXVIII Biennial Louisiana Conference on Hispanic Languages and Literatures: The Constitution of Cz, Independence in Latin America, 1812-2012 will be held in February 16-18, 2012 by LSU, Department of Foreign Languages &amp; Literatures. We invite abstracts in English or Spanish for 20-minute papers and/or 100-minute panels on the conference topic and on all areas of research related to Hispanic Languages and Literatures. Some possible areas/issues include: Independence, revolution, and search for national identity Colonial and post-colonial language studies, discourses of nationalism, imperialism, and (neo)colonialism, language variation and change in the Hispanic World Peninsular studies, hispanic Caribbean language, literature, and culture, travel narratives Afro-Hispanic language, literature, and culture, transatlantic connections, globalization, displacement, and dislocation, gender in linguistic and cultural studies, race, cultural, and linguistic identity, cultural and linguistic challenges in the Hispanic World of the 21st Century Modernity, art, and popular culture, cultural and linguistic representations of hybrid identities,diaspora, migration, and exile Issues of language maintenance and language shift in the Hispanic world. Please send a 250-word anonymous abstract in Microsoft Word or pdf format as an e-mail attachment to LSUHispanic@lsu.edu using 'LA Conference Abstract' in the subject header. Please include the following information in the body of the message: (1) name(s) of author(s), (2) title of talk, (3) area of specialization, (4) affiliation(s), (5) e?mail address(es), (6) postal address(es) by November 1, 2011. Notices of acceptance or rejection will be issued shortly after abstract deadline.</s>
    <s>&gt; &quot; Theory: A 20th-Century Genre .&quot; The MLA Division on Comparative Studies in 20th-Century Literature and the Division on Literary Criticism solicit abstracts for papers to be delivered at a joint session of the 2013 annual meeting. The panel is titled: &quot;Theory: A 20th-Century Genre.&quot; Its premise is that &quot;Big-T&quot; or &quot;Grand&quot; Theory begins with Russian Formalism at the start of the 20th century, and enters its deliquescence towards the end of the century. We look for papers that either: 1) explore Theory as a literary form subject to the &quot;laws of genre&quot;; 2) explain the &quot;take-off&quot; of Theory in the early 20th century or its post-WWII boom; or 3) investigate Theory's demise at the end of the century.</s>
    <s>&gt; Deadline: Abstracts of up to 500 words (or draft papers of ca. 2000 words) and a CV to Marshall Brown (mbrown@u.washington.edu) and Thomas Beebee (tob@psu.edu) by 15 November 2011. Notifications shortly after the 2012 MLA meeting.</s>
    <s>&gt; December 2011</s>
    <s>&gt; The International Association for Literary Journalism Studies invites submissions of original research papers, abstracts for research in progress and proposals for panels on Literary Journalism for the IALJS annual convention on 17-19 May 2012. The conference will be held at the School of Journalism and Ryerson University in Toronto, Canada. The conference hopes to be a forum for scholarly work of both breadth and depth in the field of literary journalism, and all research methodologies are welcome, as are research on all aspects of literary journalism and/or literary reportage. For the purpose of scholarly delineation, our definition of literary journalism is &quot;journalism as literature&quot; rather than &quot;journalism about literature.&quot; The association especially hopes to receive papers related to the general conference theme, &quot;Literary Journalism: The Power and Promise of Story.&quot; All submissions must be in English. The International Association for Literary Journalism Studies is a multidisciplinary learned society whose essential purpose is the encouragement and improvement of scholarly research and education in literary journalism. As an association in a relatively recently defined field of academic study, it is our agreed intent to be both explicitly inclusive and warmly supportive of a variety of scholarly approaches. Information on previous annual meetings can be found at http://www.ialjs.org/?page id=33.</s>
    <s>&gt; Please submit research papers or abstracts of works-in-progress presentations to:Prof. Isabel Soares, Universidade Tecnica de Lisboa (Portugal) 2012 IALJS-7 Research Chair; e-mail: isoares@iscsp.utl.pt.</s>
    <s>&gt; Please submit proposals for panels to:Prof. Rob Alexander, Brock University (Canada) 2012 IALJS-7 Program Co-Chair; e-mail: ralexand@brocku.ca</s>
    <s>&gt; Deadline for all submissions: No later than 1 December 2011</s>
    <s>&gt; Classica Africana: The African and African-American Presence in the Classical Tradition, Friday, March 16th, 2012, The Graduate Center, CUNY, PhD/MA Program in Classics</s>
    <s>As the classical tradition continues to move in novel and fruitful directions in an effort to scrutinize its own history, new trends of classical scholarship have begun to examine the influence of the classical tradition upon African and African-American classicists and educators. The importance of African, and African-American, reception of classics provides a more comprehensive view of the classical tradition and in 2006, Michele Valerie Ronnick coined the term Classica Africana, as &quot;a field that examines the undeniable impact, both positive and negative, that the Graeco-Roman heritage has had on people of African descent in their creative and professional endeavors&quot; (Ronnick, The Autobiography of William Sanders Scarborough , 2005, 5). From Martin Bernal's controversial argument against the Eurocentric view of antiquity to Patrice Rankine's assertion that there is a strong relationship between classics and African-American literature, issues of black classics have become essential to a proper understanding of the classical heritage. With such issues in mind, we invite submissions concerning, but not limited to, the following range of topics:</s>
    <s>*Reception of Classics in Africa</s>
    <s>*Reception of Classics in the Caribbean</s>
    <s>*Africa in the Greco-Roman imagination</s>
    <s>*African and African-American Classicists</s>
    <s>*The influence of Africa and the Near East on the Greco-Roman world</s>
    <s>*The influence of classical themes in African and African-American literature</s>
    <s>*The influence of classical themes in African and African-American visual arts and film</s>
    <s>We will accept submissions from various disciplines, including Classics, Comparative Literature, Ancient History, African-American Studies, Religion, Gender Studies, Art History, and Philosophy. Graduate students interested in presenting a paper of 15 minutes should submit an abstract of 300 words or less to classicaafricanaconference@gmail.com. On your abstract please include your name, institution, city and state (country if not USA), email address and phone number. E-mail your abstracts as a Word file by December 10, 2011. Notifications will be sent in January. Questions may be addressed to conference chairs Sarah Derbew and Aramis Lopez at classicaafricanaconference@gmail.com.</s>
    <s>&gt; January 2012</s>
    <s>&gt; Educating the Imagination: A Conference in Honour of Northrop Frye on the Centenary of His Birth . October 4 - 6, 2012, Victoria University in the University of Toronto</s>
    <s>&gt; Twenty years after his death, Northrop Frye, the author of Fearful Symmetry and Anatomy of Criticism, continues to be one of the most read and the most quoted of literary critics. His attention to form, specifically to genre and mode, and his understanding of literature as a totality have directly influenced two later generations of critics, including Hayden White, Fredric Jameson, and Franco Moretti. In order to celebrate this ongoing legacy, the Department of English and the Centre for Comparative Literature at the University of Toronto, Frye's home throughout his career, have organized a three-day symposium in his honour. Keynote speakers include Ian Balfour (York University) author of Northrop Frye (1988), The Rhetoric of Romantic Prophecy (2002); Robert Bringhurst, poet, author of A Story As Sharp As a Knife: The Classical Haida Mythtellers and Their World (1999) and Selected Poetry (2009); J. Edward Chamberlin (University of Toronto) author of Come Back to Me My Language: Poetry and the West Indies (1993) and If This Is Your Land, Where Are Your Stories? (2003); Michael Dolzani (Baldwin-Wallace College) editor of Frye's Notebooks; W.J.T. Mitchell (University of Chicago) editor of Critical Inquiry and author of What Do Pictures Want? (2005) and Picture Theory (1994); Gordon Teskey (Harvard University) author of Delirious Milton (2006); Allegory and Violence (1996)</s>
    <s>&gt; There will be panels devoted to Frye's specific legacy, which we are now in a better position to appreciate because of the completed publication of the Collected Works in thirty volumes. But we also invite speakers to take inspiration from Frye and to consider literary and cultural topics such as: 1. Educating the Imagination when the Humanities are under threat Frye and Comparative Literature 2. the place of Western Literature and theory in a global context. The spread and the provincialization of Europe. The limits of the Great Code 3. Contemporary manifestations of traditional literary modes: the popular romance,contemporary tragedy, irony after postmodernism 4. creative responses to the Bible in an era of fundamentalism and secularism 5. The survival of the literary imagination in a digital age 6. Canadian literature in a postnational age 7. The Great Code and Islam 8. History as Narrative 9. Nature in an era of environmental crisis 10. Local literature, local forms</s>
    <s>&gt; Proposals for papers or panels of papers are welcome. Abstracts of 200 words (for papers) are due January 31, 2012. Please send them by e-mail to frye.2012@utoronto.ca.</s>
    <s>&gt; The 16th Annual Graduate Symposium: Near and Middle Eastern Studies in the Midst of Revolution, March 5-6, 2012, The Department of Near and Middle Eastern Civilizations' Graduate Students Association (University of Toronto)</s>
    <s>The Near and Middle Eastern Civilizations Graduate Students Association of the University of Toronto invites proposals for the 16th Annual Graduate Symposium to be held on March 5-6, 2012. Since 1997, the NMCGSA Symposium has provided the opportunity for promising graduate students to share their original research with the broader scholarly community in a conference-like forum, and to publish their presentations as proceedings. By annually bringing together specialists in archaeology, history (both modern and ancient), anthropology, comparative literature, religion, philosophy, art, and political science, the symposium provides a unique opportunity for interdisciplinary discourse focused on the study of the Near and Middle East. The 2012 symposium aims to highlight this diversity in order to foster communication and exchange across disciplinary boundaries. While we encourage submissions that are related to the recent Arab Spring movements, we are nevertheless open to any variety of topics that pertain to the realm of Near and Middle Eastern Studies. We are also open to reviewing unorthodox proposals.</s>
    <s>Presenters are asked to submit an abstract of 250 words by e-mail attachment no later than January 9, 2012. Submissions should also include the following information in the body of the email: presenters name, program (M.A, Ph.D.), year of study, research focus, university/department, complete address, telephone number, email address, title of paper, and audio-visual requirements.</s>
    <s>Presentations must not exceed 20 minutes. The abstracts will be reviewed by committee and presenters will be informed of their acceptance no later than February 8, 2012. For purposes of anonymous adjudication, please do NOT include your name or other identification on the abstract attachment.</s>
    <s>If your paper is being submitted as part of a proposed panel or considered under a specific theme, please include the panel title or the proposed theme under the title of the paper on the abstract.</s>
    <s>In order to foster greater scholarly dialogue, partial funding will be made available to five graduate students from North American universities to assist with travel costs. For eligibility please visit the symposium web site.</s>
    <s>Please send us your submissions via the following e-mail address: nmcgsasymposium@gmail.com</s>
    <s>&gt; California State University Dominguez Hills is pleased to announce that on March 8th and 9th, 2012 it will host the XXXVII International Symposium of Hispanic Literature in conjunction with El Instituto Literario y Cultural Hispanico.</s>
    <s>At this symposium we will honor the work of Mexican writer Marcela del Rio. We are asking for your cooperation by submitting a paper to be presented at the symposium.</s>
    <s>*Suggested topic: Mexican writer Marcela del Rio or any other female Hispanic writer, although any paper on Hispanic Literature is welcome.</s>
    <s>Please note that papers to be presented should last only 15 minutes (about 7 double spaced pages). Papers may be presented in English or Spanish. The registration cost is a $50 donation to ILCH. This helps to cover the publication costs of the Literary magazine Alba de America. Once your presentation has been accepted, please mail a check to ILCH, 8452 Furman Avenue, Westminster, California 92683. Spaces are limited.</s>
    <s>Please submit your title and 50-word abstracts electronically and as soon as possible (Deadline: January 25th, 2012) to: Benito Gomez Madrid Associate Professor, Modern Languages California State University Dominguez Hills bgomez@csudh.edu</s>
    <s>&gt; Selected papers, which should be expanded, will be considered for publication in the literary journal Alba de America. For all questions regarding publications, please contact Dr. Juana Arancibia at ilchja@aol.com.</s>
    <s>&gt; The Organizing Committee is pleased to invite you to participate in theInternational Symposium on Language and Communication: Research trends and challenges (ISLC). The symposium is to be held 10-13 June 2012 in the Ataturk Congress Center, Ege University, İzmir, Turkey.</s>
    <s>&gt; ISLC is an international symposium which focuses on the research trends and challenges in the fields of interdisciplinary language, literature, history and communication studies at both national and international levels, and their consequences for the theory, policy and practice of a variety of fields such as education, economy, sociology, and all other related fields. ISLC provides an international forum that enables discussions of the latest research trends and challenges, and promotes critical debate, on the often-complex interconnections among language and communication and history, economy, sociology, education, and all related sub-fields.</s>
    <s>&gt; Subject Areas The symposium publishes research papers in the fields of humanities, social sciences and economics such as anthropology, communication studies, demography, education, ethics, geography, history, industrial relations, information science, international relations, law, linguistics, library science, methodology, philosophy, political science, population studies, psychology, public administration, sociology, literature, religious studies, visual arts, women studies, management, human resources management, international business, tourism, business ethics, development studies and so on.</s>
    <s>&gt; Papers may address (but are not limited to) the following strands: Communication: - Communication Methods and Researches - Cultural Studies, Cultural History, Humanities - Media and Society Studies, Social Communication, Social Media - Professional and Corporate Communications - Mass Communication, Mass Communication History - Communication Law, Policy and Planning - Communication and Difference - Popular Culture, Media Uses and Media Literacy - Intercultural Communication and Global Media Trends - Global Communication, Social Change, Comparative Studies and Migration Studies - Media Studies, Models of Media Systems Analysis - Communication Technologies, ICT, Online Journalism and Online Research Innovations - Ethnicity and Race in Communication, Diasporas Studies - Digital Media, Digital Culture and Human-Technology Interaction and Human Factors - New Media, Internet and New Media Theories - Mobile Technologies Used for Dissemination and Promotion of Art - Innovative Works in Computer-based Art/Digital Art/Animation - Democracy, Politics and Journalism Ethics - Media and Identity - Journalism Studies, Journalism Theory, Press Studies, Promotional Culture - Instructional and Developmental Communication - Interpersonal Communication Research And Criticism - Political Communication - Visual Communication Studies, (Television, Filmmaking, Multimedia, Multi-Standards) - Communication, Training, Cultural Variation and Challenges - Philosophy of Communication - Advertising and Marketing Language: - Status/ Survival of Language and Literature - Society and Culture - Discourse Studies - First/Second Language Acquisition - Language Diversity - Language Policy and Planning - Language Rights, Language Policy - Language and Social Interaction - Language and Identity - Multilingualism, Cross-Cultural Communication - National and Local Languages, World Languages - Language and Economic Development - Language for Employability - Language and Social Mobility - Language Teaching: Trends And Challenges - Role of the Culture in Global Supply Chain - Discourse Linguistics - Computational Linguistics, Computational Lexicography. - Language Pragmatics - Cultural and Historical Analysis - Cognitive Linguistics - Methodology of Teaching Foreign Languages - Rhetoric - Sociolinguistics - Language and the Arts - Sociology of Language - Translation Studies Language</s>
    <s>&gt; The official languages of the Symposium will be Turkish and English. Delegates are required to prepare - 15-minute oral presentations followed by 5-minute question-response periods - Posters (to be displayed at designated times throughout the conference) - Abstracts and full papers will be double blind reviewed by the referees of the symposium. Accepted papers and posters will be published in Proceeding Book of ISLC 2012.</s>
    <s>&gt; Submission of Abstracts Opens : 1th OCT</s>
    <s>Deadline for Submission of Abstracts : 27th JAN</s>
    <s>Early Discount Registration Closes : 16th MAR</s>
    <s>Deadline to Register : 6th APR</s>
    <s>Full Paper Submission Deadline : 13th APR</s>
    <s>ISLC/2012 : 10th JUN .</s>
    <s>&gt; Please read the guidelines on how to make your online submission before you start the submission process www.inlcs.org/2012 We look forward greatly to your participation in the ISLC 2012 symposium.</s>
    <s>&gt; GENERAL CALLS FOR PAPERS</s>
    <s>Inquire: Journal of Comparative Literature invites submissions to Issue 2.1 (Jan 2012) describing the participation of literary works - historical or contemporary, upmarket or downmarket - in the global intersection of languages and literatures, groups and cultures. Comparative articles emphasizing literary criticism, cultural theory or book history are welcome. Possible areas of investigation include: anthologizing literature(s); diaspora/centre-periphery issues; digitization; economics, politics and print; gender, ethnicity and race; indigenous narratives; international readerships; intra-national relationships (e.g., within Canada); pop print/culture(s); post-colonialism/globalization; proletarian literature(s); reading, writing and publishing online; traditional genres and new forms; teaching comparative/world literature; translation; transnational networks; &amp;c. Guidelines: graduate students only, 5-7,000 words including notes and works cited, MLA. Submissions &amp; inquiries: inquire@ualberta.ca. Details: http://inquire.streetmag.org/submissions. Deadline: 12 September 2011.</s>
    <s>Expositions: Interdisciplinary Studies in the Humanities, is a bi-annual, on-line journal where scholars from various disciplines gather as colleagues to converse about common texts and questions in the humanities. We seek to publish two types of contributions: Articles that either have an inter-disciplinary character and appeal or are exemplary in their respective disciplines while being of interest to those from other disciplines. Notes &amp; Insights and reflections on Teaching the Great Books benefit teaching, research, and the life of the academy. On-going acceptance of submissions. Our next issue will appear in October 2011. For more information, please see the journal's website or contact the managing editors. http://expositions.journals.villanova.edu.</s>
    <s>&gt; Intertexts , a journal of comparative and theoretical reflection, publishes articles that employ innovative approaches to explore relations between literary and other texts, be they literary, historical, theoretical, philosophical, or social. In particular, the editors are looking for work which engages issues on a sufficiently theoretical or comparative level to interest people in a variety of disciplines. Hybrid methodologies that combine elements from a range of disciplines are encouraged. For more information and for submission details, please visit the journal's website at http://www.intertexts.org/id2.html.</s>
    <s>&gt; Symposium , a quarterly journal in modern foreign literatures, welcomes contributions pertinent to modern languages and literatures. Research on authors, themes, periods, genres, works, and theory, often through comparative studies, is regularly featured. For more information and for submission details, please send an email to sym@heldref.org.</s>
    <s>&gt; Inquire , a new peer-reviewed international journal of Comparative Literature to be published online by the graduate students of the Program of Comparative Literature at the University of Alberta beginning January 2011, aims to build upon the successes of Comparative Literature as a multifaceted discipline that emphasizes the study of minor literatures and languages, translation, and literary theory by providing the space for informed discussion and creative research by graduate students.</s>
    <s>&gt; Sounding: An Interdisciplinary Journal, invites essays on topics related to any and all aspects of human values, including aesthetic, moral, political, economic, scientific, or religious values. Affiliated with the Society for Values in Higher Education, the journal has recently moved to Florida State University, where it will be housed in the Center for Humanities &amp; Society and edited by John Kelsay of the FSU Department of Religion. We welcome work from a variety of disciplinary and/or interdisciplinary approaches, including the arts, cultural studies, history, literature, philosophy, and religion, among others. For procedures related to submitting an essay, consult the CHS website (http://www.lib.fsu.edu/CHS/) or write soundings@admin.fsu.edu</s>
    <s>&gt; Please visit these sites for more calls for papers:</s>
    <s>&gt;UPenn calls for papers</s>
    <s>&gt;Voice of the Shuttle calls for papers</s>
    <s>&gt;CLC calls for papers</s>
    <s>&gt;Papers Invited</s>
    <s>&gt;American Philosophical Association</s>
    <s>&gt;Aesthetics Online calls for papers</s>
    <s>&gt;American Cultures &amp; Global Contexts (University of California-Santa Barbara) calls for papers</s>
    <s>&gt;Eserver Calls for Papers</s>
    <s>&gt;UCLA's Asia Institute's calls for papers listing</s>
    <s>&gt;H-Net: Humanities and Social Sciences Online calls for papers</s>
    <s>&gt;Queer Theory's calls for papers listing</s>
    <s>&gt;Erratic Impact's calls for papers</s>
    <s>&gt;The University of Maryland's Woman's Studies listing of calls for papers</s>
    <s>&gt;Intercollegiate Women's Studies Center (Claremont Colleges) calls for papers</s>
    <s>&gt;PopCulture.com listing of conferences and calls for papers</s>
    <s>&gt;Association for the Study of Literature and the Environment calls for papers listing</s>
    <s>acla home | about the acla | annual meeting | acla prizes | graduate students acla resources | acla membership | contact the acla</s>
    <s>(C) 2003 american comparative literature association</s>
  </text>
</page>
