<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.thotcon.org/cfp.html</url>
  <title>THOTCON - Chicago&#39;s Hacking Conference - Call for Papers [CFP]</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>BEGIN THOTCON TRANSMISSION********************************************** is a small venue hacking conference based in Chicago IL, USA. This is a non pr o </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>*BEGIN THOTCON TRANSMISSION</s>
    <s>= == ==== ==== ==== ==== ===== ==== ======= ===</s>
    <s>==== ===== ==== === == ====== ====== === === == === ====== ===</s>
    <s>==== ===== ==== == ==== ===== ===== ======== ==== == ===== ===</s>
    <s>==== ===== ==== == ==== ===== ===== ======== ==== == == === ===</s>
    <s>==== ===== == ==== ===== ===== ======== ==== == === == ===</s>
    <s>==== ===== ==== == ==== ===== ===== ======== ==== == ==== = ===</s>
    <s>==== ===== ==== == ==== ===== ===== ======== ==== == ===== ===</s>
    <s>==== ===== ==== === == ====== ====== === === == === ====== ===</s>
    <s>==== ===== ==== ==== ======= ======= ===== ==== ======= ===</s>
    <s>What: THOTCON 0x3 - Chicago's Hacking Conference</s>
    <s>When: 04.27.12</s>
    <s>Where: TOP SECRET</s>
    <s>Call for Papers: OPEN!!!!</s>
    <s>ABOUT *</s>
    <s>THOTCON (pronounced \ˈthȯt\ and taken from THree - One - Two) is</s>
    <s>a small venue hacking conference based in Chicago IL, USA. This is a non pr</s>
    <s>o non-commercial event looking to provide the best conference possible on a</s>
    <s>very limited budget.</s>
    <s>WHEN / WHERE</s>
    <s>The THOTCON 0x3 will be held in Chicago, IL on Friday, April 27th, 2012.</s>
    <s>It will be held at a location only to be disclosed to attendees and speaker</s>
    <s>s during the week before the event. It will be in Chicago and close to a CT</s>
    <s>A train stop, accessible by bus, cab, and plenty of parking.</s>
    <s>The event will be a single track.</s>
    <s>There will be ten (10) 40 minute talks selected.</s>
    <s>Topics we are interested in: retro computing, forensics, robotics, physical</s>
    <s>security, 0-days, application hacking, wireless, malware development/resea</s>
    <s>rch, hackerspaces, The Muppets, Penguins, zombies, attack detection, the nu</s>
    <s>mber 7, online game hacking, consumer device hacking, beer, and bananas fo</s>
    <s>SPEAKER PERKS *</s>
    <s>All Speakers will be given free admission to the conference as well as one</s>
    <s>(1) free attendee badge (to bring a guest). In addition, speakers who give</s>
    <s>their presentation as planned, will be given a THOTCON life-time attendanc</s>
    <s>e badge. This means you will be given free entry to every future THOTCON ev</s>
    <s>ent for life. You will also have access to the THOTCON VIP Lounge. This mea</s>
    <s>ns you will have access to free stuff and other highly discounted stuff all</s>
    <s>day. We don't have anything else to give, except you can tell your mom and</s>
    <s>your friends you spoke at THOTCON.</s>
    <s>HOW TO SUBMIT *</s>
    <s>If you are interested in speaking at this event, please send your completed</s>
    <s>speaker application below to cfp@thotcon.org.</s>
    <s>Once we receive your submission, you will get an email back within 48-72 ho</s>
    <s>urs. If you do not hear back from us, please resend.</s>
    <s>The CFP will close on Jan 1, 2012 or when we feel we have 10 outstanding ta</s>
    <s>lks. We anticipate having all speakers selected by Feb 1, 2012.</s>
    <s>CALL FOR PAPERS APPLICATION *</s>
    <s>NOTE: You must copy and paste ALL of the info below and fill in all the inf</s>
    <s>ormation to be considered for a slot.</s>
    <s>Speaker Info</s>
    <s>1. Name or Handle or Both:</s>
    <s>2. Country/State/City of Residence:</s>
    <s>3. Phone Number:</s>
    <s>4. Email Address:</s>
    <s>5. Have you presented at a con before?</s>
    <s>6. If so, which one and when?</s>
    <s>7. Brief Bio: will be printed on website and program</s>
    <s>8. Twitter Handel:</s>
    <s>9. Blog or Website:</s>
    <s>Presentation Info</s>
    <s>1. Presentation Title: be creative</s>
    <s>2. Presentation Synopsis: &lt;1 page please</s>
    <s>3. Is there a demonstration? Y or N</s>
    <s>4. Is this about a new tool? Y or N</s>
    <s>5. Is this about a new exploit? Y or N</s>
    <s>1. Shirt size: Men's Sizes</s>
    <s>2. Favorite Beer:</s>
    <s>2. Anything you would like to share:</s>
    <s>Grant of Copyright Use</s>
    <s>I warrant that the above work has not been previously published elsewhere,</s>
    <s>or if it has, that I have obtained permission for its publication by THOTCO</s>
    <s>N and that I will promptly supply THOTCON with wording for crediting the or</s>
    <s>iginal publication and copyright owner.</s>
    <s>If I am selected for presentation, I hereby give THOTCON permission to dupl</s>
    <s>icate, record and redistribute this presentation; including, but not limite</s>
    <s>d to, the conference proceedings, conference CD, video, audio, hand outs(s)</s>
    <s>to the conference attendees for educational, on-line and all other purpose</s>
    <s>Yes, I, insert your name, have read the above and agree to the Grant of C</s>
    <s>opyright Use.</s>
    <s>Agreement to Terms of Speaking Requirements</s>
    <s>If I am selected to speak, I, insert your name, understand that I must co</s>
    <s>mplete and fulfill the following requirements or I will forfeit my speaking</s>
    <s>1) I will submit a completed (and possibly updated) presentation, a copy of</s>
    <s>the tool(s) and/or code(s), and a reference to all of the tool(s), law(s),</s>
    <s>Web sites and/or publications referenced to at the end of my talk and as de</s>
    <s>scr ibed in this CFP submission for publication on the conference CD by noo</s>
    <s>n CST, April 2, 2012.</s>
    <s>2) I understand if I fail to submit a completed presentation by April 2, 20</s>
    <s>12, I may be replaced by an alternate presentation. This decision will be m</s>
    <s>ade by THOTCON and I will be informed in writing of my status.</s>
    <s>3) I will include a detailed bibliography as either a separate document or</s>
    <s>included within the presentation of all resources cited and/or used in my p</s>
    <s>4) I will complete my presentation within the time allocated to me - not ru</s>
    <s>nning over the time allocation.</s>
    <s>5) I understand that THOTCON will provide 1 LCD projector, 1 screen, and mi</s>
    <s>crophone. I understand that I am responsible for providing all other necess</s>
    <s>ary equipment, including laptops and machines (with VGA output), to complet</s>
    <s>e my presentation.</s>
    <s>6) I will submit, within 5 days of the completion of the conference, any up</s>
    <s>dated, revised or additional presentation(s) or materials that were used in</s>
    <s>my presentation but not included on the conference CD or conference procee</s>
    <s>I, (insert your name here), have read the above and understand and agree to</s>
    <s>the terms as detailed in the Agreement to Terms of Speaking Requirements.</s>
    <s>Agreement to Terms of Speaking Remuneration</s>
    <s>1) I understand that I will be responsible for my own hotel and travel expe</s>
    <s>2) I understand that I will be given 1 THOTCON attendee badge as remunerati</s>
    <s>on for my speaking at the conference. In addition, once the I have complete</s>
    <s>d my presentation I will receive 1 life-time attendance badge that will all</s>
    <s>ow me to attend ALL future THOTCON events for free.</s>
    <s>3) I understand that should my talk be determined to be unsuitable after I</s>
    <s>have presented, that I will not receive a life-time attendance badge.</s>
    <s>I, insert your name, have read the above and understand and agree to the</s>
    <s>terms as detailed in the Agreement to Terms of Speaking Remuneration.</s>
    <s>*END THOTCON TRANSMISSION</s>
    <s>THOTCON INFOBLOX v.3 ESR6</s>
    <s>212K RAM FREE</s>
    <s>Main Menu:</s>
    <s>1. Home</s>
    <s>2. About</s>
    <s>3. Call For Papers</s>
    <s>4. Contests</s>
    <s>5. Speakers</s>
    <s>6. Schedule</s>
    <s>7. Venue</s>
    <s>8. Registration</s>
    <s>9. Sponsors</s>
    <s>A. Contact</s>
    <s>B. Links</s>
    <s>C. Archive</s>
    <s>D. Exit</s>
    <s>(C) 2011 THOTCON NFP !setstats</s>
  </text>
</page>
