<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.cla-conf.org/pg/397/306</url>
  <title>CLA&#39;11 :: Call for papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>The Computational Linguistics – Applications Conference was established in This call is for papers that present research and practical developments on all </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Held in Warszawianka Hotel Wellness &amp; Spa in Jachranka (near Warsaw, Poland) on 17-19 October 2011</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Important dates</s>
    <s>For Authors</s>
    <s>Registration and fees</s>
    <s>Preliminary program</s>
    <s>Arrival / transportation</s>
    <s>Airports in Poland</s>
    <s>CLA History</s>
    <s>Website map</s>
    <s>&lt;october '11&gt;</s>
    <s>Proceedings will be submitted for indexation by:</s>
    <s>Call for papers</s>
    <s>Conference Goals</s>
    <s>The Computational Linguistics - Applications Conference was established in 2008 as the Workshop for its first three editions in response to the fast-paced progress in the area, to create a dialog between researchers and practitioners involved in Computational Linguistics and related areas of Information Technology.</s>
    <s>Traditionally, computational linguistics was limited to the scientists specialized in the processing of a natural language by computers. Scientific approaches and practical techniques come from linguistics, computer science, psychology, and mathematics. Nowadays, there is a number of practical applications available. These applications are sometimes developed by smart yet NLP-untrained developers who solve the problems using sophisticated heuristics. CLA aims to be a meeting place for both parties in order to share views and ideas. It will help scientist to better understand real world needs and practitioners not to reinvent the wheel.</s>
    <s>Computational Linguistics needs to be applied to make the full use of the Internet. There is a definite need for software that can handle unstructured text and information to allow search for information on the web. The priority aim of the research in this area is to enable users to communicate with the computer in their native language.</s>
    <s>CLA'11 Conference is a place where the parties meet to exchange views and ideas with a benefit to all involved. The Conference will focus on practical outcome of modeling human language use and the applications needed to improve human-machine interaction.</s>
    <s>Paper Topics</s>
    <s>This call is for papers that present research and practical developments on all aspects of Natural Language Processing used in real-life applications, such as (this list is not exhaustive):</s>
    <s>ambiguity resolution</s>
    <s>anaphora resolution</s>
    <s>applied CL software and systems</s>
    <s>computational morphology</s>
    <s>computational phonology</s>
    <s>corpus annotation and corpus-based language modeling</s>
    <s>creation of lexical resources</s>
    <s>dialogue systems</s>
    <s>entity recognition</s>
    <s>extraction of linguistic knowledge from text corpora</s>
    <s>information retrieval and information extraction</s>
    <s>machine learning methods applied to language processing</s>
    <s>machine translation and translation aids</s>
    <s>multi-lingual dialogue systems</s>
    <s>ontology and taxonomy evaluation</s>
    <s>opinion mining and sentiment classification</s>
    <s>paraphrasing and entailment</s>
    <s>parsing issues</s>
    <s>parts-of-speech tagging</s>
    <s>proofing tools</s>
    <s>prosody in dialogues</s>
    <s>question answering</s>
    <s>semantic networks and ontologies</s>
    <s>semantic role labeling</s>
    <s>semantic web</s>
    <s>speech recognition and generation</s>
    <s>text classification</s>
    <s>text summarization</s>
    <s>word sense disambiguation</s>
    <s>Paper Presentation</s>
    <s>The presentation of the paper has to include a demonstration of an existing tool. The papers should include a section describing the tool (or a prototype), which demonstrates the theory discussed in the paper.</s>
    <s>The presentation is divided into two parts. First, the author(s) shortly demonstrate their tools to the audience. In the second part, the authors discuss their work with other participants and let the audience test their software.</s>
    <s>Papers will be evaluated and accepted on the basis of their technical merit, usefulness of the real life application and relevance to the workshop scope by the CLA'11 Program Committee. The paper will be assessed by academics as well as industry representatives in order to assure fair and balanced assessment.</s>
    <s>All accepted and presented papers will be published in the Conference Proceedings. The best demonstrations will be selected to be shown to the general audience of the conference at a plenary session.</s>
    <s>Papers Submission</s>
    <s>Authors should submit draft papers (as Postscript, PDF of MSWord file).</s>
    <s>The total length of a paper should not exceed 8 pages (IEEE style). IEEE style templates are available here.</s>
    <s>Papers will be refereed and accepted on the basis of their scientific merit and relevance to the workshop.</s>
    <s>Accepted and Presented paper will be published in the Conference Proceedings.</s>
    <s>where science meets reality</s>
    <s>Today is:</s>
    <s>Wednesday, 5 X 2011</s>
    <s>Paper Submission</s>
    <s>for Authors</s>
    <s>PC Members / Reviewers</s>
    <s>is available</s>
    <s>Organized by:</s>
    <s>Polish Information Processing Society</s>
    <s>Co-located with:</s>
    <s>XXVII Autumn Meeting</s>
    <s>of the</s>
    <s>Polish Information Processing Society</s>
    <s>In cooperation with:</s>
    <s>TiP Sp. z o.o. (Ltd.)</s>
    <s>Sponsored by:</s>
    <s>I need to stay informed</s>
    <s>about future CLA events:</s>
    <s>Click HERE</s>
    <s>Join CL-A</s>
    <s>group HERE</s>
    <s>Back to top</s>
    <s>Copyright (C) PTI 2011 :: Code: T.S. :: Design: A.P. :: Contact :: Webmaster</s>
    <s>Total visits: 59378 times.</s>
  </text>
</page>
