<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://nbea.us/pb/wp_bb8275c3/wp_bb8275c3.html</url>
  <title>nbea.us - 2011 Conference Call for Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Welcome to the 2011 NBEA Conference Homepage Please click for the full Call for Papers. The 38th Annual Meeting of the Northeast Business &amp; Economics </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>2011 Conference Registration</s>
    <s>2011 Conference Hotel Information</s>
    <s>2011 Conference Call for Papers</s>
    <s>2011 Doctoral Student-Junior Faculty Competition</s>
    <s>2010 Conference</s>
    <s>Journal of Business &amp; Economic Studies</s>
    <s>NBEA Board of Directors</s>
    <s>Annual Membership</s>
    <s>Welcome to the 2011 NBEA Conference Homepage</s>
    <s>Please click for the full Call for Papers.</s>
    <s>The 38th Annual Meeting of the Northeast Business &amp; Economics Association (NBEA) will be held from November 3rd-5th, 2011, and hosted by Saint Joseph's University. The conference will be held at the Sheraton Society Hill Hotel in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, located within walking distance of Philadelphia's historic sites. Please click here to visit St. Joseph's University NBEA website.</s>
    <s>Guidelines for Submission</s>
    <s>Authors submit abstracts (2-4 pages), full papers or proposal for workshops in Word format electronically. Submissions must have two title pages. The first page must include the title, primary track and the following information about each author: name, affiliation, address, telephone numbers and an e-mail address. Papers with multiple authors must indicate a corresponding author for future communication. The second page must only have the title to enable blind peer review.</s>
    <s>Acceptance and Proceedings</s>
    <s>Accepted papers are eligible to be published in the NBEA Conference Proceedings. A template with publication requirements was sent to authors upon notification of acceptance and can be found by clicking here.</s>
    <s>Two Best Paper Award Competitions</s>
    <s>Everyone is eligible to enter the Best Paper Award competition and win a cash award. Submit an abstract/extended abstract for consideration by April 28, 2011. Upon acceptance, submit a full paper for award consideration by August 1, 2011.</s>
    <s>In addition, untenured junior faculty and doctoral students are eligible to submit their full papers for the Junior Faculty/Doctoral Student paper competition. One paper cannot win both awards. All winners are eligible to be published in the NBEA's Journal of Business &amp; Economic Studies .</s>
    <s>Doctoral Student Submissions Encouraged</s>
    <s>Student authors may submit works in progress, full papers, expanded abstracts, and workshop or panel proposals.</s>
    <s>Registration Fee</s>
    <s>The registration fee is $240. Early registrations received before October 1,2011 qualify for the discounted rate of $190. The registration fee for faculty emeritus and students is $120, $95 if paid before October 1, 2011.</s>
    <s>Key Dates/Contacts</s>
    <s>Paper Proposal Submissions by: April 26, 2011</s>
    <s>Acceptance Notification by: May 31, 2011</s>
    <s>Award Submissions (full papers only) by: August 1, 2011</s>
    <s>Proceedings Submission by: August 31, 2011</s>
    <s>E-Mail Paper Submissions:</s>
    <s>Proceedings Editor</s>
    <s>Dr. Rajneesh Sharma</s>
    <s>Finance Department</s>
    <s>Mandeville Hall, 340</s>
    <s>Saint Joseph's University</s>
    <s>5600 City Avenue</s>
    <s>Philadelphia, PA 19131-1395</s>
    <s>Conference Information:</s>
    <s>Conference Chair</s>
    <s>Dr. George P. Sillup</s>
    <s>Pharmaceutical &amp; Healthcare Marketing Department</s>
    <s>Mandeville Hall, 245</s>
    <s>Saint Joseph's University</s>
    <s>5600 City Avenue</s>
    <s>Philadelphia, PA 19131-1395</s>
    <s>©2005 Doteasy.com</s>
    <s>(C) 2000 - 2011 powered by</s>
  </text>
</page>
