<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.nationalevacuationconference.org/</url>
  <title>National Evacuation Conference</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>National Evacuation Conference. Welcome, Regristration, Program, Paper Submissions &middot; Accommodations &middot; Organizers &middot; Keynote Speakers &middot; Sponsors </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>!National Evacuation Conference</s>
    <s>About the Conference</s>
    <s>The next National Evacuation Conference will appear again in New Orleans February 7-9, 2012 at the Hilton RiversideThe 2012 Sponsorship Packet is now available for download by clicking here. Please continue to check back for more information about the conference. If you would like to receive notifications about the next conference, please email Blair Beter: bbeter1@lsu.edu</s>
    <s>Conference Information</s>
    <s>This conference will bring together the fields of transportation and emergency management to discuss evacuation planning to accommodate the needs of all people before, during and after a major disaster. The purpose of the conference is to foster an interdisciplinary exchange of ideas surrounding a broad range of evacuation issues, particularly mass evacuations prompted by disasters.</s>
    <s>Special topics of discussion include:</s>
    <s>Addressing the challenges faced by special needs populations</s>
    <s>during disasters</s>
    <s>Improvements in evacuation planning and modeling</s>
    <s>National evacuation policy development</s>
    <s>This conference will be relevant to both academics and professionals with an interest in the development and modeling of comprehensive evacuation plans. The conference will offer a venue for dialogue between the academy and practice, as well as between the private and public sector. Participants will contribute to an important step towards more efficient and effective evacuation planning.</s>
    <s>2012 Conference Packet</s>
    <s>[PDF ]</s>
    <s>!Graphic: Important DatesWho Should Attend</s>
    <s>The conference will assemble together professional, academics, nonprofit and for-profit organizations, consultants, emergency managers, government officials and transportation planners to discuss evacuation planning for cities and regions across the United States.</s>
    <s>Conference is organized by the Stephenson Disaster Management Institute and the Gulf Coast Research Center for Evacuation and Transportation Resiliency both at Louisiana State University and the University of New Orleans.</s>
    <s>Read more about the hosts.</s>
    <s>2010 National Evacuation Conference:</s>
    <s>Paper Submissions</s>
    <s>Keynote Speakers</s>
    <s>Conference Photos:</s>
    <s>Welcome Reception Photos</s>
    <s>Day 1 Photos</s>
    <s>Day 2 Photos</s>
    <s>Welcome | Registration | Program | Paper Submissions | Accommodations | Organizers | Keynote Speakers | Sponsors</s>
  </text>
</page>
