<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.gsdi.org/node/326</url>
  <title>Call for Papers: Global Geospatial Conference 2012 | GSDI</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Call for Papers: Global Geospatial Conference 2012. Sun, 09/11/2011 - 11:24 — Harlan Onsrud. Dear GSDI Association, International Geospatial Society, and </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Primary links</s>
    <s>Association Information</s>
    <s>Join GSDI Association</s>
    <s>News List Archive</s>
    <s>Discussion Lists</s>
    <s>Electronic Gateways</s>
    <s>Upcoming Conferences</s>
    <s>Past GSDI Conferences</s>
    <s>Members &amp; Sponsors</s>
    <s>Founding Members</s>
    <s>International Geospatial Society</s>
    <s>Members Only</s>
    <s>Site Search</s>
    <s>13 Oct 2011</s>
    <s>Feed aggregator</s>
    <s>Call for Papers: Global Geospatial Conference 2012</s>
    <s>Sun, 09/11/2011 - 11:24 — Harlan Onsrud</s>
    <s>Dear GSDI Association, International Geospatial Society, and SDI Community Members and Friends,</s>
    <s>We are delighted to announce that the GSDI World Conference (GSDI 13), 14th GEOIDE Annual Scientific Conference, Canadian Geomatics Conference (CGC 2012) and the 7th 3D GeoInfo Conference will be jointly held as the Global Geospatial Conference 2012 to take place at the Québec City Convention Center from May 14-17, 2012.</s>
    <s>This joint conference offers numerous opportunities for oral presentations and refereed and non-refereed publication outlets. We invite presentations covering the full range of practice, development and research experiences that advance the practice and theory of spatially enabling government, industry and citizens .</s>
    <s>This call supports three primary forms of publication:</s>
    <s>(1) a normal conference proceedings with abstracts and full non-refereed and refereed articles published on a USB drive or CD and archived on the web,</s>
    <s>(2) a pre-conference published book of fully refereed articles titled &quot;Spatially Enabling Government, Industry and Citizens: Research and Development Perspectives&quot; to be distributed to all conference participants and archived on the web, and</s>
    <s>(3) a pre-conference selection of articles for publication in the International Journal of Spatial Data Infrastructures Research (IJSDIR) to be selected, refereed, revised and published prior to and in affiliation with the conference.</s>
    <s>In addition, two separate calls arising from the joint conference are being issued for chapter submissions to two additional books:</s>
    <s>(1) &quot;The Added Value of Scientific Networking: GEOIDE Network Experiences&quot; to be distributed to all conference participants (Call for chapters at http://www.geoide.ulaval.ca/call-for-chapters.aspx), and</s>
    <s>(2) &quot;3DGeo Info Conference Proceedings&quot; (Springer) to be mailed after the conference to all 3DGeo Conference participants which will be a single track on Wednesday and Thursday (Call at http://www.3dgeoinfo2012.ulaval.ca/?page id=48).</s>
    <s>IMPORTANT DATES</s>
    <s>Deadline for Submission of Abstracts: 15 November 2011</s>
    <s>Deadline for Submission of Full Papers for Refereed Outlets: 15 November 2011</s>
    <s>Conference Dates: 14-17 May 2012</s>
    <s>IMPORTANT LINKS</s>
    <s>Joint Conference Call for Abstracts and Papers: http://www.gsdi.org/gsdiconf/gsdi13/papers.html</s>
    <s>Conference Website: http://www.gsdi.org/gsdi13</s>
    <s>Past GSDI World Conference Proceedings: http://www.gsdi.org/gsdiConferences</s>
    <s>Past open access Books affiliated with the conference: http://www.gsdi.org/openaccessbooks</s>
    <s>Other Important Dates: http://www.gsdi.org/gsdiconf/gsdi13/dates.html</s>
    <s>We look forward to seeing you in Quebec in May 2012.</s>
    <s>Best regards, The Joint Conference Organizing Committee</s>
    <s>News List Archive</s>
    <s>GSDI Association Web Page by GSDI Association is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 United States License.</s>
  </text>
</page>
