<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.aasianst.org/conferences/conferences.htm</url>
  <title>Asian Studies Conferences</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>CALL FOR PAPERS: East Asian Law and Society Conference 2011. Dialects and Dialectics: East Asian Dialogues in Law and Society. Dates: 30 September – 1 </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>About the AAS</s>
    <s>Contact Information</s>
    <s>Board of Directors/Officers</s>
    <s>AAS Committees</s>
    <s>Northeast Asia Council (NEAC)</s>
    <s>Southeast Asia Council (SEAC)</s>
    <s>South Asia Council (SAC)</s>
    <s>China and Inner Asia Council (CIAC)</s>
    <s>Council of Conferences (COC)</s>
    <s>AAS Regional Conferences</s>
    <s>AAS Affiliate Organizations</s>
    <s>Constitution and Bylaws</s>
    <s>Membership Information</s>
    <s>Become a Member of AAS</s>
    <s>Frequently Asked Questions</s>
    <s>Member Login</s>
    <s>View/Edit Your Member Profile</s>
    <s>Online Member Directory</s>
    <s>Online Journal of Asian Studies</s>
    <s>Annual Conference</s>
    <s>AAS Publications</s>
    <s>Publications Catalog/Shopping Cart</s>
    <s>Asia Past and Present Book Series</s>
    <s>Key Issues in Asian Studies Booklets</s>
    <s>The Journal of Asian Studies</s>
    <s>Education About Asia</s>
    <s>Bibliography of Asian Studies</s>
    <s>Asian Studies Newsletter</s>
    <s>First Book Subvention Program</s>
    <s>AAS Book Prize Competitions</s>
    <s>Ordering Information and Terms</s>
    <s>Advertising Opportunities and Mailing Labels</s>
    <s>Conferences and Meetings</s>
    <s>AAS Annual Conference</s>
    <s>AAS Regional Conferences</s>
    <s>General Conference Announcements</s>
    <s>Job Listings</s>
    <s>Submit or Pay for a Job Ad</s>
    <s>Student Pages: Overview</s>
    <s>The Profession: A Career in Asian Studies</s>
    <s>Asian Studies Programs and Centers</s>
    <s>Grants, Fellowships, and Prizes</s>
    <s>Study Programs</s>
    <s>First Book Subvention Program</s>
    <s>Links &amp; Resources</s>
    <s>Links and Resources: Overview</s>
    <s>Asian Studies Programs and Centers</s>
    <s>AAS Affiliate Organizations</s>
    <s>Grants, Fellowships, and Prizes</s>
    <s>Study Programs</s>
    <s>AAS Book Prize Competitions</s>
    <s>AAS Asia Photo Gallery</s>
    <s>Advertising Opportunities and Mailing Labels</s>
    <s>AAS Accounting: Secure Payment</s>
    <s>Asian Studies Conferences and Meetings</s>
    <s>If you wish to have your conference announcement included in the print Asian Studies</s>
    <s>Newsletter or here, please contact Teresa Spence at tspence@asian-studies.org.</s>
    <s>Print Newsletter deadlines are: January 1, April 1, September 1, and November 1.</s>
    <s>Please limit your announcement (print or online) to approximately 500 words.</s>
    <s>[AAS ANNUAL CONFERENCE | AAS REGIONAL CONFERENCES ]</s>
    <s>The University of California Humanities Research Institute presents</s>
    <s>In conjunction with the Center for Chinese Studies at the University of Hawai'i at Manoa</s>
    <s>SEMINAR IN EXPERIMENTAL CRITICAL THEORY VII: ReWired: Asian/TechnoScience/Area Studies</s>
    <s>August 1-10, 2011</s>
    <s>Applications are due by April 22, 2011 at 5:00 PM</s>
    <s>The Seminar will address how technoscientific knowledge-systems are re-ordered when geo-political formations shift.</s>
    <s>You &quot;don't invent the future,&quot; John Seely Brown famously noted - &quot;you unleash it by leveraging the global community mind.&quot;</s>
    <s>Today the fastest expansion of technoscientific knowledge production and urban development isoccurring across multiple Asian sites in the throes of techno-economic boom. Seely Brown's observation, made in conversation with Paul Duguid, was meant to characterize late 20th century knowledge institutions and sites of technological production in the US. It nevertheless uncannily predicts the radical de-centering of global technological futures in the 21st century, not least in the Asian context.</s>
    <s>The 2011 Seminar in Experimental Critical Theory (SECT VII) seeks to elucidate these rapidly transforming landscapes of knowledge production, the shaping of contemporary knowledge institutions, their impact on social life in intense urban contexts, and this century's techno-scientific horizons of possibility. Comprehending these movements, forces, and structures requires integrating deep understandings of history and politics represented by Asian and critical Area Studies with emergent work on the transnational dynamics of science and technology as well as on market economies and their modes of governance.</s>
    <s>Instructional faculty: Itty Abraham, University of Texas // Ivan da Costa Marques, Universidade Federal do Rio de Janeiro // Wendy Chun, Brown University // Joe Dumit, UC Davis // Roger Hart, University of Texas // Cori Hayden, UC Berkeley // Tim Lenoir, Duke University // Kavita Philip, UC Irvine // Achal Prabhala, Wikimedia Foundation // Sha Xin Wei, Concordia University, Montreal // Nishant Shah, Center for Internet and Society // Lucy Suchman, Lancaster University // Siva Vaidhyanathan, University of Virginia // Kath Weston, University of Virginia</s>
    <s>Location: University of Hawai'i at Manoa</s>
    <s>Application Fee: $20</s>
    <s>Registration Fee: $1250 (includes shared housing, instruction, and some meals)</s>
    <s>Applicants are urged to seek funding from their home institutions. A very limited number of scholarships may be available to full-time registered students.</s>
    <s>For additional information, please contact us at sect@hri.uci.edu or visit our website: http://uchri.org/sect.php</s>
    <s>Call for Proposals: Japan Studies Association of Canada / Association canadienne d'etudes sur le Japon 24th Annual Conference</s>
    <s>18-21 August 2011</s>
    <s>Saint Mary's University</s>
    <s>Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada</s>
    <s>The Japan Studies Association of Canada (JSAC; Association canadienne d'etudes sur le Japon, ACEJ) is the largest organization in Canada devoted to the academic study of Japan. Its annual meeting--the only national level assembly of Japan scholars in Canada--brings together a wide range of researchers, not only from across Canada but also typically from Japan, the United States, and elsewhere. Supported by the Japan Foundation, the JSAC annual conference offers a valuable and unique scholarly gathering.</s>
    <s>In an effort to elicit the widest variety of papers possible this conference was initially organized without any theme. In light of recent events, however, conference organizers now also welcome paper and panel proposals that could fall under the heading &quot;Resilient Japan.&quot;</s>
    <s>The Klaus Pringsheim Award will be awarded at the conference banquet to the student paper presented at the conference judged to be the most deserving by a select JSAC committee.</s>
    <s>Deadline: 31 May 2011 (proposals may be submitted beginning 1 April; first-time applicants encouraged to apply early).</s>
    <s>Deadline for Thesis Workshop: 31 May 2011.</s>
    <s>Travel and accommodation subsidies may be available for conference presenters and graduate students attending the thesis workshop.</s>
    <s>For details visit: http://husky1.smu.ca/~bsewell/JSAC2011.html</s>
    <s>Questions concerning this event may be directed to Prof. Bill Sewell, Department of History, Saint Mary's University (902-420-5755; fax 902-420-5141; JSAC2011@smu.ca).</s>
    <s>&quot;Identity and Community after the Cold War Era&quot;</s>
    <s>August 25-27, 2011, University of Kansas, Lawrence, KS</s>
    <s>The last two decades have witnessed the confluence of many different kinds of radical change--the demise of communism as a force in politics, the resurgence of religious community, the emergence of global warming as a major challenge to traditional economies and communities, and the innovative growth of technology. Concepts of community have been radically altered. Maps, borders, governments, and alliances have shifted. The World Wide Web came into being, bringing with it major changes in cultural ritual, self-perception, and community-building. The universalist ideologies characteristic of modernity have retreated, replaced by some older concepts of identity and community. In many parts of the world new versions of traditional religions have emerged as mass forces. The arts and architecture have experienced a shift in focus and form.</s>
    <s>The combined area and international studies centers at the University of Kansas (African; East Asian; Latin American; Russian, East European, and Eurasian; Global and International Studies) invite 200-word proposals for papers in both Humanities and Social Sciences, as well as History and Sociology of the Natural Sciences, that address issues of &quot;Identity and Community after the Cold War Era.&quot; We seek papers focusing on a specific world area or country; interdisciplinary and trans-regional proposals are also welcome.</s>
    <s>The goal of the conference is to describe, examine, and understand the various areas and kinds of shift that have happened since the late 1980s and to attempt a complex model of the world humanity now inhabits.</s>
    <s>Possible topics might include but are not limited to:</s>
    <s>• post-communist identities in various of the arts/literature/architecture</s>
    <s>• concepts of ideal space/utopia/built environment</s>
    <s>• history and memory</s>
    <s>• political, cultural, and social implications of the internet</s>
    <s>• new states, new alliances</s>
    <s>• socio-cultural language and shifts in consciousness</s>
    <s>• party formation/deformation</s>
    <s>• borders, centers, peripheries</s>
    <s>• religious alliances/communities</s>
    <s>• meanings and uses of national identity</s>
    <s>• language, identity, and community</s>
    <s>• censorship</s>
    <s>A volume of selected conference papers is planned.</s>
    <s>Please send your proposal and updated c.v. by March 1, 2011, to: crees@ku.edu. Put in the subject header of your email: August 25-27 conference proposal</s>
    <s>Edith W. Clowes,</s>
    <s>Professor, Department of Slavic Langs. and Lits.</s>
    <s>Director, Center for Russian, E. European, and Eurasian Studies</s>
    <s>University of Kansas</s>
    <s>Lawrence, KS 66045</s>
    <s>CALL FOR PAPERS: East Asian Law and Society Conference 2011. Dialects and Dialectics: East Asian Dialogues in Law and Society</s>
    <s>Dates: 30 September - 1 October 2011</s>
    <s>Venue: Yonsei University, Seoul, Republic of Korea</s>
    <s>Organizers: Collaborative Research Network on East Asian Law and Society (CRN-EALS)</s>
    <s>Korean Society for the Sociology of Law</s>
    <s>The Second East Asian Law and Society Conference will be held on 30 September and 1 October 2011 at Yonsei University in Seoul, Korea. The CRN-EALS was formed within the Law and Society Association (www.lawandsociety.org) to provide a forum for intellectual dialogue and collaborations between socio-legal scholars engaged in Northeast and Southeast Asia-related research and scholars seeking to enrich their research and theories with findings from these regions. The co-organizers hope to build on the success of inaugural East Asian Law and Society Conference, convened by the CRN-EALS in Hong Kong last year with over 150 participants from around the world.</s>
    <s>The theme for this conference is Dialects and Dialectics: East Asian Dialogues in Law and Society. &quot;Rule of law&quot; is now accepted as the universal language of governance, but it is undeniable that various dialects are spoken in different regions of the world. While efforts are made at the national level to promote a standard form of &quot;rule-of-law speech,&quot; sub-national dialects persist within each jurisdiction. This is particularly true in Asia, despite increasing pressures toward the global convergence of national legal systems. Genuine convergence, however, can only come about through dialectical relationships among the different legal dialects. A true dialectical relationship, in turn, will be possible only when meaningful dialogues take place among speakers of those different dialects. The organizers hope to explore these plural interactions through a diverse array of panels and paper presentations.</s>
    <s>We invite proposals for papers and panels on law and society in Asia that relate either (i) directly to the conference theme (Dialects and Dialectics: East Asian Dialogues in Law and Society); or (ii) to any topic in connection with law and society in Asia.</s>
    <s>Submission Procedures:</s>
    <s>Scholars, practitioners and graduate students are all welcome to participate. Participants need not be members of the CRN-EALS or the Korean Society for the Sociology of Law.</s>
    <s>All proposals must be submitted via email to: eastasialsa2@gmail.com by 15 March 2011 (US Pacific Standard Time).</s>
    <s>All paper and panel proposals must be in English and include the following content:</s>
    <s>For Paper Proposals:</s>
    <s>1. Title of the paper;</s>
    <s>2. An abstract of not more than 300 words*;</s>
    <s>3. Information about the presenter:</s>
    <s>a. Full name;</s>
    <s>b. Title (Prof/Dr/Mr/Ms/Mrs/Miss);</s>
    <s>c. Institutional Affiliation;</s>
    <s>d. Email address; and</s>
    <s>e. Postal address.</s>
    <s>For Panel Proposals:</s>
    <s>1. Title of the panel;</s>
    <s>2. A brief description of the panel in not more than 300 words;</s>
    <s>3. Titles of each paper (each panel must have three to four papers and presenters must be from more than one jurisdiction/country);</s>
    <s>4. Abstracts of each paper (not more than 300 words each)*;</s>
    <s>5. Information about each presenter:</s>
    <s>a. Full name;</s>
    <s>b. Title (Prof/Dr/Mr/Ms/Mrs/Miss);</s>
    <s>c. Institutional affiliation;</s>
    <s>d. Email address; and</s>
    <s>e. Postal address.</s>
    <s>All applicants will be notified of the acceptance of their proposals by 15 May 2011.</s>
    <s>All presenters will be requested to submit a more detailed abstract of not less than four pages before the conference. Submission of full papers will also be welcome.</s>
    <s>Additional Information: For information about registration, fees, and accommodation, please consult the conference website at: http://sociologyoflaw.or.kr/EALS2011</s>
    <s>For other enquiries about the conference, please contact the Korean Society for the Sociology of Law via email at: sociolaw@gmail.com</s>
    <s>Annual Conference 2011 &quot;Frontiers of Knowledge&quot;</s>
    <s>Cluster of Excellence &quot;Asia and Europe in a Global Context&quot; at Heidelberg University, Germany, October 5-7 , 2011</s>
    <s>This year's topic is &quot;Frontiers of Knowledge: Health, Environment and the History of Science&quot;. The conference presents the ongoing research results of the Cluster's Research Area C &quot;Health and Environment&quot; in collaboration with renowned scholars from around the globe. Together they will examine and discuss transcultural issues in these fields transgressing the conventional intellectual divisions between Asia and Europe.</s>
    <s>The conference features keynote lectures by Prof. Sunder Rajan (University of Chicago) on transcultural health and Prof. Janet Hunter (London School of Economics) on earthquake and economics. Four major panel sessions will discuss the topics &quot;Ancient Medicine&quot;, &quot;Circulation and Changing of Conceptions of Knowledge&quot;, &quot;Travelling Technologies, Tracing Transculturality: Paradigm Shifts in Science, Medicine and Society&quot;, and &quot;Seascapes and Shipping&quot;. To showcase the research being conducted at the Cluster, twelve further panels will question how we have conceived and are conceiving knowledge in the past and present. During the Annual Conference 2011, the &quot;Transcultural Studies Association&quot; will be ceremonially inaugurated.</s>
    <s>For further information on the conference, please visit our website at http://www.asia-europe.uni-heidelberg.de/en/annual-conference-2011. Please let us know if you will attend the conference by sending an email to events@asia-europe.uni-heidelberg.de by September 23, 2011.</s>
    <s>Conference announcement and Call for Papers - Rethinking Religion in India III: European Representations and Indian Responses - University of Pardubice, Czech Republic, 11 to 14 October 2011</s>
    <s>Today, a virtual consensus has come into being among scholars that the dominant modern descriptions of Hinduism, Brahmanism, Vedism, Sikhism, Jainism are the result of collaboration between Europeans and Indians. Scholars like Brian Pennington, Phillip Wagoner, Thomas Trautmann and others have characterised this collaboration as a kind of dialogue, a dialogue between people belonging to two different cultures possessing different conceptual frameworks. This dialogue, it is said, has resulted in descriptions that contain elements of both sides and are therefore neither entirely European nor entirely Indian.</s>
    <s>In the third Rethinking Religion in India conference we want to take a closer look at this consensus, at its implications and examine whether and how it helps us in the study of religion in India.</s>
    <s>The conference will work towards these ambitions in three formats:</s>
    <s>1. The Platform Sessions: Monologue or Dialogue?</s>
    <s>In the course of three sessions three clearly formulated theses will be discussed among four experts. The speakers that are invited for this session are: Prof. Arvind Mandair, Prof. Brian Pennington, Prof. Nicholas Dirks and Prof. S.N. Balagangadhara (speakers to be confirmed).</s>
    <s>2. The Roundtable Sessions: The Indian Response</s>
    <s>In these plenary sessions we will look at the Indian side of the dialogue: how have Indians responded to the European descriptions of their religion and culture?</s>
    <s>3. The Parallel Sessions: in the Parallel Paper Sessions scholars will present their research on one of the themes given below. In the &quot;How to ?&quot; Workshops there will be more room for participation from the public.</s>
    <s>A call for papers for the Parallel Paper Sessions is open on the following themes:</s>
    <s>The colonial construction of Hinduism</s>
    <s>The caste system and Indian religion</s>
    <s>Secularism in Europe and India</s>
    <s>Said and Orientalism: dead or alive?</s>
    <s>What does the modernization of Indian traditions mean?</s>
    <s>Islamic mysticism in European and Indian perspective</s>
    <s>We also invite submissions of proposals for &quot;How to…?&quot; workshops.</s>
    <s>For more information on all the sessions please visit our website: www.rethinkingreligion.org</s>
    <s>Abstracts and proposals for workshops can be submitted online via our website (see call for papers).</s>
    <s>The deadline for submissions of abstracts and proposals is June 15, 2011.</s>
    <s>A number of interviews, presentations and debates of the first two conferences, Rethinking Religion in India I &amp; II, can be watched on www.youtube.com/cultuurwetenschap</s>
    <s>This conference is jointly organised by:</s>
    <s>the Research Centre Vergelijkende Cultuurwetenschap (Ghent University, Belgium),</s>
    <s>the Department of Religious Studies (University of Pardubice, Czech Republic),</s>
    <s>the Centre for the Study of Local Cultures (Kuvempu University, India),</s>
    <s>the India Platform UGent (Ghent University, Belgium) and</s>
    <s>the Karnataka Academy of Social Sciences and Humanities (ĀSHA)</s>
    <s>Marianne Keppens</s>
    <s>Research Centre Vergelijkende Cultuurwetenschap</s>
    <s>Ghent University, Belgium</s>
    <s>tel: +32 (0)9 264 93 71</s>
    <s>E-mail: Marianne.Keppens@UGent.be</s>
    <s>&quot;Word and Image, East and West&quot;</s>
    <s>University of Sydney, Faculty of Arts and Social Sciences</s>
    <s>28-29 October 2011</s>
    <s>In 1991 Mieke Bal defended the verbal and textual aspects of visual artifacts, arguing that a new cultural paradigm exists based on the assumption that &quot;the culture in which works of art and literature emerge and function does not impose a strict distinction between the verbal and the visual domain. In cultural life the two domains are constantly intertwined&quot; (&quot;Reading Rembrandt&quot;, 1991, p. 5).</s>
    <s>In the last twenty years the relationship between the visual and the verbal has become a key issue in the humanities in general and, in particular, in the creation of new inter-, multi- or transdisciplinary areas of study. Reaction to the growing presence of images in contemporary culture has, thus, led to a flourishing of publications, conferences and academic courses on the varied interactions between text and image. Yet, a comparative investigation on the way the East and West perceive the interrelation between the visual and the textual still needs particular attention.</s>
    <s>The purpose of the symposium is to bring together scholars and researchers from different backgrounds (historical, literary, theoretical or philosophical) in order to discuss and compare the mutual interdependence of words and images, the mixed mediality of the visual and the verbal, and the way they have been interlacing in different geographical and cultural areas, from Europe and the US to the Middle East and the Asia Pacific region, throughout the years.</s>
    <s>Contributions are invited, but not limited to: literature and painting; iconography and narrative; visual poetry; writing and photography; narrative and maps; mixed-media forms and intermedia texts; graffiti.</s>
    <s>Discussions are therefore encouraged on the different modalities one medium has been included in the other in the Western and Eastern cultures, as well as the way the interaction of word and image has contributed to challenge the East/West binary. Contributions are invited to discuss issues of: transcription; juxtaposition; transposition and translation; interference; ekphrasis</s>
    <s>We invite proposals for twenty-minute papers in English. Please submit a 500-word abstract and include name, university affiliation, as well as a short paragraph with biographical information by 30 May 2011. Selected contributions will be included in a 2012 Special Issue of the international refereed journal Literature &amp; Aesthetics (University of Sydney Society of Literature &amp; Aesthetics). Essays (in English) for the issue will be commissioned by 15 November 2011. Commissioned essays are due no later than 1 March 2012.</s>
    <s>Enquiries and proposals should be addressed to Giorgia Alu: giorgia.alu@sydney.edu.au or Francesco Borghesi: francesco.borghesi@sydney.edu.au</s>
    <s>CALL FOR PAPERS ASIAN ENCOUNTERS: NETWORKS OF CULTURAL INTERACTION</s>
    <s>An International Conference Organized by IIC-Asia Project and the Department of History, University of Delhi</s>
    <s>November 1-3, 2011</s>
    <s>The centuries-old exchange of ideas, knowledge systems, resources, skills, and materials among the people of the Asian continent left a lasting legacy in various spheres of human experience. This was a dialogue that involved a rich exchange of literary, religious and artistic ideas and forms across the regions of Asia. The proposed conference focuses on the processes and manifestations of these cultural interactions in pre-modern times.</s>
    <s>While studies in the history of Asian cultures have addressed some of these processes, a holistic understanding of their various dimensions and the totality of the impact of this intense and prolonged cultural interaction is still very inadequate. How has cultural discourse been shaped and shared by Asians? How do Asians view their shared past through their artistic, literary, and religious discourse? What were the political and social contexts, motivating factors and modes of communication and interaction that made this exchange possible? What systems of knowledge were communicated through these transactions and how do these reflect the distinctiveness as much as the commonalities of Asian cultures? In what ways are these understandings revealed in modern-day museum displays and the management of ancient and medieval heritage sites? How do such displays and strategies of heritage management in turn influence academic discourse on Asian pasts? These are some of the issues that scholars are invited to address in this conference.</s>
    <s>The many textures and levels of cultural 'exchange' and 'dialogue' among Asians are of course, rooted in larger concerns and circumstances and need to be understood in their historical context. The scope of the conference thus extends across the disciplines of history, art history, aesthetics, archaeological and conservation practices, epigraphy, museology, studies in Asian religions and literature, and other allied disciplines. Papers that include comparative perspectives or collaborations across two or more Asian regions in relation to pre-modern art and cultural heritage would be especially pertinent to its objectives.</s>
    <s>Some of the specific themes include the following:</s>
    <s>1. Historical contexts and avenues of cultural interaction</s>
    <s>2. Aesthetic theories and praxis</s>
    <s>3. Religious and cultural matrices of artistic and literary discourse</s>
    <s>4. Art, religion, and literature: inter-relationships, transmission and transformation of the narrative, iconic, and built traditions</s>
    <s>5. The artist and the creative process; context, patronage, and reception of art</s>
    <s>6. The past in the present: museums of Asian art; archaeological and conservation practices</s>
    <s>Place: Delhi: India International Centre and the University of Delhi.</s>
    <s>Submission of Paper Proposals: Paper proposals should include a title and a 400-word abstract, together with a short biography of the applicant. Proposals should be received by 15th March 2011 and successful applicants will be informed of their acceptance by 31st March 2011.</s>
    <s>Proposals should be e-mailed to the conference convenors:</s>
    <s>Prof. Upinder Singh (upinders@gmail.com) and Dr. Parul Pandya Dhar (parulpd@gmail.com)</s>
    <s>Department of History, University of Delhi, Delhi 110007</s>
    <s>and to Dr Kapila Vatsyayan, Chairperson, IIC-Asia Project:</s>
    <s>email: asiaprojectiic@yahoo.com</s>
    <s>India International Centre, 40 Max Mueller Marg, New Delhi 110003.</s>
    <s>CALL FOR PAPERS</s>
    <s>International Conference on</s>
    <s>DECENTRALIZATION AND ITS DISCONTENTS: RECALIBRATING PUBLIC SERVICE DELIVERY IN ASIA</s>
    <s>18-19 November, 2011 at the Centre for Governance and Citizenship, The Hong Kong Institute of Education, Hong Kong</s>
    <s>Asian governments embraced decentralization with a great deal of enthusiasm and optimism in the late 1990s. In the ensuing years, many governments in the region devolved not only their rowing but also their steering role in public services in the belief that lower levels of governments and external agencies were better placed to manage the implementation process. The results of these decentralization efforts were varied but often were disappointing.</s>
    <s>In recent years, governments in the region have begun to reassert their role in the decentralized sectors. However, this reassertion is not meant to return to status quo ante. Rather, the emerging arrangements suggest a desire for more pragmatic partnerships in delivering public services based on the partners' (lower level governments, NGOs, social enterprises, and private firms) different but complementary capabilities.</s>
    <s>The Conference will explore the decentralization-centralization dynamics in Asia and beyond with the purpose of assessing the current situation and developing workable ('best practices&quot;) arrangements for partnerships. It is expected that papers will highlight the ways in which the relationship between central and local governments is being redefined and recalibrated to more effectively deliver public services. The papers will not only describe and evaluate decentralization efforts and how they are being modified in sectors such as education, health care, housing, irrigation, transportation, and energy, but will also situate the discussion within the larger theoretical context of public management and administrative reforms. Issues that will be particularly relevant to the conference include identifying the preconditions for successful collaborative governance, the new challenges to implementation capacity posed by decentralization and de-concentration, and the manner in which policy innovations diffuse through policy learning and transfer.</s>
    <s>The refereed Conference is being organized by the Centre for Governance and Citizenship, the Hong Kong Institute of Education. Partners include Research Committee on Comparative Public Policy (RC30), International Political Science Association, and the journals Policy and Society and Journal of Asian Public Policy.</s>
    <s>Participants presenting papers will be exempt from registration fees. A limited number of conference attendance grant is available on a competitive basis. Please indicate in your email submitting the abstract if you will need the grant to be able to participate.</s>
    <s>Please send an approximately 500 word abstract to cgc@ied.edu.hk by 1 July 2011. The abstracts will be reviewed by a panel and results of the review will be announced in mid-July 2011.</s>
    <s>Wwebsite: http://www.ied.edu.hk/cgc</s>
    <s>Muslim Religious Authority in Contemporary Asia (24 - 25 Nov 2011, Singapore)</s>
    <s>CALL FOR PAPERS (DEADLINE: 1 JULY 2011)</s>
    <s>Most of the world's Muslim population lives in Asia, but to date this important region continues to be underrepresented in studies of contemporary Islam. Contemporary Muslim leaders across Asia confront major changes in their diverse socio-political environments, experiencing varying degrees of democratization, the rise of populist religious movements, and the (re-) assertion of autocratic rule. Within these contexts, Muslim religious leaders face complex questions regarding how to exercise authority in the public sphere. This workshop will develop a nuanced assessment of the developing roles of Muslim religious leaders (ulama) in modern Asia, pursued through contextualized studies of social, legal and political dynamics of Islamic religious leadership in diverse Asian contexts. In doing so, it will address questions including, but not limited to:</s>
    <s>• How do ulama and their religious organizations engage with electoral politics?</s>
    <s>• What is the involvement of ulama and their religious organizations with political parties, politicians and the state bureaucracy?</s>
    <s>• How are political activities undertaken by ulama and their religious organizations regulated by the state?</s>
    <s>• What are the public perceptions of religious leaders who participate in politics?</s>
    <s>• What are the potential consequences of ulama involvement in politics? How does their involvement in political activities bolster or compromise their spiritual and communal roles?</s>
    <s>SUBMISSION DETAILS</s>
    <s>We invite those interested in participating in the workshop to submit original paper proposals which should include a title, an abstract of 250 words, a short biography of 100-150 words, and should be submitted using the Paper Proposal Submission Form. Please submit your proposal to Sharon Ong at arios@nus.edu.sg by 1 July 2011. Papers that have been selected will be notified by 1 August 2011. If accepted, the full paper must be submitted by 30 September 2011. Participants are encouraged to seek funding for travel from their home institutions. However, a limited number of travel grants will be available for the participants.</s>
    <s>For more details and the paper submission form, please visit http://www.ari.nus.edu.sg/events categorydetails.asp?categoryid=6&amp;eventid;=1165</s>
    <s>International Conference of the 1911 Revolution: Call for Papers</s>
    <s>2011 marks the 100 Anniversary of the 1911 Revolution. Hence we would like to organize a conference discussing the contemporary significance of this Revolution. We invite submissions from potential participants.</s>
    <s>Tokyo Conference:</s>
    <s>Special Themes Panels 1-4, and 6.</s>
    <s>Kobe Conference:</s>
    <s>Special Themes, Panels 1-4.</s>
    <s>The panels are described in detail on the Japanese page. The Conference will result in a Conference Volume, which will be widely distributed both in Japan and internationally.</s>
    <s>1. Schedule and Location</s>
    <s>Tokyo Conference: December 3-4, 2011, the University of Tokyo, Komaba Campus</s>
    <s>Kobe Conference: December 10, 2011, Kobe University Centennial Hall</s>
    <s>2. Invited Participants</s>
    <s>Tokyo Conference: About 10 Invitees</s>
    <s>Kobe Conference: About 6 Invitees</s>
    <s>3. Requirements for being Invited</s>
    <s>a. Assistant professors in Japanese or foreign Universities</s>
    <s>b. Post-docs or lecturers</s>
    <s>c. PhD students</s>
    <s>d. Other people (not professors) who do specialized research and have scholarly publications.</s>
    <s>5. Expenses</s>
    <s>The Conference will pay for accommodation and meals during the time of the conference. It will also fund travel within Japan. People coming from overseas will have to pay for their own travel.</s>
    <s>6. Languages</s>
    <s>Japanese, Chinese and English</s>
    <s>7. Application deadline (strictly observed)</s>
    <s>December, 2010 to January 31, 2011</s>
    <s>8. Application Forms</s>
    <s>a. Application Form (Excel format)</s>
    <s>b. Abridged CV showing major publications (any format)</s>
    <s>9. Method of application</s>
    <s>Send the required materials to the Committee by e-mail.</s>
    <s>10.Method of Selection</s>
    <s>A committee of experts in the field will make the selections.</s>
    <s>11. Schedule for Conveying Results</s>
    <s>In the beginning of April, 2011, the committee will contact various applicants and inform them about the status of their application.</s>
    <s>12. Contact</s>
    <s>For more information, please refer to our website http://www.shingai100japan.jp/english.html</s>
    <s>or contact The Secretary of Committee of International Conference of the 1911 Revolution</s>
    <s>The Committee for the International Conference of the 1911 Revolution</s>
    <s>Growing Pains and Growth Paths: China and Japan in Modern Economic Growth</s>
    <s>Sponsored and organised by New Zealand Contemporary China Research Centre at Victoria University and Asia Institute at Auckland University, New Zealand, 5-6 December 2011</s>
    <s>China and Japan are two countries that have been related in critically different ways at different historical points. China dominated the region until the 19th century. The Meiji Restoration in the late 19th century in Japan set the two countries onto different paths of modern development. Japan's leadership in East Asia's rapid economic growth in the early post-World War II decades has further set itself apart from China. When China embarked on its economic reform and opening 30 some years ago, the two countries were so different in so many ways that not many would think they were even comparable. For more detailed information on the conference, please go to the China Centre website.</s>
    <s>This conference is designed to bring leading China and Japan scholars, and scholars of growth economics and political economy in general to address these issues. We are inviting paper proposals on the following conference themes: (1) institutions and culture for modern market economy; (2) The variety of capitalism; (3) The waves of East Asian rapid economic growth;</s>
    <s>(4) Temporal and sequence analysis of modern economic development; and (5) the global economic system and national economic development. We will publish selected papers as an edited volume by an international publisher.</s>
    <s>Those interested to give a paper at the conference shall forward their paper proposals (title and a 150-word abstract, with full contact details) to Professor Xiaoming Huang (xiaoming.huang@vuw.ac.nz) and Professor Hugh Whittaker (h.whittaker@auckland.ac.nz), co-chairs of the conference organizing committee, no later than 30 September, 2011. The conference will provide travel and accommodation support for selected papers. Registration details for the conference and acceptance letters will be sent shortly after that. For those who require a formal letter for funding, travel and visa purposes, please send your proposal early and indicate accordingly.</s>
    <s>AAS AREA COUNCILS: Northeast Asia | China &amp; Inner Asia | South Asia | Southeast Asia</s>
    <s>Contact | About AAS | Membership | Annual Conference | Publications</s>
    <s>Conferences | Students | Jobs | Forums | Links &amp; Resources</s>
    <s>(C) Association for Asian Studies, Inc.</s>
    <s>825 Victors Way, Suite 310</s>
    <s>Ann Arbor, MI 48108 USA</s>
    <s>Tel: (734) 665-2490</s>
    <s>Fax: (734) 665-3801</s>
  </text>
</page>
