<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.h-e-r-a.org/hera_call.htm</url>
  <title>Calls for Papers - HERA - Humanities Education and Research ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Calls for Papers. 2012 Conference - Salt Lake City. March 7-10, 2012 - Marriott Downtown. C R O S S R O A D S. HERA 2012 Conference Call Submission </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Calls for Papers</s>
    <s>2012 Conference - Salt Lake City</s>
    <s>March 7-10, 2012 - Marriott Downtown</s>
    <s>C R O S S R O A D S</s>
    <s>HERA 2012 Conference Call</s>
    <s>Submission deadline: November 15, 2011</s>
    <s>In keeping with HERA's mission of promoting the study of the humanities across a wide range of disciplines, we invite presentations exploring any form of artistic representation ---literature, the visual arts, music, theatre, opera, dance, film, photography, architecture et al--- from any world culture, using an interdisciplinary &quot;crossroads&quot; approach to enrich and deepen our understanding of these cultural artifacts and the societies that produced them.</s>
    <s>Presentations on interdisciplinary approaches to teaching the humanities are also welcome.</s>
    <s>&gt;Click here for the web portal for submissions of papers, panels, or workshops. Presentation time for individual papers is limited to 15-20 minutes.</s>
    <s>Questions may be directed to Michael Call (michael call@byu.edu), or Marcia Green at (mgreen@sfsu.edu).</s>
    <s>&gt;Member News</s>
    <s>Follow HERA on Facebook and always get the latest news on the Humanities.</s>
    <s>INTERDISCIPLINARY HUMANITIES</s>
    <s>Ongoing call for essays</s>
    <s>and poems</s>
    <s>Upcoming Issues</s>
    <s>Deadline: Nov. 1, 2011</s>
    <s>Spring 2012 - Children's Media</s>
    <s>Wynn Yarbrough, guest editor. This issue will offer up articles, essays, interviews, and creative works by authors who write or produce works for children. Video games, picture books, fantasy, hip-hop, children's poetry: the various media that are relevant to children and have become part of twenty first century humanities warrant study and exploration for teachers and scholars in the humanities. Send inquiries and submissions to Dr. Wynn Yarbrough at wynnyarbrough@gmail.com.</s>
    <s>Deadline: January 15, 2012</s>
    <s>Summer 2012 - Trans form ations Conference Issue</s>
    <s>featuring papers delivered at the March 2011 HERA conference held in San Francisco, California.</s>
    <s>Co-Editors: Lee Ann Westman (lewestman@utep.edu) and Stephen Husarik (shusarik@uafortsmith.edu).</s>
    <s>Deadline: May 1, 2012</s>
    <s>Fall 2012 - Service Learning in the Humanities</s>
    <s>Co-editors Isabel Baca and Joana Owens.</s>
    <s>Service learning across the humanities will include articles, essays, and reflective pieces on service-learning from various points of view: students, faculty, agency mentors, and higher-education and non-profit community administration and staff. Documents may focus on studies, theory, and reflection.</s>
    <s>Send inquiries and papers to Isabel Baca at: ibaca@utep.edu and Joana Owens: jowens1@ju.edu.</s>
    <s>Deadline: November 1, 2012</s>
    <s>Spring 2013 - Pride and Humility</s>
    <s>From the rage of Achilles to Priam's subservient pleadings for Hector's body, from the conceit of King Lear to the meekness of Cordelia, from the terribiliti&gt; of Michelangelo's Moses to the earthy nobility of Van Gogh's Potato Eaters , from the detachment of Lao Tzu to the powerful assertions of Nietzsche, and from the pride punished in Dante's Inferno and Purgatory to the pride celebrated by Michael Eric Dyson; writers, thinkers, and artists through the ages have addressed fundamental questions about the nature of pride and humility.</s>
    <s>This issue of Interdisciplinary Humanities draws upon the widest variety of insights from the humanities to addresses the difficult and even paradoxical questions around pride and humility. Topics related to this theme include, but are not limited to, hubris, victory disease, group think, narcissism, esteem, identity pride, anatta, egolessness, openness, epochbracketing, indeterminacy, and cognitive conflict.</s>
    <s>For more information contact: Shawn Tucker at !</s>
    <s>Deadline: January 15, 2013</s>
    <s>Summer 2013 - Crossroads Conference Issue</s>
    <s>featuring papers delivered at the March 2012 HERA conference held in Salt Lake City, Utah.</s>
    <s>In keeping with HERA's mission of promoting the study of the humanities across a wide range of disciplines, we invite presentations exploring any form of artistic representation--- literature, the visual arts, music, theatre, opera, dance, film, photography, architecture et al ---from any world culture, using an interdisciplinary &quot;crossroads&quot; approach to enrich and deepen our understanding of these cultural artifacts and the societies that produced them -- See conference page.</s>
    <s>Co-Editors: Lee Ann Westman (lewestman@utep.edu) and Stephen Husarik (shusarik@uafortsmith.edu).</s>
    <s>Deadline: May 1, 2013</s>
    <s>Fall 2013 - Fat Representations</s>
    <s>Co-Editors: Dr. Brenda Risch and Christoph Zepeda, M.A.</s>
    <s>The peer-reviewed journal Interdisciplinary Humanities invites submissions of scholarly articles, nonfiction essays, and book and film reviews that explore representations and theories of fat, gender and eating. Suggested topics include, but are not limited to:</s>
    <s>Eating: Representations of eating in popular culture, literature, film, and art. How is eating positioned as an activity of significance/insignificance? How is eating gendered, raced, classed, sexed, etc? What are the linkages between eating and identity, and how are these connections theorized?</s>
    <s>Fat Positive Representations: How do positive representations of fat articulate subjectivity? How is gender, race, class, sexuality, religion, age, physical ability woven into or expressed through fat positive view points? What theories of being rise out of positioning fat/plenitude/abundance as a positive attribute?</s>
    <s>Fat Superheros: What makes a Hero or Heroine of size? What complexities and textures of superhero-hood become visible in a fat superhero? How is she/he translated in film, literature, paintings, action figures, comic books, graphic novels, ceramics, and music?</s>
    <s>Additional topics include: Fat Sexualities; Fat Abroad; Global Perspectives on Fat/Size.</s>
    <s>IH asks that all essays be interdisciplinary in nature, double-spaced, numbered, with one-inch margins on all sides, and that they do not exceed 6,000 words. Please include a 100 word abstract, c.v. and author biography of 200 words with your submission.</s>
    <s>Send queries and submissions to:</s>
    <s>Co-Editors: Brenda Risch (brisch@utep.edu) and Christoph Zepeda (czepeda@alliant.edu).</s>
    <s>Deadline: Nov. 1, 2013</s>
    <s>Spring 2014 - Online Learning in the Humanities</s>
    <s>Send queries and submissions to John R. Groves, Ferris State University (JohnGroves@ferris.edu) and Stephen Husarik, University of Arkansas--Fort Smith (shusarik@fortsmith.edu).</s>
    <s>Deadline: Jan. 15, 2014</s>
    <s>Summer 2014 - Conference Issue</s>
    <s>Book Reviews</s>
    <s>Deadline: Ongoing</s>
    <s>Send book reviews to Wynn Yarbrough at wynnyarbrough@gmail.com.</s>
    <s>Deadline: Ongoing</s>
    <s>General essays: We ask that all essays be interdisciplinary in nature and that they do not exceed 6,000 words. Moreover, essays should be in Microsoft Word format. Submit your essays for consideration to Stephen Husarik at shusarik@uafortsmith.edu and Lee Ann Westman at lewestman@utep.edu.</s>
    <s>Other Humanities Related Calls for Papers (Ongoing)</s>
    <s>Deadline: Ongoing</s>
    <s>CRITIQUE is a peer-reviewed literary journal devoted to essays on contemporary fiction. The editors are also interested in critical essays on the fiction of significant emerging writers from any country.</s>
    <s>More information about CRITIQUE is available at: metapress.com/content/119918/.</s>
    <s>Deadline: Various</s>
    <s>English and American Literature</s>
    <s>The English Department at the University of Pennsylvania hosts a website at: www.english.upenn.edu/CFP/ for calls for papers on English and American Literature and Culture for journals and conferences.</s>
    <s>The host encourages conference or panel organizers and volume editors to post calls to gain the largest possible audience for their announcements by posting them on this list and web archive. Announcements can include calls for upcoming conferences, panels, essay collections, and special journal issues related to English and American literature, and can include calls for completed papers, abstracts, and proposals. The boundaries are flexible: all English-language literatures, cultural studies, literary theory, bibliography, humanities computing, and comparative literature (even when not concerned specifically with English or American literature) are within the pale.</s>
    <s>Due to the volume of postings and the fact that each posting must be approved and edited by hand, the CFP list and web archive is only for calls for papers, not for general conference announcements.</s>
    <s>Deadline: Various</s>
    <s>HNet - Humanities and Social Sciences on Line</s>
    <s>An international consortium of scholars and teachers, H-Net creates and coordinates Internet networks with the common objective of advancing teaching and research in the arts, humanities, and social sciences. H-Net is committed to pioneering the use of new communication technology to facilitate the free exchange of academic ideas and scholarly resources.</s>
    <s>Call for paper announcements can be found at:www.hnet.org/ announce/group.cgi?type=CFPs</s>
    <s>Deadline: Ongoing</s>
    <s>NEBULA is an online academic periodical interested in all things intellectual with the intention of providing a platform for interdisciplinary reading. NEBULA accepts academic articles from any discipline provided that these are written in non-specialist language and in a manner that appeals to a broad audience. In addition, the editors encourage academics and intellectuals to participate in a public debate as regards world politics. Nebula particularly welcomes submissions of a marginal or &quot;against the grain&quot; nature and those that heavily interrogate popular political ideologies in a sound and well-evidenced manner. Writings of high caliber that are particularly underrepresented in other academic periodicals are most welcome for consideration. Nebula also publishes literary and art works and is willing to consider any (graphic, cartoon etc.) material, which can be published on the world wide web.</s>
    <s>More info on submissions is available at www.nobleworld.biz/index.html</s>
    <s>Deadlines vary by issue</s>
    <s>OCHRE Journal of Women's Spirituality is an academic, peer-reviewed, online journal published by the Women's Spirituality, Philosophy and Religion MA and PhD program at California Institute of Integral Studies. OCHRE provides an interdisciplinary and international forum for discourse on women's spirituality among a diversity of voices. The intent of the journal is to utilize the wisdom of women's spirituality to create greater justice, well-being, and peace in our local, global, and planetary communities. You can view the inaugural issue of OCHRE at www.ciis.edu/ochrejournal.</s>
    <s>Other Humanities Related Calls for Papers</s>
    <s>Abstracts due: Nov. 30, 2011</s>
    <s>Final Essays due: Feb. 15, 2012</s>
    <s>Edited Collection</s>
    <s>&quot;Because My Story Matters: Struggle and Success on Higher Education's Frontlines&quot;</s>
    <s>We are interested in what it takes for students to succeed in college-what must be balanced, what must be sacrificed, what must be overcome. We think students, their parents, educators, administrators, and policy makers need this information, too.</s>
    <s>In 2009, Obama charged Higher Ed with dramatically increasing its students' rates of &quot;successful completion,&quot; so 55 % of American citizens will have a college degree or certificate by 2025. This presumably meritorious goal may be misdirected as changes in education ideology and policy are being made absent a clear, shared definition of either &quot;success&quot; or &quot;completion.&quot; Political rhetoric on all levels is rightly acknowledging that many students today have significant and diverse barriers to success; however, the need to secure funding is leading some institutions to rely on historically inflexible gauges of success-like the graduation rates of &quot;first-time full-time&quot; students. This singular statistic often denies students' complex realities by prioritizing some students' stories over others.</s>
    <s>We believe that for real and meaningful change to occur in higher education, the voices of the real people on the frontlines need to be considered before we institutionalize definitions and policies. We are seeking narratives and interviews that tell the experiences of students--those who achieve despite great obstacles, those who challenge traditional notions of success by forging their own paths, those who struggle to keep one foot in the door, those who don't manage to do so-and those teachers and advisors who have always invested time and personal energy in those individuals, even without the national incentives.</s>
    <s>Specifically, we are interested in narrative essays or interviews, written or co-authored by students, educators, advisors, and other ground-level college employees, that feature specific student experiences that should inform-or even challenge-- national discussions of &quot;success&quot; and &quot;completion.&quot; We envision receiving essays or interviews responding but not limited to the following questions:</s>
    <s>What motivates individuals to pursue a college education given their unique life circumstances?</s>
    <s>What kept them on that path as they pursued a degree or certificate?</s>
    <s>Conversely, what made them decide to leave that path?</s>
    <s>How does their experience challenge institutional definitions of &quot;success&quot; that often rely on full-time status or a certain time to degree?</s>
    <s>If they were able to meet the traditional definition of &quot;successful completion&quot; by obtaining a degree or certificate as a full-time student, what did that commitment entail?</s>
    <s>What investment of time, energy, skill, money, etc. did it require of the instructor or advisor to assist one particular student with said challenges?</s>
    <s>Send abstracts (250-300 words) and inquiries to Susan Bernadzikowski and Jennifer Levi (Cecil College) at higheredfrontlines@gmail.com by Nov. 30, 2011.</s>
    <s>Please include contact information and a short bio that is relevant to the project.</s>
    <s>Final essays/interviews of 2000 words maximum due Feb. 15, 2012.</s>
    <s>Proposal Deadline: December 15, 2011</s>
    <s>Conference: April 11-14, 2012</s>
    <s>Boston, Massachusetts</s>
    <s>Medieval Popular Culture and Arthurian Legends</s>
    <s>42nd Annual Popular and American Culture Associations Conference</s>
    <s>Call for papers and panel proposals on all popular treatments of the Middle Ages or Arthurian Legend from any period and in any medium. We will consider all proposals for papers, but we especially encourage abstracts on the following for this years conference:</s>
    <s>Arthurian themes in</s>
    <s>Dragon Age I and II</s>
    <s>Harry Potter and medievalism</s>
    <s>The Lost finale and the Holy Grail Medievalism in Martins G ame of Thrones The Mists of Avalon after 30 years</s>
    <s>New Camelots: Camelot on Starz and the BBCs Merlin</s>
    <s>Paranormal romance and medievalism</s>
    <s>Robin Hood</s>
    <s>Abstracts should not exceed 250 words and papers must keep to a reading time of 15 minutes (approximately 7-8 double spaced pages).</s>
    <s>Be sure to include your full name, affiliation, mailing address, phone number and email address on your abstract, not just in the email. Email submissions are preferred.</s>
    <s>Send submissions to Amy Kaufman at: kaufmana@mtsu.edu or mail to: Amy S. Kaufman Department of English, Middle Tennessee State University MTSU, Box 0070, 1301 East Main Street, Murfreesboro, TN 37132-0001</s>
    <s>Please note: Membership in the PCA is required for participation. Membership forms and more information about the conference are available online at www.pcaaca.org.</s>
    <s>Conference contact email: kaufmana@mtsu.edu</s>
    <s>Proposal Deadline: Oct. 31, 2011.</s>
    <s>The Kenya Studies Review (KSR) is interested in doing a special issue in honor of Professor Wangari Maathai. The issue will be released in 2012. To that end, KSR is interested in receiving paper proposals (title and abstract) from scholars willing to contribute articles for the issue.</s>
    <s>Since Wangari Maathai contributed substantially to Kenya's political economy, environment, ecology, forestry, academia, land, and politics, we'd be especially interested in receiving papers in this areas. Nevertheless, we'll consider all paper proposals that deal with an aspect of Wangari's life. KSR notes for authors are available at: http://kessa.org/kenya studies review - journal</s>
    <s>Please send your paper ideas (title and sbstract) to Maurice N. Amutabi (amutabi@gmail.com) and copy your email to the associate editors: Kefa M. Otiso (kmotiso@bgsu.edu), Francis Koti (ftkoti@una.edu) and Charles G. Manyara (cmanyara@radford.edu).</s>
    <s>Proposal Deadline: September 15, 2011</s>
    <s>Conference Dates: January 8-10, 2012</s>
    <s>Honolulu, Hawaii</s>
    <s>2012 Arts and Humanities Conference</s>
    <s>The 2012 Hawaii University International Conferences (HUIC) on Arts and Humanities welcomes and invites papers, in English only, from all areas and related fields. The conference will be held from 8 January, Sunday to 10 January, Tuesday, 2012 at Ala Moana Hotel in Honolulu Hawaii.</s>
    <s>The conference aim objective is to provide a platform for researchers, academicians as well as professionals from all over the world to present their research results and development in their related fields.</s>
    <s>Submitted conference papers will be peered reviewed Arts and Humanities Topics/Focus Area Origianl Contributions on topics covered under broad areas but not limited to:</s>
    <s>American Studies</s>
    <s>Art History</s>
    <s>Art Management</s>
    <s>Dance Drama, Film, Television, and other Media</s>
    <s>English Ethnic Studies</s>
    <s>Graphic Design</s>
    <s>Languages and Literatures</s>
    <s>Performing Arts</s>
    <s>Product Design</s>
    <s>Second Language Studies</s>
    <s>Speech/Communication and Translation</s>
    <s>Theatre Visual Arts</s>
    <s>Inter-disciplinary and other areas of Arts and Humanities</s>
    <s>PAPER SESSIONS will consist of three to four presentations in a 90 minute session. The session will be divided equally between the presenters. LCD projectors will be available for presentation.</s>
    <s>WORKSHOP PRESENTATIONS will be given a full 90 minute session. LCD projectors will be available for presentation.</s>
    <s>POSTER SESSIONS: A 90 minute open concept with various presenters. This session allows attendees to interact with the presenters one-to-one. Supplies will be provided: Easel, Tri-fold Display Board, Markers, Push Pins, Tapes, Table, etc.</s>
    <s>REVIEWERS are selected among the academic members of the Institute and non-related to Institute academics and researchers. An attempt is made to homogenize the review process and reviewers decisions are based on overall quality of analysis. In cases that the 2 referees have different opinions, the editor decides whether the paper is accepted or rejected. All accepted papers will be considered for publication in the conference proceedings (CD-ROM) which will be made available. Papers Not Presented, are not considered for publication. All the accepted papers will be intimated to the corresponding author only through e-mail. EVERYONE IS WELCOME TO ATTEND the conference. If you wish to participate without presenting a paper, i.e. chair a session, evaluate papers to be included in the conference program and proceedings please send an email to: artshumanities@huichawaii.org</s>
    <s>SESSION CHAIR is required to register for the conference.</s>
    <s>SUBMITTING A PROPOSAL / Submission Procedure: via email or regular post mail. Please indicate the topic/area for which your paper is suitable. Each paper will be double-blind peer reviewed in the relevant area 1. Create a Title Page for your submission. The title page should include: a. Title of your paper/proposal b. Topics/Areas c. Presentation format: Papers, Workshop, or Poster d. Name(s) of the author(s) e. Department(s) and Affiliation(s) f. Mailing Address(es) g. E-mail Address(es) h. Contacts/Phone Number(s) i. Fax number(s) j. Corresponding/presenting author if different than lead author</s>
    <s>2. SENDING ABSTRACT(s) / PROPOSAL(s): Call for Research Papers, Student Papers, Case Studies, Reports, Thesis, and Abstracts Please send your ABSTRACTS or PAPERS as an MS word/PDF attachment to the following Email-address: artshumanities@huichawaii.org</s>
    <s>By regular mailing to: P.O. Box 29056 Honolulu, Hawaii 96820</s>
    <s>Conference Proceedings Publication - US Library of Congress: ISSN 2160-2581 (CD-ROM) ISSN 2610-2573 (ONLINE)</s>
    <s>11452 Hawaii University International Conferences P.O. Box 29056 Honolulu, Hawaii 96820.</s>
    <s>The Conference accepts a limit of two contributed submissions per lead author. Email your abstract and/or paper, along with a title page, acknowledgement of received submissions will be corresponded via email. If you have not heard from within 72 hours, please do not hesitate to contact us or send us an email.</s>
    <s>For more information go to: http://www.huichawaii.org/paper-formats-2012anh</s>
  </text>
</page>
