<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://spaceelevatorconference.org/callforpapers.aspx</url>
  <title>2011 Space Elevator Conference Call for Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Call for Papers. Abstracts must be in English, one page or less, and summarize a presentation suitable for the conference. For all submittals, please include the </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>2011 Space Elevator Conference</s>
    <s>August 12-14 | Microsoft Conference Center | Redmond, Washington, USA</s>
    <s>Technical Program</s>
    <s>Family Science Fest</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>About the Space Elevator</s>
    <s>Hotels &amp; Directions</s>
    <s>Press Releases</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Abstracts must be in English, one page or less, and summarize a presentation suitable for the conference. For all submittals, please include the title, authors and affiliations, mail address, e-mail, and phone number of the corresponding author, and up to 10 key words.  Abstracts are due by July 1, 2011.  Authors will be notified of acceptance by July 8th, 2011 or earlier.  Final drafts of the presentations in PowerPoint or PDF formats will be due before the conference on July 29, 2011.</s>
    <s>We will collect all presentations made and include them in the conference proceedings, to be offered for sale on digital media after the conference.  By submitting a presentation to the conference, the author(s) explicitly gives the Space Elevator Conference organizing committee the right to include their presentation in these proceedings.  In addition, the author(s) are expected to submit a supporting paper which will also be included in the proceedings, the deadline for which is August 29, 2011.</s>
    <s>Submit your abstracts and papers to the online Conference Management Tool (CMT).</s>
    <s>Abstracts, papers, and technical program inquiries to:</s>
    <s>David Horn (david.horn@microsoft.com)</s>
    <s>Due Dates</s>
    <s>Abstracts Due:  July 1, 2011</s>
    <s>Final Acceptance: By July 8, 2011</s>
    <s>Draft Presentations Due:  July 29, 2011</s>
    <s>Papers for Proceedings Due:  August 29, 2011</s>
  </text>
</page>
