<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://iassais.wordpress.com/2011/04/16/call-for-papers-1st-international-conference-on-semiotics-and-visual-communication/</url>
  <title>Call for papers: 1st International Conference on Semiotics and ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Apr 16, 2011 Call for papers. 1st International Conference on Semiotics and Visual Communication. Date: 25-Nov-2011 – 27-Nov-2011. Location: Limassol </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>IASS Publications</s>
    <s>Entries RSS | Comments RSS</s>
    <s>Recent Posts</s>
    <s>Call for Papers - 11th World Congress of Semiotics</s>
    <s>WATS: World Association for Theoretical Semiotics</s>
    <s>On Youtube: Eero Tarasti lecture course on the &quot;European semiotics&quot; and a roundtable about his theory of existential semiotics</s>
    <s>Tourist Spaces Between Practices and Theories - International Conference</s>
    <s>Publication of Lexia n.7-8</s>
    <s>Call for Papers of Lexia n. 11: The Semiotics of Worship</s>
    <s>New semiotic journal - SIGNATA - Université de Liège</s>
    <s>Opening speech Imatra ISI Summer congresses, Finland, June 5, 2011</s>
    <s>Final Program: 26th International Summer School for Semiotic and Structural Studies - Imatra</s>
    <s>New book: Performance et savoirs - André Helbo</s>
    <s>Call for papers: Tourist Spaces - Between Practices and Theories - University of Palermo, July 7-8-9, 2011</s>
    <s>Call for papers: 1st International Conference on Semiotics and Visual Communication</s>
    <s>Victoria Welby and Significs: Essays for a Special Issue of Semiotica</s>
    <s>Call for papers: Analysing Multimodal Discourse: Systemic Functional Linguistics Meets Pragmatics</s>
    <s>Select Month October 2011 (1) September 2011 (1) July 2011 (2) June 2011 (5) May 2011 (3) April 2011 (3) March 2011 (5) February 2011 (6) January 2011 (3) December 2010 (1) November 2010 (2) October 2010 (2) September 2010 (3) August 2010 (3) July 2010 (2) June 2010 (1) May 2010 (11) April 2010 (41) March 2010 (63)</s>
    <s>Call for papers: 1st International Conference on Semiotics and Visual Communication</s>
    <s>Posted on April 16, 2011 by iassais</s>
    <s>Call for papers</s>
    <s>1st International Conference on Semiotics and Visual Communication</s>
    <s>Date: 25-Nov-2011 - 27-Nov-2011</s>
    <s>Location: Limassol, Cyprus</s>
    <s>The department of Multimedia and Graphic Arts of the Cyprus University of Technology is organizing the 1st International Conference on Semiotics and Visual Communication themed ‘From Theory to Practice’ (25-27 November 2011). The conference aims at exploring the broad subject of semiotics in a wide sense, aspiring to bring together researchers and practitioners who study and evaluate the ways that semiotic theories can be analyzed, perceived and applied in the context of various forms in visual communication.</s>
    <s>Keynote Speakers:</s>
    <s>-        Theo van Leeuwen, Professor, Dean, Faculty of Arts and Social Sciences, University of Technology, Sydney, Australia</s>
    <s>-        Gregory Paschalidis, Associate Professor of Cultural Studies, School of Journalism and Mass Communications, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki</s>
    <s>Thematic areas</s>
    <s>The conference is categorized into 6 main thematic areas, under the scope of Semiotics and:</s>
    <s>- Design for Print applications</s>
    <s>- Design for Screen based media</s>
    <s>- Design for three-dimensional products</s>
    <s>- Pedagogy of Visual Communication</s>
    <s>- Architecture and Spatial design</s>
    <s>- Visual Arts</s>
    <s>Some indicative issues include, but are not limited to Semiotics and:</s>
    <s>- Typography, Editorial design, Publishing, Advertising, Packaging and Information design.</s>
    <s>- Interface and web design, Multimedia design and interactive applications, Animation, Motion graphics and Kinetic-typography.</s>
    <s>- Product design, Jewelry design, Fashion and Textile design.</s>
    <s>- Architecture, Interior design, Landscape architecture, Scientific mapping and mental maps.</s>
    <s>- Photography, Illustration, Painting, New-media art, Video, Film, Cinema and Television.</s>
    <s>The official languages of the conference are Greek and English.</s>
    <s>Speakers are invited to engage with the above thematic areas, and should describe original work, either completed historical or theoretical research or significant work in progress. Individual papers will be allocated 30 minutes (20 minutes for presentation and 10 minutes for discussion).</s>
    <s>Submissions will be reviewed on the basis of extended abstracts between 400 and 600 words, to be received by e-mail no later than the 2nd of May 2011.</s>
    <s>Abstracts must include the thematic area, the title of the paper, the full name/s, together with author/s brief c.v. of no more than 200 words, institutional and e-mail addresses of all authors and a telephone number for at least one contact author. Authors will be notified by the 6th of June 2011 about review results for their submissions. Publication opportunities of extended versions of a selected range of papers will be considered in the form of an edited book.</s>
    <s>For abstract submission and proposal inquiries please contact:</s>
    <s>Evripides Zantides, Cyprus University of Technology, Cyprus, Department of Multimedia and Graphic Arts, e-mail: evripides.zantidescut.ac.cy</s>
    <s>The abstract proposals can be in Greek or English and should include the following information:</s>
    <s>- Thematic choice</s>
    <s>- Title of paper</s>
    <s>- Author/s name/s, institution/s and country/ies, email address/es, one telephone number</s>
    <s>- Abstract (between 400 and 600 words)</s>
    <s>- Brief CV (of no more than 200 words)</s>
    <s>Conference site: http://www.cut.ac.cy/</s>
    <s>The conference fee for all three days is 50 Euros. Registrations are made online.</s>
    <s>Deadline for registration-authors: July 15th, 2011</s>
    <s>Deadline for registration-participants: November 1st 2011</s>
    <s>Scientific Committee:</s>
    <s>Savvas Christodoulides, Assistant Professor, Department of Applied Arts, Frederic University</s>
    <s>Anastasia Christodoulou, Assistant Professor in Semiotics, Department of Italian Studies, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki</s>
    <s>Antonis Danos, Lecturer, Department of Multimedia and Graphic Arts, Cyprus University of Technology</s>
    <s>Matthew Hobson, Senior Lecturer, Graphic Design, London Metropolitan University</s>
    <s>Marianna Kafaridou, Associate Professor, Department of Design and Multimedia, University of Nicosia</s>
    <s>Evangelos Kourdis, Lecturer, Department of French Language and Literature, Section of Translation, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki</s>
    <s>Alexandros Ph. Lagopoulos, Professor Emeritus, Department of Architecture, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Corresponding Member of the Academy of Athens</s>
    <s>Jeff Leak, Course Leader, Graphic Communication, University of Wolverhampton</s>
    <s>Paul Middleton, Dean, School of the Arts, University of Northampton</s>
    <s>Arafat Al Naim, Associate Professor, Faculty of Art and Design, Zarqa University</s>
    <s>Grigoris Paschalidis, Associate Professor, Department of Journalism and Media, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki</s>
    <s>Marios Phocas, Associate Professor, Department of Architecture, University of Cyprus</s>
    <s>Evripides Zantides, Assistant Professor, Department of Multimedia and Graphic Arts, Cyprus University of Technology</s>
    <s>Organizing Committee:</s>
    <s>Monika Herodotou, Special Teaching Staff, Department of Multimedia and</s>
    <s>Graphic Arts, Cyprus University of Technology</s>
    <s>Eleftheria Iasonos, Graphic Designer</s>
    <s>Theseas Mouzouropoulos, Special Teaching Staff, Department of Multimedia and Graphic Arts, Cyprus University of Technology</s>
    <s>Aspasia Papadima, Lecturer, Department of Multimedia and Graphic Arts, Cyprus University of Technology</s>
    <s>Ioanna Tymbiotou, Special Scientist, Department of Multimedia and Graphic Arts, Cyprus University of Technology</s>
    <s>Evripides Zantides, Assistant Professor, Department of Multimedia and Graphic Arts, Cyprus University of Technology</s>
    <s>Panayiotis Zaphiris, Associate Professor, Department of Multimedia and Graphic Arts, Cyprus University of Technology</s>
    <s>Share this:</s>
    <s>Like this:</s>
    <s>Be the first to like this post.</s>
    <s>Filed under: Congress &amp; Call for Papers</s>
    <s>« Victoria Welby and Significs: Essays for a Special Issue of Semiotica Call for papers: Tourist Spaces - Between Practices and Theories - University of Palermo, July 7-8-9, 2011 »</s>
    <s>2 Responses</s>
    <s>1. !</s>
    <s>uniench, on July 14, 2011 at 8:36 am said:</s>
    <s>how to registration? i'm concern about this call paper !:)</s>
    <s>Log in to Reply</s>
    <s>priborges, on July 14, 2011 at 12:09 pm said:</s>
    <s>Please access the conference site for more information. http://www.cut.ac.cy/</s>
    <s>Log in to Reply</s>
    <s>Leave a Reply Cancel reply</s>
    <s>Enter your comment here </s>
    <s>Log In</s>
    <s>Log In</s>
    <s>Log In</s>
    <s>Email (required) (Not published)</s>
    <s>Name (required)</s>
    <s>!WordPress.com Logo</s>
    <s>Please log in to WordPress.com to post a comment to your blog.</s>
    <s>!Twitter picture</s>
    <s>You are commenting using your Twitter account. (Log Out)</s>
    <s>!Facebook photo</s>
    <s>You are commenting using your Facebook account. (Log Out)</s>
    <s>Connecting to %s</s>
    <s>Notify me of follow-up comments via email.</s>
    <s>Notify me of new posts via email.</s>
    <s>Online Services</s>
    <s>Bulletin Board Announcements</s>
    <s>Congress &amp; Call for Papers</s>
    <s>IASS Meetings (CFP)</s>
    <s>Congress Calendar</s>
    <s>Presidential Message</s>
    <s>Research Projects</s>
    <s>Semiotic Online</s>
    <s>Online Resources</s>
    <s>Semiotic Publications</s>
    <s>Semiotic Research Institutes</s>
    <s>Semiotic Teaching</s>
    <s>Email Subscription</s>
    <s>Enter your email address to subscribe to this blog and receive notifications of new posts by email.</s>
    <s>Join 81 other followers</s>
    <s>Apr|2010 Apr|2011 Aug|2010 Bibliography BUAP Cognitive Semiotics Dec|2010 ESCOM Paris European Union Finnish Network University Hellenic Semiotic Society iass IASS Congress International Semiotics Institute July|2010 July|2011 June|2010 Lund University MA May|2010 New Bulgarian University Nov|2010 Oct|2010 Portuguese Catholic University PUC-SP Rijksuniversiteit Groningen Semiotics Institute Online Sept|2010 Sign Dictionaries Swiss Association of Semiotics Tallinn University (Estonia) Tartu University Tel Aviv University Terminological Lexica UNAM México University of Bremen University of Helsinki Università di Bologna Urbino University Vilnius University Lithuania</s>
    <s>Your Collaboration</s>
    <s>You are kindly asked to visit the site periodically - we do our best to satisfy your needs. But, in order to be able to do so, we have to rely on your help: You are kindly invited (1) to send us any kind of information that should be presented to the semiotic community, (2) to tell us what kind of information you would like to find on these pages, (3) to tell us about other interesting web pages on semiotics and related fields, (4) etc.</s>
    <s>You can collaborate with the IASS Blog posting comments or e-mailing Priscila Borges: borges.iass@gmail.com</s>
    <s>Blog at WordPress.com. Theme: Digg 3 Column by WP Designer.</s>
    <s>Follow IASS-AIS</s>
    <s>Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.</s>
    <s>Join 81 other followers</s>
    <s>Powered by WordPress.com</s>
    <s>Send to Email Address Your Name Your Email Address</s>
    <s>!loading Cancel</s>
    <s>Post was not sent - check your email addresses</s>
    <s>Email check failed, please try again</s>
    <s>Sorry, your blog cannot share posts by email.</s>
    <s>*RSS: Really Simple Syndication</s>
  </text>
</page>
