<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.cmhtampaconference.com/</url>
  <title>2012 CMH Tampa Conference</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>The 25th Annual Children&#39;s Mental Health Research and Policy Conference seeks to enhance the effectiveness of services and systems for Call for Papers </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Conference Registration</s>
    <s>Hotel Registration</s>
    <s>Our History</s>
    <s>Research Highlights</s>
    <s>24th Conference</s>
    <s>23rd Conference</s>
    <s>Past Conferences</s>
    <s>Contact Us</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>March 4 -7, 2012 at the Hyatt Regency Hotel in Tampa, FL</s>
    <s>This is your opportunity to be a part of the national dialogue about cutting edge research and policy in children’s mental health</s>
    <s>Read More</s>
    <s>Research Highlights</s>
    <s>Research Highlights brings you a closer look at published articles from featured presentations at the annual Children’s Mental Health Research &amp; Policy Conference.</s>
    <s>Current Issue Past Issues</s>
    <s>Tampa, FL Weather</s>
    <s>!Mostly Cloudy</s>
    <s>Mostly Cloudy</s>
    <s>Humidity: 88%</s>
    <s>Wind: N at 0 mph</s>
    <s>Thu 67°F / 86°F !Showers</s>
    <s>Fri 63°F / 88°F !Clear</s>
    <s>Sat 63°F / 85°F !Clear</s>
    <s>Sun 65°F / 85°F !Mostly Sunny</s>
    <s>Conference Updates</s>
    <s>Subscribe to our mailing list</s>
    <s>indicates required</s>
    <s>First Name *</s>
    <s>Last Name *</s>
    <s>Email Address *</s>
    <s>Why You Should Attend</s>
    <s>Since 1988, Department of Child and Family Studies at the University of South Florida has been a leader in promoting the expansion of the research base essential to improved service systems for children and youth with mental health challenges and their families. Our first national conference, also initiated in 1988, was on system of care research primarily to enhance the capacity of the children’s mental health field to systematically study important issues. This conference has continued each year, bringing together more than 500 researchers, evaluators, policy-makers, administrators, parents, and advocates to share dialogue about important issues such as health, education and welfare, share new knowledge, and identify challenges that remain for the field.</s>
    <s>Featured Speakers</s>
    <s>Our keynote and plenary speakers are individuals who have made great contributions toward improving services for children, youth and families. A standing room only crowd attended the 2011 keynote address by celebrated educator Geoffrey Canada.</s>
    <s>Symposia, papers and posters</s>
    <s>The annual conference is the focal point for the national dissemination of outcome data, ongoing research and policy development updates in the children’s mental health field. The conference features a wide array of symposia, papers and poster presentations from an international field of scholars, educators, policy makers and families who are integrally involved in shaping the children’s mental health field in America.</s>
    <s>Intensive pre-conference sessions</s>
    <s>Each year topical intensive pre-conference sessions are designed to stretch your thinking about how the use of research can and does impact policy and practice in children’s mental health.</s>
    <s>National technical assistance forums</s>
    <s>A hallmark of this conference is the close collaboration with national research and training centers focused on community-based approaches to meeting the needs of children and families.</s>
    <s>Topics for 2012:</s>
    <s>» Research on system level structures and processes that impact effectiveness</s>
    <s>» Research within and across systems, policy and practice (such as child/adolescent to adult mental health, school to employment supports)</s>
    <s>» Research regarding family, youth, and young adult roles in mental health services</s>
    <s>» Linking primary care to mental health</s>
    <s>» Family-to-family and peer-to-peer supports</s>
    <s>» Community-based approaches to reducing disparities</s>
    <s>» Integration of policy and practice across sectors (such as child welfare and mental health, schools and juvenile justice)</s>
    <s>» Implementing evidence-based and community-defined practices</s>
    <s>» The role of youth and young adult leadership in shaping system change</s>
    <s>» Innovative approaches to research, evaluation and performance measurement in complex settings</s>
    <s>» Early childhood mental health</s>
    <s>» Substance abuse and dual diagnosis among youth and young adults</s>
    <s>» Community-based participatory research</s>
    <s>» Innovative approaches for older youth and young adults</s>
    <s>The Department of Child &amp; Family Studies (C) 2011 | Privacy policy | Copyright</s>
  </text>
</page>
