<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.icahdq.org/</url>
  <title>International Communication Association</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>UC-ICA Conference: Call for Papers - Trends in International and Latin American Communication Research Call for Papers Also Available in Spanish </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>About ICA</s>
    <s>President's Welcome</s>
    <s>Contact Us</s>
    <s>Mission Statement</s>
    <s>Ethics Statement</s>
    <s>Executive Committee</s>
    <s>Past Presidents</s>
    <s>Join Us</s>
    <s>Member Benefits</s>
    <s>Affiliate Organizations</s>
    <s>Renew Your Membership</s>
    <s>ICA Conferences</s>
    <s>Co-Sponsored Conferences</s>
    <s>Other Conferences</s>
    <s>ICA Books</s>
    <s>Publication Manual</s>
    <s>ICA Newsletter</s>
    <s>Calls and Announcements</s>
    <s>APA Style</s>
    <s>Annual and Other Reports</s>
    <s>ICA Newsletter</s>
    <s>Press Releases</s>
    <s>Outstanding Book Award Winners</s>
    <s>Fellows Book Award Winners</s>
    <s>Award Winners</s>
    <s>Advertise Here</s>
    <s>Newsletter Ad Rates</s>
    <s>Membership Address List Rental</s>
    <s>2012 Call For Papers</s>
    <s>Preconference CFPs</s>
    <s>Publication CFPs</s>
    <s>Other CFPs</s>
    <s>Paper &amp; Management System</s>
    <s>Member Resources</s>
    <s>Member Login</s>
    <s>Find a Colleague</s>
    <s>ICA Budget</s>
    <s>CIOS Login</s>
    <s>Publisher Discounts</s>
    <s>Manage Your Account</s>
    <s>ICA Members </s>
    <s>The Best Research</s>
    <s>By asking relevant questions and conducting academically sound research to find solutions, communication scholars, with ICA as their premier academic association, are uniquely poised to answer questions of real societal import. Find out more about ICA membership by clicking here.</s>
    <s>ICA Conferences </s>
    <s>Highest-Caliber Scholarship</s>
    <s>ICA Conferences include some of the premier scholars in communication studies worldwide. We aim to advance the scholarly study of human communication by encouraging and facilitating excellence in academic research. Visit our conference website for information about current, past, and future ICA conferences.</s>
    <s>ICA Awards Global Recognition</s>
    <s>ICA presents nine prestigious research awards to communication scholars at our annual awards ceremony. Learn more about the awards, past recipients, or click here for nomination guidelines.</s>
    <s>ICA Publications </s>
    <s>Consistently Top Ranked</s>
    <s>ICA publishes the best available scholarship on all aspects of communication. Each of our five highly ranked journals and other publications offer high quality research and analyses from diverse theoretical and methodological approaches from all fields of communication, media and cultural studies.</s>
    <s>Top News</s>
    <s>Vote in the ICA Elections</s>
    <s>ICA Members: The annual election of officers and section officers is open now until October 14th. Read the candidates' statements here or as a pop up window during the voting process. When you sign in to the election site, you will see a personalized ballot based on the divisions and interest groups of which you are a member. To vote go to the ICA voting site</s>
    <s>Renew Your Membership</s>
    <s>Paper Submission and Management System Open for Submissions</s>
    <s>Other News of Interest</s>
    <s>Read the latest ICA Newsletter</s>
    <s>Learn about Preconferences for the ICA Annual Conference in Phoenix</s>
    <s>UC-ICA Conference: Call for Papers - Trends in International and Latin American Communication Research</s>
    <s>Call for Papers Also Available in Spanish</s>
    <s>2012 Annual Conference in Phoenix</s>
    <s>Access the full call for papers</s>
    <s>Access the Paper Management Site to Submit or Edit a Proposal</s>
    <s>Go to Conference Page to Learn More &quot;</s>
    <s>Student/Fellowship Opportunities</s>
    <s>ICA aims to connect scholars with opportunities that will advance individual academic pursuits and the study of communication. When opportunities for studentships, fellowships, and funding become available, ICA will publicize these posts in the Student/Fellowship Opportunities section of our website.</s>
    <s>Audiences: A Cross Generational Dialogue</s>
    <s>Doctoral Scholarship - Institute of Culture &amp; Society</s>
    <s>Career Development Fellow in Media and Democracy</s>
    <s>Postgrad Research at Dublin City U</s>
    <s>ICA Membership</s>
    <s>International Communication Association's mission is to advance the scholarly study of human communication by encouraging and facilitating excellence in academic research worldwide.</s>
    <s>ICA membership include subscriptions to any of our journals. Full-text online access to ALL previously published ICA journals are available to members. To see other membership benefits, visit our membership benefits page. To join ICA, visit our membership application site. If you are a current or former member wishing to renew, click here to renew or reinstate your membership!</s>
    <s>Donate to ICA</s>
    <s>We would like to thank you for considering a donation to the International Communication Association. ICA is a not-for-profit that relies primarily on membership and conference fees and publication royalties for its income. Although ICA has been doing well financially in recent years, the organization needs to look toward its future. In doing so, ICA hopes to establish the resources necessary to pursue the Association's mission.</s>
    <s>Every donation aids ICA in achieving our mission to advance the scholarly study of human communication by encouraging and facilitating excellence in academic research worldwide. Your contribution is an investment in the future of communication research and helps build a solid foundation for future scholars. ICA offers its know-how to everybody and every area of the world where the norms of personal freedom and democracy are upheld and assists our members in actively contributing to public debate on topics relative to our mission. For more information or to make a donation, start at http://www.icahdq.org/fundraising/</s>
    <s>About ICA</s>
    <s>Join Us</s>
    <s>Calls For</s>
    <s>Member Resource Center</s>
    <s>Communication and Technology</s>
    <s>Communication Law and Policy</s>
    <s>Children, Adolescents and the Media</s>
    <s>Communication History</s>
    <s>Environmental Communication</s>
    <s>Ethnicity and Race in Communication</s>
    <s>Feminist Scholarship</s>
    <s>Game Studies</s>
    <s>Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual and Transgender Studies</s>
    <s>Global Communication and Social Change</s>
    <s>Health Communication</s>
    <s>Information Systems</s>
    <s>Intergroup Communication</s>
    <s>Instructional and Developmental Communication</s>
    <s>Intercultural Communication</s>
    <s>Interpersonal Communication</s>
    <s>Journalism Studies</s>
    <s>Language and Social Interaction</s>
    <s>Mass Communication</s>
    <s>Organizational Communication</s>
    <s>Philosophy of Communication</s>
    <s>Political Communication</s>
    <s>Popular Communication</s>
    <s>Public Relations</s>
    <s>Visual Communication Studies</s>
    <s>Select LanguageAfrikaansAlbanianArabicArmenianAzerbaijaniBasqueBelarusianBulgarianCatalanChinese (Simplified)Chinese (Traditional)CroatianCzechDanishDutchEnglishEstonianFilipinoFinnishFrenchGalicianGeorgianGermanGreekHaitian CreoleHebrewHindiHungarianIcelandicIndonesianIrishItalianJapaneseKoreanLatvianLithuanianMacedonianMalayMalteseNorwegianPersianPolishPortugueseRomanianRussianSerbianSlovakSlovenianSpanishSwahiliSwedishThaiTurkishUkrainianUrduVietnameseWelshYiddish</s>
  </text>
</page>
