<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.sas.org/virtualConf.html</url>
  <title>Virtual Conference Call for Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>&quot;Virtual&quot; Conference on Informal Science Education. Spring 2004. As part of our 10-year anniversary celebration, the Society for Amateur Scientists is expanding </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Search www Search www.sas.org</s>
    <s>! !!</s>
    <s>Virtual Conference</s>
    <s>LABRats Home</s>
    <s>&quot;Virtual&quot; Conference on Informal Science Education</s>
    <s>Spring 2004</s>
    <s>As part of our 10-year anniversary celebration, the Society for Amateur Scientists is expanding its educational mission and developing LABRats, a revolutionary new informal science education program that will link scientists and engineers of all stripes to Americas teens. We are hosting this &quot;virtual&quot; conference to gain valuable insights to help inform LABRats design and the field of informal science education in general.</s>
    <s>We asked for personal reflections of informal science education experiences. We wanted to understand the factors that influence the quality of an informal science experience from all perspectives  student, teacher, mentor, program director, etc. In addition, we wanted to know how these experiences impacted the people who had them.</s>
    <s>We received a collection of papers that reflect a wide variety of perspectives and experiences. We hope you enjoy learning from the &quot;virtual&quot; conference as much as we did.</s>
    <s>To stay informed of major LABRats developments, we invite you to subscribe to the LABRats Newsgroup.</s>
    <s>How did you like the conference? Email us your comments, questions, and suggestions.</s>
    <s>Mentoring Student Scientists: Four Case Studies</s>
    <s>Forrest M. Mims III</s>
    <s>Forrest Mims is a highly accomplished citizen scientist and is dedicated to the education of the next generation of scientists. In this article, Forrest shares his experiences mentoring four exceptional students and highlights the benefits for both students and mentors.</s>
    <s>360 Degrees of COSI Academy</s>
    <s>David Briley, Jim Bergner, Bryan May, Kyle Moore, and Amy Schlegel</s>
    <s>David Briley is the Founder of COSI Academy, an informal science education program for teenagers. In this collection of essays from David, a COSI mentor, and several COSI participants, the reader is treated to a full-circle view of the program.</s>
    <s>They Actually Did Print It</s>
    <s>John W. Gudenas, Ph.D.</s>
    <s>Dr. Gudenas developed scifair.org, a premier website for students working on science fair projects. In peak months, the site receives almost 4 million hits. In this paper, Dr. Gudenas shares his experiences with the media in relation to scifair.org and other service learning projects.</s>
    <s>The Hands-On Approach of Teaching Science to Young People</s>
    <s>Scott Little</s>
    <s>Scott Little is a Systems Engineer/Project Manager. He is also the parent of two boys, ages nine and five. This paper discusses his experiences with his boys as he tries to instill in them the love of science he has by taking apart electronic and household items.</s>
    <s>The Development of a Scientist</s>
    <s>Donald Sieber</s>
    <s>Donald Sieber is a retiree and a dedicated member of the Society for Amateur Scientists. In this article, Donald shares the role informal science education played in his life and his current joy in conducting science demonstrations for 4th through 6th graders.</s>
    <s>Reflections on Three &quot;Might-Have-Been&quot; Mentors</s>
    <s>Sheldon Greaves, Ph.D.</s>
    <s>Dr. Greaves is Managing Editor and Webmaster for the Society for Amateur Scientists. Looking back on his science education experiences, both informal and formal, this paper makes a call for deeper, longer-term mentor relationships that not only excite young people about science, but also teach the process of science.</s>
    <s>Barn Rats</s>
    <s>F. Emilie Glover</s>
    <s>In this paper, Emilie explores the benefits observation of and interaction with horses can offer to young people interested in science.</s>
    <s>The Use of Field Experience in Formal Biology Teaching for 1st through 10th Graders</s>
    <s>James W. Farr</s>
    <s>James relates his experiences as a part-time naturalist introducing students in 1st through 10th grade on field trips to the world of living things.</s>
    <s>Contact Us | Careers | Privacy Statement | Legal Disclosure</s>
    <s>Copyright (C) 2004 Society for Amateur Scientists</s>
  </text>
</page>
