<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.8thfeministconference.org/index.php%3Fmenu%3D3</url>
  <title>Call for papers - 8th Feminist Conference | Budapest, Hungary</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Call for Papers. The 8th European Feminist Research </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Self portrait with magnifier</s>
    <s>by Kiss Marta</s>
    <s>The Politics of Location Revisited: Gender@2012</s>
    <s>8th European Feminist Research Conference</s>
    <s>May 17-20, 2012 | Budapest, Hungary</s>
    <s>HomeCall for papersStudent's DayRegistrationTravel Information</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>The 8th European Feminist Research Conference welcomes papers that keep in focus the connections among a number of relevant axes that frame current researches in the field. We have in mind connections between disciplines and interdisciplinarity; the past, the present and the future; gender and intersectionality; activism and power; local and global; margin and center. The strands listed below indicate the main lines of inquiry around which the Conference will be structured.</s>
    <s>Participants must indicate the strand their paper addresses. Based on this indication the Conference Committee will create intersecting panels across different strands. Please be aware that the strands were created with the intention to be inclusive, and the descriptions might help you to decide what framework is the best for your research.</s>
    <s>Conference Strands, Student's Day</s>
    <s>Women's and Gender Studies between Neo-discipline and Interdisciplinarity</s>
    <s>» description</s>
    <s>Rooting and Shifting (in) Feminist Research: Assessing the 'Turns' in Feminist Theory</s>
    <s>» description</s>
    <s>Teaching 'Gender' across the Borders of the Human, Social, Natural and Biomedical Sciences</s>
    <s>» description</s>
    <s>Located at Crossroads of Race and Gender: Intersectional Analysis in Women's and Gender Studies</s>
    <s>» description</s>
    <s>Shifting Sexualities, Masculinities and Femininities: LGBTQI</s>
    <s>» description</s>
    <s>Revisiting 'Equality vs. Difference': Feminism in the 21st Century</s>
    <s>» description</s>
    <s>Triple Helix of Social Inclusion: Connecting Activism, Policy-making and Gender Research</s>
    <s>» description</s>
    <s>Feminist Legacies, Feminist Futures: Generating Feminisms</s>
    <s>» description</s>
    <s>The Politics of Migration: Transnational Feminisms?</s>
    <s>» description</s>
    <s>Re-Imagining 'Europe': Imperialism, Post-State Socialism and Multiculturalism in the 21st Century</s>
    <s>» description</s>
    <s>Violence Revisited: Security, War and Peace Narrated</s>
    <s>» description</s>
    <s>Religion Revisited: Spirituality, Gender and the Post-Secular</s>
    <s>» description</s>
    <s>Creativity Reconsidered: Rethinking Feminist Art, Media and Technological Practices</s>
    <s>» description</s>
    <s>Student's Day</s>
    <s>» description</s>
    <s>Conference Strands Abstract Submission</s>
    <s>ASSZISZTENCIA Szervezo Kft. • Szent Istvan krt 7, H-1055 Budapest, Hungary • Phone: +36 1 350 1854 • Fax: +36 1 350 0929 • Email: info@asszisztencia.hu</s>
  </text>
</page>
