<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.cmascenter.org/conference/2011/call_for_papers.cfm</url>
  <title>Community Modeling and Analysis (CMAS) - 2011 Conference Call ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Sep 2, 2011 HOME &gt; conference &gt; call for papers The deadline to submit oral and poster abstracts for the 10th Annual CMAS Conference has passed. </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Create a CMAS Account or Login</s>
    <s>October 13, 2011</s>
    <s>Home | about | cmas quarterly | contact | eac | sitemap | user survey | users forum |</s>
    <s>Help Desk</s>
    <s>hardware consulting</s>
    <s>Download Center</s>
    <s>release calendar</s>
    <s>Conferences &amp; Meetings</s>
    <s>2011 Agenda</s>
    <s>2011 Call for Papers</s>
    <s>other conferences</s>
    <s>payment info</s>
    <s>payment info</s>
    <s>training facility</s>
    <s>visa info</s>
    <s>visiting scientist program</s>
    <s>Research &amp; Development</s>
    <s>cmaq review process</s>
    <s>for developers</s>
    <s>Community Resources</s>
    <s>image gallery</s>
    <s>job postings</s>
    <s>user directory</s>
    <s>!User Details</s>
    <s>Create a CMAS Account</s>
    <s>or Login Below:</s>
    <s>Forgot your password?</s>
    <s>New User Information</s>
    <s>HOME &gt; conference &gt; call for papers</s>
    <s>2011 Conference Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Sessions | Extended Abstract Guidelines | Presenter Information</s>
    <s>CMAS is NO LONGER accepting oral and poster abstracts for the sessions listed below . The deadline to submit oral and poster abstracts for the 10th Annual CMAS Conference has passed. Please see the 10th Annual CMAS Conference Agenda to view accepted oral and poster abstracts.</s>
    <s>Sessions planned for the 10th Annual CMAS Conference:</s>
    <s>Session 1: Air Quality Forecasting (Special Session; In memory of Dr. Daewon Byun)</s>
    <s>Real-time air quality forecasts are important source of information to alert the public of potential poor air quality conditions, and to support organizations that strive to improve public health. This session focuses on papers describing new improvements in air quality forecasting techniques, applications, and community needs. This session topics include:</s>
    <s>Operational and computational needs</s>
    <s>Model performance evaluation and forecasting skills</s>
    <s>Objective analysis methods</s>
    <s>Accuracy and Spatial Resolution</s>
    <s>Public and media dissemination</s>
    <s>Session 2: Model Development</s>
    <s>Work in recent years has vastly improved the science of air quality and methodologies for modeling and analyzing the distribution of air pollutants at various temporal and spatial scales. Such advances were motivated by the results from the multitude of applications and evaluations of air quality models that addressed various research, development and regulatory modeling issues. We seek abstracts that illustrate innovative methodologies and process algorithms in air quality modeling. This Session topics include:</s>
    <s>Indirect radiative effect of aerosols</s>
    <s>Adjoint modeling</s>
    <s>Direct Decoupled Method (DDM)</s>
    <s>Variable and adaptive grids</s>
    <s>Hybrid modeling approaches</s>
    <s>Coupled meteorology/chemistry modeling</s>
    <s>Downscaling and data assimilation and nudging</s>
    <s>Hemispheric chemistry-transport modeling</s>
    <s>Dust models</s>
    <s>Session 3: Policy and Decision Support</s>
    <s>Air quality models have become indispensable tools in air quality management. This session will focus on research towards science-based policy and applications of models as decision support tools. The session will cover various applications that would inform the decision-making process for air quality improvement. Work that integrates air quality science and modeling with other relevant disciplines such as policy, economics, health, or climate science, and with models used in those disciplines, will be highlighted. Conceptual efforts demonstrating or exploring integrated assessment models and decision support systems will be covered as well. This session topics include:</s>
    <s>Exposure and human health assessment</s>
    <s>Air pollution decision support systems</s>
    <s>Air pollution-agriculture, and -ecological policies</s>
    <s>Decision making under uncertainty and uncertainty analysis</s>
    <s>Air pollution economics</s>
    <s>Design of pollution abatement strategies</s>
    <s>Coordinated air pollution/climate policies</s>
    <s>Session 4: Regulatory Modeling and SIP Applications</s>
    <s>Air quality models continue to be important tools for guiding decision makers in preparing State Implementation Plan (SIP) applications to set standards for compliance. We seek abstracts that describe how air quality models are used in specific applications, with particular emphasis on the types of sensitivity and diagnostic analyses employed and on the model evaluation studies that were conducted for various applications. This session topics include:</s>
    <s>Model intercomparison</s>
    <s>Statistical analyses and evaluation metrics</s>
    <s>Measurement networks</s>
    <s>Impacts on air quality that result from controlling air pollutants</s>
    <s>Session 5: Emissions Inventories, Models, and Processes</s>
    <s>This session is dedicated to the application of innovative methodologies for preparing and processing emissions for air quality modeling applications. Techniques to improve estimates of dust and biogenic emissions are of special interest for this session. This session topics include:</s>
    <s>Updates to inventories and emissions processing</s>
    <s>Emissions from alternative fuel use (e.g., bio-fuels in the transportation sector)</s>
    <s>Emissions from aviation activities</s>
    <s>Projection of emissions to future-year scenarios</s>
    <s>Inverse modeling</s>
    <s>Natural emission sources</s>
    <s>Session 6: Air Quality and Climate Change</s>
    <s>Scientific evidence highlights the role of the atmosphere's chemical constituents in driving climate variability at various scales. Direct radiative forcing due to the presence of certain chemical species of atmospheric aerosols (e.g., sulfate) tends to mitigate warming resulting from greenhouse gases. Short-lived climate forcers, such as sulfate, black carbon, and ozone precursors (including NOx, VOCs, CO), are key players in forming the air quality and climate feedback loops. We seek abstracts that address linkages between regional climate variability and air quality. This session topics include:</s>
    <s>Regional climate impacts on air quality</s>
    <s>Impacts of air pollution on climate change</s>
    <s>Intercontinental transport of pollutants</s>
    <s>The climate impacts of short-lived climate forcers</s>
    <s>The impacts of clouds, as carrying media of pollutants and moisture, on climate</s>
    <s>International applications</s>
    <s>Session 7: Model Evaluation and Analysis</s>
    <s>Evaluation of air quality modeling systems (including meteorological and emissions models) is a key to identify the integrity of such modeling systems for various applications at various spatial and temporal resolutions. Abstracts are invited to present results of model evaluation studies, with emphasis on new techniques for model evaluation. This session topics include:</s>
    <s>Diagnostic tools</s>
    <s>Analyses and comparisons with data from measurement networks</s>
    <s>Model inter-comparisons</s>
    <s>Process evaluation</s>
    <s>Session 8: Air Quality Measurements and Observational Studies</s>
    <s>Papers in this session are devoted to analyzing data from both conventional and remote-sensing observational platforms. In particular, presentations are invited on the integration of data collected from different platforms, and on the use of new satellite data products in air quality modeling. This session topics include:</s>
    <s>Conventional measurement networks</s>
    <s>Field measurement studies</s>
    <s>Satellite data</s>
    <s>Data assimilation techniques</s>
    <s>Session 9: Air Pollution Meteorology</s>
    <s>Meteorological processes are critical to all aspects of air pollution in particular emissions, dispersion and transport, dry and wet deposition, photochemical and chemical reactions, and pollutant concentrations. The accuracy in modeling basic meteorological parameters such as wind speed and direction, and temperature as well as processes such as cloud formation and boundary layer characteristics are fundamental to the accuracy of air quality model simulations. This session topics include:</s>
    <s>Cloud processes</s>
    <s>Boundary layer parameterizations</s>
    <s>Evaluation of meteorological models</s>
    <s>Data assimilation techniques</s>
    <s>Extended Abstracts</s>
    <s>Extended abstracts should be submitted by September 26, 2011. All presenters (Oral and Poster) need to provide an extended abstract. The abstracts should be NO LONGER THAN 6 pages and should be submitted in PDF format. The abstract should include your name, affiliation, e-mail address, fax number, and phone number. Please e-mail your extended abstract to cmas@unc.edu with the subject line &quot;Conference extended abstract&quot; by September 26, 2011. Extended abstracts will not be accepted after November 1, 2011.</s>
    <s>Extended Abstract Template: PDF or MS Word (Remember to convert to PDF before sending!)</s>
    <s>Presenter Information</s>
    <s>For more information about Oral Presentations, please visit our Oral Presentations page.</s>
    <s>For more information on Poster Presentations, plese visit our Poster Session page.</s>
    <s>Conference Info</s>
    <s>COST/PAYMENT INFO</s>
    <s>CALL FOR PAPERS</s>
    <s>ORAL PRESENTATIONS</s>
    <s>POSTER SESSION</s>
    <s>CONFERENCE CENTER</s>
    <s>EXHIBITOR INFO</s>
    <s>VISA INFO</s>
    <s>VISITOR INFO</s>
    <s>Community Modeling and Analysis System (CMAS)</s>
    <s>More information, questions, comments, and concerns should be directed to cmas@unc.edu</s>
    <s>Page Last Modified: 09/02/2011 04:03:46 PM</s>
  </text>
</page>
