<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.edemocracy-conf.org/cfp.asp</url>
  <title>IADIS e-Democracy, Equity and Social Justice 2011: Call for Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Call for Papers. This conference aims to encourage and foster efforts of researchers and practitioners by sharing cutting-edge research, innovations, models </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>call for papers</s>
    <s>topics of interest</s>
    <s>important dates</s>
    <s>conference rates</s>
    <s>hotel info</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>This conference aims to encourage and foster efforts of researchers and practitioners by sharing cutting-edge</s>
    <s>research, innovations, models, theories and strategies that address issues and challenges related to cultivating</s>
    <s>online communities for grassroots democracy, equity and social justice.</s>
    <s>This will include research that addresses social justice and equity through the cultivation of progressive and open</s>
    <s>online communities of interest, which attempt to realize the United Nations Millennium Development Goals. In</s>
    <s>particular, submission of papers the address the following are encouraged:</s>
    <s>Topics for this conference include, but are not limited to:</s>
    <s>Unleashing the power of citizens in developing countries to use the Internet to drive their own social &amp; political development agenda</s>
    <s>Digital divide:</s>
    <s>Achievement of equity by bridging the digital divide and promoting critical and digital literacies</s>
    <s>Provision of effective online platforms for meaningful participation of citizens</s>
    <s>Optimization of wider access to democratic dialogues through successful community cultivation</s>
    <s>Community cultivation</s>
    <s>Enhance the benefits of social development interventions through the use of digital, wireless and mobile</s>
    <s>technologies for cultivating communities to conduct inquiry and socio-political action</s>
    <s>Facilitating sustainable grassroots, bottom up co-created solutions and approaches to leadership, human rights,</s>
    <s>and civil society development</s>
    <s>Reports and reflections on the successes and failures of deploying e-mentoring strategies for raising political</s>
    <s>awareness, civic consciousness and community cultivation</s>
    <s>North-South, South-South, and public-private partnerships and collaboration for co-creation of online communities</s>
    <s>Community Ownership &amp; Strengthening</s>
    <s>Studies of efforts of involving citizens as stakeholders in initiatives to promote democracy, social justice and</s>
    <s>equity by strengthening their capabilities and promoting their involvement in online communities.</s>
    <s>To evaluate and build consensus on the most recent scientific data on online community</s>
    <s>participation/involvement/action for promoting social justice and equity in health and education</s>
    <s>To identify additional research required to maximize the benefits of online community cultivation</s>
    <s>To identify key actions by researchers, policymakers and civil society to collaborate in strengthening human and</s>
    <s>financial investment in capacity-building, resource mobilization and implementation of a robust online community cultivation agenda</s>
    <s>The conference will also foster interdisciplinary collaboration with the other IADIS multi-conferences in developing</s>
    <s>capabilities for online community ecologies for adding value to the discourses and practices of e-democracy, social justice</s>
    <s>and equity using Web 2.0 approaches/paradigm.</s>
    <s>The Conference will be composed of several types of contributions:</s>
    <s>Full Papers These include mainly accomplished research results and have 8 pages at the maximum (5,000 words).</s>
    <s>Short Papers These are mostly composed of work in progress reports or fresh developments and have 4 pages</s>
    <s>at maximum (2,500 words).</s>
    <s>Reflection Papers These might review recent research literature pertaining to a particular problem or</s>
    <s>approach, indicate what the findings suggest, and/or provide a suggestion - with rationale and justification -</s>
    <s>for a different approach or perspective on that problem. Reflection papers might also analyze general trends or</s>
    <s>discuss important issues in topics related to the conference. These have 4 pages at maximum (2,500 words).</s>
    <s>Posters / Demonstrations These contain implementation information or work-in-progress and have two pages</s>
    <s>at maximum (1,250 words) besides the poster itself (or demonstration) that will be exposed at the conference.</s>
    <s>Tutorials Tutorials can be proposed by scholars or company representatives. A proposal of maximum 250</s>
    <s>words is expected.</s>
    <s>Invited Talks These will be made of contributions from well-known scholars and company representatives.</s>
    <s>An abstract will be included in the conference proceedings.</s>
    <s>Panels Discussions on selected topics will be held. A proposal of maximum 250 words is expected.</s>
    <s>Doctoral Consortium - A Doctoral Consortium will discuss in group, individual projects and on going work of</s>
    <s>PhD students. Prospective students should send a report of their PhD projects and work so far with a maximum</s>
    <s>of 4 pages (2,500 words).</s>
    <s>Corporate Showcases &amp; Exhibitions The former enables companies to present recent developments and</s>
    <s>applications, inform a large and qualified audience of your future directions and showcase companys</s>
    <s>noteworthy products and services. There will be a time slot for companies to make their presentation in a room.</s>
    <s>The latter enables companies the opportunity to display its latest offerings of hardware, software, tools, services</s>
    <s>and books, through an exhibit booth. For further details please contact the publicity chair - secretariat@mccsis.org .</s>
    <s>This is a blind peer-reviewed conference.</s>
    <s>Important Dates:</s>
    <s>- Submission deadline (2nd call): 29 April 2011</s>
    <s>- Notification to Authors (2nd call): 30 May 2011</s>
    <s>- Final Camera-Ready Submission and Early Registration (1st call) : Until 25 March 2011</s>
    <s>- Late Registration (1st call): After 25 March 2011</s>
    <s>- Conference: Rome, Italy, 20 to 22 July 2011</s>
  </text>
</page>
