<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.crossroads2012.org/%3Fq%3Den/node/26</url>
  <title>Call for papers | ACS Crossroads 2012 in Paris - July 2-6, 2012</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>2nd call for papers - Updated deadline: November 30th, 2011 that the 9th International Conference Crossroads in Cultural Studies will be held in Paris, France </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Skip to main content</s>
    <s>ACS Crossroads 2012 in Paris - July 2-6, 2012</s>
    <s>Hosting Institutions</s>
    <s>Sorbonne Nouvelle University</s>
    <s>Sorbonne Paris Cité</s>
    <s>Conference Venues</s>
    <s>About the Organizers</s>
    <s>Invited Speakers</s>
    <s>Plenary Sessions</s>
    <s>Paper Submission</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Topic Suggestions</s>
    <s>Submission Guidelines</s>
    <s>Submit a Session</s>
    <s>Submit a Paper</s>
    <s>Conference Fee</s>
    <s>Travel Info</s>
    <s>Practical Informations</s>
    <s>Arrivals &amp; Departures</s>
    <s>Hotels &amp; Accommodations</s>
    <s>About Paris</s>
    <s>You are here</s>
    <s>Home » Paper Submission</s>
    <s>Call for papers</s>
    <s>Crossroads in Cultural Studies 2012</s>
    <s>Hosted by Sorbonne Nouvelle University</s>
    <s>2nd call for papers - Updated deadline: November 30th, 2011</s>
    <s>We are pleased to announce that the 9th International Conference Crossroads in Cultural Studies will be held in Paris, France, from July 2nd to 6th, 2012, hosted by Sorbonne Nouvelle University.</s>
    <s>The conference will also be hosted by UNESCO, the international organization that has always championed cultural diversity and difference. Given the long association between Cultural Studies research and UNESCO, this conference should be an occasion for Cultural Studies to look back on its own evolution as well as explore new scholarly insights. We believe UNESCO will also offer an exceptional platform to discuss important current issues and contribute to the visibility of Cultural Studies in France and Europe.</s>
    <s>10 WORLD-CLASS KEYNOTE AND PLENARY SPEAKERS FROM ALL OVER THE WORLD, ALL CONFIRMED: Sara Ahmed, Marie-Hélène Bourcier, John Erni, Jeremy Gilbert, Achille Mbembe, Walter Mignolo, Bobby Noble, Phaedra Pezzullo, Jacques Rancière and Françoise Vergès. Check the provisional program now!</s>
    <s>STATE OF THE ART CONFERENCE TOPICS. All topics relevant to Cultural Studies, especially new and innovative areas of research are welcome. See a list of possible topic areas.</s>
    <s>SUBMIT YOUR PROPOSAL NOW USING THE ONLINE FORMSThe call for papers and organized panel proposals is now open. Check the submission guidelines and submit a proposal using the online forms - session submission or paper submission - before November 30th, 2011.</s>
    <s>ACS ASSISTANCE SCHEME FOR CROSSROADS 2012.The Association for Cultural Studies will offer a small number of grants to assist participants from ACS under-represented regions with travel accommodation or registration expenses.</s>
    <s>ATTRACTIVE AND CONVENIENT ACCOMMODATION IN THE HEART OF THE CITY OF PARIS AND CLOSE TO THE CONFERENCE VENUES. Cheaper campus accommodation will also be available close at hand at the International Paris University Campus.</s>
    <s>SPREAD THE NEWS! Please forward this message to your colleagues and friendsWe look forward to seeing you in Paris in 2012!</s>
    <s>Since its inception in 1996 in Tampere, Finland, the Crossroads in Cultural Studies Conference has played an important role in the creation of a global discussion about Cultural Studies. It has become a major international conference where scholars from all five continents gather regularly to exchange research, views and insights. Organized by the Association for Cultural Studies (ACS), the Crossroads Conference is held every other year in different parts of the world. Previous conferences have taken place in Birmingham (United Kingdom), Urbana-Champaign (USA), Istanbul (Turkey), Kingston (Jamaica), and Hong Kong (China).</s>
    <s>Search form</s>
    <s>With the support of</s>
    <s>Don't forgetImportant</s>
    <s>Call for papers</s>
    <s>NEW DEADLINE: November 30th, 2011!</s>
    <s>Recent articles</s>
    <s>Presentation of Sorbonne Paris Cité</s>
    <s>Conference Fee</s>
    <s>Connect with us</s>
    <s>! on Facebook</s>
    <s>Legal - Contact - Admin</s>
  </text>
</page>
