<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.iranianstudies.com/conferences/2012/call-for-papers</url>
  <title>Call for Papers | iranianstudies.com</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Call for Papers. The International Society for Iranian Studies (ISIS) The Ninth Biennial Iranian Studies Conference 1-5 August 2012. Istanbul, Turkey </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Primary links</s>
    <s>Sign Up</s>
    <s>ISIS Discussion List</s>
    <s>Journal Archives</s>
    <s>Notation Style</s>
    <s>Formatting and Style</s>
    <s>Tables and Figures</s>
    <s>Transliteration Scheme</s>
    <s>2012 Conference</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Submission Guideline</s>
    <s>2010 Conference</s>
    <s>Conference Program</s>
    <s>Book a Room</s>
    <s>2008 Conference</s>
    <s>2006 Conference</s>
    <s>Film Programme</s>
    <s>Film Synopsis</s>
    <s>Programme Outline</s>
    <s>Programme Sessions</s>
    <s>Programme Speakers</s>
    <s>Special Sessions</s>
    <s>2004 Conference</s>
    <s>Latest Posts</s>
    <s>Blog Archives</s>
    <s>Book Series</s>
    <s>CAIF Advisory Board</s>
    <s>CAIF Committee Members</s>
    <s>Saidi-Sirjani Book Award</s>
    <s>Past Winners</s>
    <s>Ehsan Yarshater Book Award</s>
    <s>Latifeh Yarshater Award</s>
    <s>Lifetime Achievement Award</s>
    <s>Best Dissertation Award</s>
    <s>The Lois Roth Prize</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>The International Society for Iranian Studies (ISIS)</s>
    <s>The Ninth Biennial Iranian Studies Conference</s>
    <s>1-5 August 2012</s>
    <s>Istanbul, Turkey</s>
    <s>In partnership with Iran Heritage Foundation and the co-sponsorship of American Institute for Iranian Studies and the Foundation for Iranian Studies</s>
    <s>Conference Chair: Touraj Atabaki, International Institute of Social History, Amsterdam, Leiden University</s>
    <s>Program Chair: Mansour Bonakdarian, Brooklyn College</s>
    <s>The International Society for Iranian Studies (ISIS) invites proposals for the Ninth Biennial Iranian Studies Conference in all subfields of Iranian studies. ISIS particularly encourages works that are devoted to areas of transnational inquiry and which probe new scholarly approaches to Iranian Studies. ISIS also welcomes submissions on all aspects of the Turko-Iranian history and culture. The primary language of the conference will be English, and scholars are strongly encouraged to use that language, but proposals for papers in Persian will be considered as well.</s>
    <s>The submission deadline for proposals has been extended to May 20, 2011. Paper proposals must be limited to 300 words and must present succinct scholarly outlines of the central themes and main arguments of the presentations. Prearranged panels are strongly encouraged. Ordinarily four papers are presented at each panel. Scholars wishing to submit a proposal for a pre-arranged panel should complete the panel registration form. The completed paper and panel proposal forms must be posted electronically at the ISIS website. The forms for both paper and panel proposals can be accessed on the ISIS website (for instructions on how to submit, please visit here).</s>
    <s>Membership and preregistration are a required component of the proposal process. All conference presenters must be members of ISIS and preregister for the conference. To become a member of ISIS please click here.</s>
    <s>For further information please contact 2012program@iranianstudies.com.</s>
    <s>2012 Conference</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Submission Guideline</s>
    <s>Username: *</s>
    <s>Password: *</s>
    <s>Forgot Your Password?</s>
    <s>Home | About | Membership | Journal | Conferences | Privacy Policy | Terms and Conditions | Refund Policy</s>
    <s>Instructions for Authors</s>
  </text>
</page>
