<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.hiceducation.org/cfp_edu.htm</url>
  <title>Call for Papers - Hawaii International Conference on Education</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Hawaii International Conference on Education - Call for Papers.</s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>!Description: Description: Description: Description: C:\Users\Marketing\Desktop\Websites\Education Website\EDUpicture1.jpg</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Information for Authors</s>
    <s>Exhibitors/ Advertising</s>
    <s>Travel and Tours</s>
    <s>Co-Sponsored by:</s>
    <s>Pepperdine University - Graduate School of Education and Psychology</s>
    <s>University of Louisville - Center for Sustainable Urban Neighborhoods</s>
    <s>New Horizons in Education - The Journal of Education, Hong Kong Teachers' Association</s>
    <s>California State University, East Bay - Educational Leadership Program</s>
    <s>Organized By:</s>
    <s>Hawaii International Conferences</s>
    <s>For more information,</s>
    <s>please contact:</s>
    <s>Joelle Lee, Conference Coordinator</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Submission/Proposal Deadline: August 12th, 2011</s>
    <s>Submission/Proposal Deadline Extended to:</s>
    <s>September 9th, 2011</s>
    <s>Topic Areas (All Areas of Education are Invited)</s>
    <s>Academic Advising and Counseling</s>
    <s>Art Education</s>
    <s>Adult Education</s>
    <s>Business Education</s>
    <s>Counselor Education</s>
    <s>Curriculum, Research and Development</s>
    <s>Distance Education</s>
    <s>Early Childhood Education</s>
    <s>Educational Administration</s>
    <s>Educational Foundations</s>
    <s>Educational Measurement and Evaluation</s>
    <s>Educational Psychology</s>
    <s>Educational Technology</s>
    <s>Education Policy and Leadership</s>
    <s>Elementary Education</s>
    <s>Health Education</s>
    <s>Higher Education</s>
    <s>Human Resource Development</s>
    <s>Indigenous Education</s>
    <s>Kinesiology &amp; Leisure Science</s>
    <s>Language Education</s>
    <s>Mathematics Education</s>
    <s>Music Education</s>
    <s>Reading Education</s>
    <s>Rural Education</s>
    <s>Science Education</s>
    <s>Secondary Education</s>
    <s>Social Studies Education</s>
    <s>Special Education</s>
    <s>Student Affairs</s>
    <s>Teacher Education</s>
    <s>Cross-disciplinary areas of Education</s>
    <s>Other Areas of Education</s>
    <s>Call for Papers, Reports, Abstracts, and Studies:</s>
    <s>The Hawaii International Conference on Education encourages the following types of submissions:</s>
    <s>Research Papers</s>
    <s>Completed research papers in any of the topic areas listed above or related areas.</s>
    <s>Abstracts of completed or proposed research in any of the topic areas listed above, or related areas. The abstract for proposed research should include the research objectives, proposed methodology, and a discussion of expected outcomes.</s>
    <s>Student Papers</s>
    <s>Research done by students in any of the topic areas listed above, or related areas.</s>
    <s>Case Studies</s>
    <s>Case studies in any of the topic areas listed above, or related areas.</s>
    <s>Work-in-Progress Reports or Proposals for Future Research</s>
    <s>Incomplete research or ideas for future research in order to generate discussion and feedback in any of the topic areas listed above, or related areas.</s>
    <s>Reports on Issues Related to Teaching</s>
    <s>Reports related to innovative instruction techniques or research related to teaching in any of the topic areas listed above or related areas.</s>
    <s>Format of Presentations:</s>
    <s>Paper sessions will consist of three to four presentations in a 90 minute session. The session will be divided equally between the presenters.</s>
    <s>Workshop presentations will be given a full 90 minute session.</s>
    <s>Panel sessions will provide an opportunity for three or more presenters to speak in a more open and conversational setting with conference attendees. Submissions for these 90 minute sessions should include the name, department, affiliation, and email address of each panelist in addition to a description of the presentation and the title page.</s>
    <s>Poster sessions will last 90 minutes and consist of a large number of presenters. Poster sessions allow attendees to speak with the presenters on a one-to-one basis. The following supplies will be provided:</s>
    <s>Tri-fold display board (48 x 36 inches)</s>
    <s>Push pins</s>
    <s>Round table</s>
    <s>Submitting a Proposal/Paper:</s>
    <s>Make your submission now</s>
    <s>following these two easy steps:</s>
    <s>1. Create a detailed title page for your submission. The title page must include:</s>
    <s>a. title of the submission (be sure to use proper capitalization)</s>
    <s>b. topic area of the submission (choose a topic area from the list at the top of this page)</s>
    <s>c. presentation format (choose one: Paper Session, Workshop, Panel Session, or Poster Session)</s>
    <s>d. paper author(s):</s>
    <s>For EACH author, list the following:</s>
    <s>Full Name</s>
    <s>Email Address (all acceptance/rejection letters are sent via email, so it is very important to have a correct email address for each author!)</s>
    <s>2. Email your abstract and/or paper, along with the above described title page, to education@hiceducation.org Receipt of submissions will be acknowledged via email within 48 hours. There is a limit of two contributed submissions per lead author.</s>
  </text>
</page>
