<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.hsuniversityprograms.org/default/index.cfm/news-and-announcements/2011-cbd-st-conference-call-for-papers-and-sessions/</url>
  <title>2011 CBD S&amp;T Conference Call for Papers and Sessions - Default</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>2011 CBD S&amp;T Conference Call for Papers and Sessions: 2011 Chemical and Biological Defense S&amp;T Conference Call for Papers and Sessions The 2011 </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>SKIP TO MAIN</s>
    <s>Homeland Security University ProgramsTODAYS RESEARCH &amp; EDUCATION, TOMORROW'S SECURITY</s>
    <s>Centers of Excellence</s>
    <s>Funding Opportunities</s>
    <s>Research Database</s>
    <s>Portal Login</s>
    <s>» University Programs News and Announcements</s>
    <s>» 2011 CBD S&amp;T Conference Call for Papers and Sessions</s>
    <s>2011 Chemical and Biological Defense S&amp;T Conference Call for Papers and Sessions</s>
    <s>The 2011 Chemical and Biological Defense Science and Technology (CBD S&amp;T) Conference will consist largely of platform and poster presentations that will be awarded based on the quality and content of the abstracts submitted to the Conference. For the first time, the Conference is welcoming interested parties to submit proposals to host a contributed session. The Conference is particularly interested in any relevant innovations or developments that have not yet been introduced to the defense community.</s>
    <s>The Conference welcomes abstract submissions in the following scientific areas:</s>
    <s>- Leveraging Innovative Computational Methods for Predicting CBRN Effects</s>
    <s>- Understanding Human Reactions to CB Events</s>
    <s>- Disease Prediction, Outbreak Characterization and Impact Modeling</s>
    <s>- Virtual World Development and Use for Representation of CBRN Threats</s>
    <s>- CB Sensing and Molecular Recognition</s>
    <s>- Host Response: Provide Molecular and Cellular Understanding of Host-Agent Interactions</s>
    <s>- Agent Characterization: Characterize and Forecast Current and Emerging Threats</s>
    <s>- Bio-inspired functional materials - biomimetics and beyond</s>
    <s>- Material Design and Synthesis: Develop Novel Materials for CB Protection and Threat Mitigation</s>
    <s>- Investigations in Rapid Response and Recovery and Technology Transition</s>
    <s>- Threat Activity Sensing and Reporting</s>
    <s>- Hazard Mitigation and Contamination Control</s>
    <s>- Human Performance in a CBRN Environment</s>
    <s>- Novel Vaccine Technologies</s>
    <s>- Therapeutics</s>
    <s>- Medical Countermeasures for Chemical Weapon and Radiation Exposure</s>
    <s>- Advances in Regulatory Sciences: Flexible and Agile Biomanufacturing</s>
    <s>- Advances in Regulatory Sciences: Rapid Enhanced Development and Evaluation</s>
    <s>- Novel Next Generation System Platform Technologies</s>
    <s>- Bioinformatics: Creation of a Knowledge Management System to Support Biomarker Discovery</s>
    <s>- Pathogen ID and Characterization</s>
    <s>- Host Biomarker Discovery</s>
    <s>- Biosurveillance in Reservoir Hosts and Vectors</s>
    <s>Proposals for contributed sessions are sought in all areas of Chemical and Biological Defense, including, but not limited to:</s>
    <s>- Nanotechnology</s>
    <s>- Life Science Technologies</s>
    <s>- Omics</s>
    <s>- Novel Threat and Disruptive Chemical and Biological Discovery</s>
    <s>- Dynamic Functional Materials</s>
    <s>- Applied Mathematics and Innovative Computational Tools</s>
    <s>- Flexible Design, Synthesis and Manufacturing</s>
    <s>- Systems Biology and Engineering</s>
    <s>- Disease Surveillance, Threat Detection and Point of Need Diagnostics</s>
    <s>- Adaptive Medical Countermeasures and Technologies</s>
    <s>- Rapid Response and Restoration Science and Technology</s>
    <s>- Threat Activity Sensing and Reporting</s>
    <s>The deadline for submitting abstracts and proposals is 1700 EDT on 24 June 2011.</s>
    <s>CBRNIAC is distributing this announcement at the request of the organizers. Please contact cbdstconf11@sainc.com with any questions.</s>
    <s>NEWS &amp; EVENTS</s>
    <s>START Is Seeking Executive Director and Director of Administrative Services</s>
    <s>LEARN MORE</s>
    <s>COE Explorer Tool Available for Use</s>
    <s>LEARN MORE</s>
    <s>Proceedings Published for 2011 DHS S&amp;T University Summit</s>
    <s>LEARN MORE</s>
    <s>2011 Technologies for Critical Incident Preparedness Conference &amp; Expo</s>
    <s>LEARN MORE</s>
    <s>PROJECT UPDATES</s>
    <s>Y6 IAS 7-1f- Analysis of Decisions, Options, and Risks: Develop and organize relevant databases as inputs for the DSS</s>
    <s>- Updated : Sep 14, 2011</s>
    <s>Y6 EOS- Establish Extension Specie Specific Educational Resource Teams (SSERTs) for foreign animal and zoonotic disease defense at 1890 Cooperative Extension Programs</s>
    <s>- Updated : Sep 2, 2011</s>
    <s>Y6 EOS 11-5- Develop youth education and job-training with public health and regulatory emphases of zoonotic and exotic diseases</s>
    <s>- Updated : Sep 2, 2011</s>
    <s>Y6 EOS 11-4- Develop Hispanic educational curriculum and workshops targeted at agricultural workers providing animal health care on a routine basis</s>
    <s>- Updated : Sep 2, 2011</s>
    <s>Y6 EOS 10-4- Develop a web-based national curriculum for train-the-trainers in FAZDs</s>
    <s>- Updated : Sep 2, 2011</s>
    <s>NEWS ARCHIVE</s>
    <s>&quot;Operating in the Arctic: Supporting the Coast Guard through Research&quot; Funding Opportunity now CLOSED.</s>
    <s>FULL ARCHIVE</s>
    <s>SUMMIT 2011</s>
    <s>LEARN MORE</s>
    <s>RELATED TERMS</s>
    <s>STATES BIRDS OUTBREAKS PATHOGEN DIAGNOSTIC HUMAN DEVELOP OBJECTIVE APPLY RAPID VIRUSES IMPORTANT MOUTH MODELS DISEASE METHODS FEVER RESISTANCE UNITED SECOND MARKETS GENES LABORATORY SPECIFIC THESE ANALYSIS VALLEY FACTORS SPECIES</s>
    <s>Copyright (C) (C)2011 Homeland Security University Programs All rights reserved.</s>
    <s>BACK TO TOP</s>
  </text>
</page>
