<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.aom-iaom.org/conferences.html</url>
  <title>AoM-IAoM Conference Call for Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>The AoM/IAoM 27th Annual Conference is pleased to announce a special offering for Deans/ Department/Division chairpersons to submit proposals for papers, </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>!OUR MISSION</s>
    <s>AoM/IAoM is a professional organization of scholars and practitioners responsible for providing annual conferences, worldwide meetings , curricula and executive programs, speakers, and an active portfolio of professional publications in Management, Education, Leadership, and Technology.</s>
    <s>About AoM/IAoM</s>
    <s>New Books</s>
    <s>Featured Articles</s>
    <s>Leadership/Dev. Plans</s>
    <s>Dissertation Coaching</s>
    <s>Contact Us</s>
    <s>The AoM/IAoM is soliciting submissions for its 2010 conference</s>
    <s>in three specific categories:</s>
    <s>(I) Individuals, (2)Deans/Department Chairs, for individual or departmental (Group) submissions, and (3) Management Practitioners, either individual or organizational (Group) submissions.</s>
    <s>Click Here for Dates &amp; Fees</s>
    <s>INDIVIDUALS (back to top)</s>
    <s>(The guidelines for submissions are described in the sections below.)</s>
    <s>This year, the AoM/IAoM 27th Annual Conference, in response to the economic crisis that has resulted in institutional cutbacks, offers individual and group submissions for a variety of presentation formats to meet cost effectiveness for delegates and maximize organizational participation.</s>
    <s>All submissions will be published in the annual AoM/IAoM Proceedings. Certificate awards will be provided for best paper category, platform presentations and attendance.</s>
    <s>DEANS/DEPARTMENT HEADS/CHAIRPERSONS (back to top)</s>
    <s>(The guidelines for submissions are described in the sections below.)</s>
    <s>The AoM/IAoM 27th Annual Conference is pleased to announce a special offering for Deans/ Department/Division chairpersons to submit proposals for papers, panels, and symposia in groups of two or more individuals on their faculty. We welcome a variety of topics in the general realm of management including, but not limited to, human resource management, organizational behavior, and information technology. The invited groups originating from academic departments and divisions, under the leadership of deans and chairs, do not have to address interrelated topics but will be placed in the conference program thematically. All papers submitted will undergo the regular peer review process.</s>
    <s>All submissions will be published in the annual AoM/IAoM Proceedings. Certificate awards will be provided for best paper category, platform presentations and attendance.</s>
    <s>PRACTITIONERS (back to top)</s>
    <s>(The guidelines for submissions are described in the sections below.)</s>
    <s>The AoM/IAoM 27th Annual Conference is inviting CEOs, executives and managers at all levels, to submit abstracts or proposals for practitioner papers, panels, symposia, case studies, innovations, benchmarks, and demonstration projects. We welcome a variety of topics that fall into the general realm of management including, but not limited to, human resource management, organizational behavior, information technology, corporate education, and leadership.</s>
    <s>All submissions will be published in the annual AoM/IAoM Proceedings. Certificate awards will be provided for best paper category, platform presentations and attendance.</s>
    <s>GENERAL CONFERENCE OVERVIEW (back to top)</s>
    <s>Visions of what is ahead coupled with high levels of uncertainty and ambiguity, rapid economic, political, social, technological and organizational changes are demanding new leadership and management which are passionately discussed and debated around the globe. The increasing value and extraordinary leverage knowledge offers concerns leaders in both private and public sectors worldwide. In the global economy of today, it is not just knowledge that counts more than anything else. It is the continued acquisition andexpansion of knowledge and the honing of skills in the domains of management, higher education, leadership, and technology and their interdependencies and interrelationships that are very much sought after. In today's competitive and fast-paced global environment, education is at a premium because of the high value creation potential knowledge workers bring to organizations. The real assets in this economy are ideas, innovative and creative products and services which enhance the organization's competitive advantage in the global marketplace.</s>
    <s>SUBMISSION GUIDELINES (back to top)</s>
    <s>Below is a set of guidelines and formatting instructions to help you prepare your paper. Please read them carefully prior to submitting.</s>
    <s>Each paper can only be submitted to ONE MELT domain.</s>
    <s>Submitted papers must NOT have been previously presented, published, accepted for publication, and if under review, must NOT appear in print before the conference</s>
    <s>To facilitate the blind review process, remove ALL authors identifying information, including acknowledgements, from the text. (Any submissions with author information will be automatically DELETED).</s>
    <s>The entire paper (title page, abstract, main text, figures, tables, references, etc.) must be in ONE document created in PDF format.</s>
    <s>The maximum length of the paper is 5000 words (including ALL tables, appendices and references). The paper format should follow the Academy of Management Journal's Style Guide.</s>
    <s>Use Times New Roman 12-pitch font, double spaced, and 1-inch (2.5 cm) margin all around.</s>
    <s>Number all of the pages of the paper.</s>
    <s>NO changes in the paper title, abstract, authorship, and actual paper can be made AFTER the submission deadline.</s>
    <s>Check that the paper prints correctly (i.e. all imported figures and tables are there), and ensure that the file is virus-free.</s>
    <s>Once you are sure your submission meets our requirements and guidelines, you may</s>
    <s>ACCEPTANCE, REVIEW AND PUBLICATION PROCESS (back to top)</s>
    <s>All accepted submissions will be published in the Annual Conference Proceedings which are organized into several volume issues. Authors of accepted submissions who have registered for the conference receive a copy of the proceedings in which their paper is published. Attendees without papers select a proceedings of their choice. Selection must be made at the time of registration Exceptional papers, after revisions, can be submitted for publication consideration in the AoM/IAoM journals. Ample opportunities exist at the conference to discuss revisions and extensions of papers presented at the conference and published in the conference proceedings for journal publication with journal representatives. The revised paper must clearly warrant a new publication separate from the paper published in the conference proceedings.</s>
    <s>All submissions undergo a blind review process. The title page should include the following: title of the submission, author(s) contact information with mailing (postal) address, e-mail address, and phone numbers. Identifying information should only appear on the title page; the author's name should not appear on the abstract or the remaining pages of the submission.</s>
    <s>If you are interested in participating as a Session Chair, Discussant or Reviewer of Papers, please complete the following application.</s>
    <s>Online Participation Application</s>
    <s>Print-Version Submission Form</s>
    <s>You may either submit online or print the form and fax it to:</s>
    <s>Fax : (757) 482-0325</s>
    <s>E-mail: aomgt@inter-source.org</s>
    <s>Attention: Conference administration</s>
    <s>(back to top)</s>
    <s>At least one author must be a registered presenter. If more than one author attends the conference, each must register and pay the fee. Fees are due with the submission of the final paper together with the conference registration fee no later than the date indicated in the schedule.</s>
    <s>By submitting a paper, the author(s) agree, if their paper is accepted, to submit the final paper in a timely fashion. All conference participants, including presenters and attendees, must register for the conference and pay the appropriate registration fee. This rule applies to presenters of all session formats, discussants, plenary leaders, workshop leaders, panelists, and symposium participants. Paper and proposal acceptance is contingent upon presenters paying the conference registration fee. Please note that no presentations will be programmed and no papers will be published unless the registration fee has been received and verified.</s>
    <s>Individual presenters are limited to two separate submissions: one (1) competitive paper and one (1) other type of a noncompetitive presentation such as a workshop or symposium. Only two (2) submissions per author will be accepted and scheduled for presentation. Duplicate submissions tendered to more than one (1) domain will be eliminated.</s>
    <s>(back to top)</s>
    <s>Support the conference by staying at the AoM/IAoM Conference Center Hotel. Especially favorable rates have been negotiated based on occupancy projection to provide you with professional and personal amenities.</s>
    <s>RULES OF PARTICIPATION (back to top)</s>
    <s>The AoM/IAoM organization is specified in Article IX of the constitution (adopted July 1, 1983 and last revised August 2001). At least one author must be a registered presenter. If more than one author attends the conference, each must register and pay the fee. Fees are due with the submission of the final presentation proposal together with the conference registration fee no later than the date indicated in the schedule.</s>
    <s>By submitting a presentation proposal, the author(s) agree to submit the final version of the presentation in a timely fashion. All conference participants, including presenters and attendees, must register for the conference and pay the appropriate registration fee. This rule applies to presenters of all session formats, discussants, plenary leaders, workshop leaders, panelists, and symposium participants. Proposal acceptance is contingent upon presenters paying the conference registration fee. Please note that no presentations will be programmed unless the registration fee has been received and verified.</s>
    <s>(back to top)</s>
    <s>ADMINISTRATION (back to top)</s>
    <s>Language: English is the conference language.</s>
    <s>Submissions: To submit a paper, proposal, etc. for the conference, participants must first fill out the Conference Submission Form and the AoM/IAoM Membership form.</s>
    <s>Submissions are accepted electronically (see above links)</s>
    <s>If you are interested in serving as a reviewer or session chair, contact AoM/IAoM headquarters at aomgt@inter-source.org or call (757) 482-2273. Conference reviewers will be sent 2-3 papers for review in their areas of expertise and interest.</s>
    <s>AUDIO-VISUAL PRESENTATIONS (back to top)</s>
    <s>Presenters are responsible for supplying the equipment needed for the delivery of their presentations. Each breakout room will be equipped with the standard audio-visual setup, which will support electronic presentations.</s>
    <s>The standard package is: XGA LCD Projector (1024 x 768 resolution), Projector Stand, 7-8' Tripod Screen, Power Cord, VGA Switcher, and Microphone</s>
    <s>NOTE: Presenters are required to bring their own Laptops!</s>
    <s>PROCEEDINGS (back to top)</s>
    <s>The Conference Proceedings are part of the conference package distributed on site. Registered 'no shows' must arrange for pick-up of their proceedings at the conference since unclaimed copies are made available to interested delegates at the meeting. No unclaimed Proceedings are returned to headquarters after the conference.</s>
    <s>SUBMISSIONS CHECKLIST (back to top)</s>
    <s>Before submitting your paper or proposal electronically use the submission checklist below to ensure that all necessary elements are included.</s>
    <s>Conference Submission Form</s>
    <s>Conference registration form and fees</s>
    <s>Membership application and dues</s>
    <s>PAYMENT DETAILS (back to top)</s>
    <s>Payment may be made on-line with credit card or AoM/IAoM will accept payment in the following categories:</s>
    <s>Institutional Check</s>
    <s>Money Order</s>
    <s>Payment can be sent to:</s>
    <s>Surface Mail</s>
    <s>AoM/IAoM Headquarters</s>
    <s>P.O. Box 64841</s>
    <s>Virginia Beach, VA 23467-4841</s>
    <s>Express Mail</s>
    <s>AoM/IAoM Administrative Offices</s>
    <s>c/o Maximilian Press Publishing Company</s>
    <s>920 S. Battlefield Blvd., Suite 100</s>
    <s>Chesapeake, VA 23322</s>
    <s>FINAL REMINDER (back to top)</s>
    <s>Final papers must be accompanied by conference registration and affiliate fees. Late and on-site registration fees apply after the deadline dates. The registration fees that apply to the deadlines are specified in the table on the conference page.</s>
    <s>The AoM/IAoM regards a submission to the annual conference as a commitment from at least one author to register for the conference and present the accepted submission. Failure to do this is regarded as a breach of professional ethics. Purchase orders will not be accepted in lieu of fees. The AoM/IAoM sincerely regrets that it is not able to provide support to offset the costs of registration and travel for individuals with limited funding.</s>
    <s>(back to top)</s>
    <s>Abstracts and/or Competitive Submissions - May 1, 2010</s>
    <s>Review Process and Acceptance Notice - May 31, 2010</s>
    <s>Final Corrected Submission Notice - June 15, 2010</s>
    <s>Conference Fees due - June 30, 2010</s>
    <s>Conference Dates: July 28 - July 31</s>
    <s>$350.00 regular conference fee</s>
    <s>$175.00 - A submitting conference delegate may invite a colleague at an additional half the regular fee ; each may present and each may bring any number of doctoral students with them who may also present.</s>
    <s>$60.00 - Doctoral student fee.</s>
    <s>For larger group discounts, please contact us at: conferences@aom-iaom.org</s>
    <s>(back to top)</s>
    <s>(C) Copyright 2007 AoM/IAoM All Rights Reserved.</s>
    <s>P.O. Box 64841, Virginia Beach, VA 23467-4841</s>
    <s>Website designed by deevinemissm.com</s>
  </text>
</page>
