<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.renewableenergyworld.com/rea/partner/photovoltaics-world/news/article/2010/07/call-for-papers-for-2011-photovoltaics-world-conference</url>
  <title>Call for Papers for 2011 Photovoltaics World Conference ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Jul 1, 2010 Make your voice heard! We are now accepting abstract submittals for the 2011 Photovoltaics World Conference program. Submit your abstracts </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Sign-In or Create a Free Account</s>
    <s>World's 1 Renewable Energy Network for News &amp; Information</s>
    <s>Recent Activity About Blog Press Releases Calendar Products Feeds Contact</s>
    <s>Call for Papers for 2011 Photovoltaics World Conference</s>
    <s>By Pete Singer, Photovoltaics World | 2010-07-01 00:00:00.0</s>
    <s>Do you like this press release?</s>
    <s>Email PrintFeedShare</s>
    <s>Tweet Share</s>
    <s>Make your voice heardWe are now accepting abstract submittals for the 2011 Photovoltaics World Conference program. Submit your abstracts on-line by August 6, 2010 using our on-line submission form at www.pvworldevent.com. Abstracts should be 200-400 words in length and address all key points of the issue/project/technology to be covered in your presentation. The event will be held March 8-11, 2011 in Tampa, Florida, at the Tampa Convention Center.</s>
    <s>Make your voice heardWe are now accepting abstract submittals for the 2011 Photovoltaics World Conference program. Submit your abstracts on-line by August 6, 2010 using our on-line submission form at www.pvworldevent.com. Abstracts should be 200-400 words in length and address all key points of the issue/project/technology to be covered in your presentation. The event will be held March 8-11, 2011 in Tampa, Florida, at the Tampa Convention Center.</s>
    <s>Co-located with Renewable Energy World Conference &amp; Expo, Photovoltaics World Conference 2011 will provide a forum dedicated to the manufacture, distribution and implementation of solar power produced by photovoltaic solar cells.</s>
    <s>Estimates vary, but the installed capacity of PV systems is expected to grow some 68% in 2010, reaching 8.6 GW globally. However, cost reductions will be required in an effort to keep up with the price declines and to address shrinking profit margins. While technology advances continue to result in record-breaking cell efficiencies, more needs to be done to keep manufacturing costs low.</s>
    <s>A program of two technical tracks will showcase the latest advances in solar cell design and manufacturing, including crystalline silicon, thin film and concentrated PV. We'll also be covering the other elements that are involved in the generation and distribution of solar power. This includes the &quot;balance of system&quot; components (i.e., wiring, inverters and brackets) that can make up half the cost of a PV installation, as well as PV system installation. Issues related to the technology selected for utility-scale solar installations versus that for residential roof-tops and smaller scale installations will also be covered.</s>
    <s>I'm presently assembling a program committee that will be responsible for reviewing submitted abstracts and suggesting additional speakers. If you're interested, please contact me directly at psinger@pennwell.com or at 603-891-9217.</s>
    <s>Photovoltaics World Conference 2011 is your opportunity to keep yourself up to date on the technology and market, present your results to the community and network with colleagues. I hope you can join us!</s>
    <s>Pete Singer</s>
    <s>Additional Information</s>
    <s>Visit the Photovoltaics World Website</s>
    <s>The information on this page was created and posted by the company identified above. RenewableEnergyWorld.com does not endorse, edit, or substantiate this information and assumes no obligation for this content's accuracy.</s>
    <s>Photovoltaics World</s>
    <s>Add to my network</s>
    <s>About: Photovoltaics World, the newest member of PennWell’s Electronics Group, covers photovoltaics manufacturing and solar power generation. more »</s>
    <s>Recent Press Release</s>
    <s>Free Webcast: Solar PV Materials Advances Enable Better Solar Panels</s>
    <s>Blog from Intersolar North America</s>
    <s>Growing Your Business? Learn More about Total Access Featured Total Access Partners</s>
    <s>World's 1 Renewable Energy Network</s>
    <s>Home | About Us | Contact Us | Advertising &amp; Services | Privacy Policy | Terms &amp; Conditions | Sitemap</s>
    <s>News | Blogs | Finance | Video | Products | Companies | Events | Jobs | Magazines | Conference &amp; Expo</s>
    <s>Renewable Energy | Solar Energy | Wind Energy | Geothermal Energy | Bioenergy | Hydropower | Hydrogen &amp; Fuel Cells</s>
    <s>(C) Copyright 1999-2011 RenewableEnergyWorld.com - All rights reserved.</s>
    <s>RenewableEnergyWorld.com - World's 1 Renewable Energy Network for News &amp; Information</s>
    <s>Twitter Facebook Linked In RSS Feeds e-Newsletters</s>
  </text>
</page>
