<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.esociety-conf.org/cfp.asp</url>
  <title>IADIS e-Society 2012: Call for Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Call for Papers. The IADIS e-Society 2012 conference aims to address the main issues of concern within the Information Society. This conference covers both </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>call for papers</s>
    <s>topics of interest</s>
    <s>important dates</s>
    <s>hotel info</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>The IADIS e-Society 2012 conference aims to address the main issues of concern within the Information Society.</s>
    <s>This conference covers both the technical as well as the non-technical aspects of the Information Society. Broad areas of interest are eSociety and Digital Divide, eBusiness / eCommerce, eLearning, New Media and E-Society, Digital Services in ESociety, eGovernment / eGovernance, eHealth, Information Systems, and Information Management. These broad areas are divided into more detailed areas (see below). However innovative contributes that don't fit into these areas will also be considered since they might be of benefit to conference attendees.</s>
    <s>Topics related to e-Society are of interest. These include best practice, case studies, strategies and tendencies in the following areas:</s>
    <s>eSociety and Digital Divide</s>
    <s>Connectivity may imply social coherence and integration. The opposite may result as well, when systematic measures are taken to exclude certain individuals or certain groups. Papers are welcomed on the next keywords:</s>
    <s>- Social Integration</s>
    <s>- Social Bookmarking</s>
    <s>- Social Software</s>
    <s>- E-Democracy</s>
    <s>eBusiness / eCommerce</s>
    <s>May include issues relating to:</s>
    <s>- Business Ontologies and Models</s>
    <s>- Digital Goods and Services</s>
    <s>- eBusiness Models</s>
    <s>- eCommerce Application Fields</s>
    <s>- eCommerce Economics</s>
    <s>- eCommerce Services</s>
    <s>- Electronic Service Delivery</s>
    <s>- eMarketing</s>
    <s>- Languages for Describing Goods and Services</s>
    <s>- Online Auctions and Technologies</s>
    <s>- Virtual Organisations and Teleworking</s>
    <s>May include issues relating to:</s>
    <s>- Collaborative Learning</s>
    <s>- Curriculum Content Design &amp; Development</s>
    <s>- Delivery Systems and Environments</s>
    <s>- Educational Systems Design</s>
    <s>- E-Citizenship and Inclusion</s>
    <s>- eLearning Organisational Issues</s>
    <s>- Evaluation and Assessment</s>
    <s>- Political and Social Aspects</s>
    <s>- Virtual Learning Environments and Issues</s>
    <s>- Web-based Learning Communities</s>
    <s>New Media and E-Society</s>
    <s>- Digitization, heterogeneity and convergence</s>
    <s>- Interactivity and virtuality</s>
    <s>- Citizenship, regulation and heterarchy</s>
    <s>- Innovation, identity and the global village syndrome</s>
    <s>- Internet Cultures and new interpretations of Space</s>
    <s>- Polity and the Digitally Suppressed</s>
    <s>Digital Services in ESociety</s>
    <s>- Service Broadcasting</s>
    <s>- Political Reporting</s>
    <s>- Development of Digital Services</s>
    <s>- Freedom of Expression</s>
    <s>- E-Journalism</s>
    <s>- Open Access</s>
    <s>eGovernment /eGovernance</s>
    <s>May include issues relating to:</s>
    <s>- Accessibility</s>
    <s>- Democracy and the Citizen</s>
    <s>- Digital Economies</s>
    <s>- Digital Regions</s>
    <s>- eAdministration</s>
    <s>- eGovernment Management</s>
    <s>- eProcurement</s>
    <s>- Global Trends</s>
    <s>- National and International Economies</s>
    <s>- Social Inclusion</s>
    <s>May include issues relating to:</s>
    <s>- Data Security Issues</s>
    <s>- eHealth Policy and Practice</s>
    <s>- eHealthcare Strategies and Provision</s>
    <s>- Legal Issues</s>
    <s>- Medical Research Ethics</s>
    <s>- Patient Privacy and Confidentiality</s>
    <s>Information Systems</s>
    <s>May include issues relating to:</s>
    <s>- Electronic Data Interchange (EDI)</s>
    <s>- Intelligent Agents</s>
    <s>- Intelligent Systems</s>
    <s>- IS Security Issues</s>
    <s>- Mobile Applications</s>
    <s>- Multimedia Applications</s>
    <s>- Payment Systems</s>
    <s>- Protocols and Standards</s>
    <s>- Software Requirements and IS Architectures</s>
    <s>- Storage Issues</s>
    <s>- Strategies and Tendencies</s>
    <s>- System Architectures</s>
    <s>- Telework Technologies</s>
    <s>- Ubiquitous Computing</s>
    <s>- Virtual Reality</s>
    <s>- Wireless Communications</s>
    <s>Information Management</s>
    <s>May include issues relating to:</s>
    <s>- Computer-Mediated Communication</s>
    <s>- Content Development</s>
    <s>- Cyber law and Intellectual Property</s>
    <s>- Data Mining</s>
    <s>- ePublishing and Digital Libraries</s>
    <s>- Human Computer Interaction</s>
    <s>- Information Search and Retrieval</s>
    <s>- Knowledge Management</s>
    <s>- Policy Issues</s>
    <s>- Privacy Issues</s>
    <s>- Social and Organizational Aspects</s>
    <s>- Virtual Communities</s>
    <s>- XML and Other Extensible Languages</s>
    <s>The Conference will be composed of several types of contributions:</s>
    <s>Full Papers These include mainly accomplished research results and have 8 pages at the maximum (5,000 words).</s>
    <s>Short Papers These are mostly composed of work in progress reports or fresh developments and have 4 pages at maximum (2,500 words).</s>
    <s>Reflection Papers These might review recent research literature pertaining to a particular problem or approach, indicate what the findings suggest, and/or provide a suggestion - with rationale and justification - for a different approach or perspective on that problem. Reflection papers might also analyze general trends or discuss important issues in topics related to e-Society. These have 4 pages at maximum (2,500 words).</s>
    <s>Posters / Demonstrations These have one page at the maximum (625 words) besides the poster itself (or demonstration) that will be exposed at the conference.</s>
    <s>Tutorials Tutorials can be proposed by scholars or company representatives. A proposal of maximum 250 words is expected.</s>
    <s>Panels Discussions on selected topics will be held. A proposal of maximum 250 words is expected.</s>
    <s>Invited Talks These will be made of contributions from well-known scholars and company representatives. An abstract will be included in the conference proceedings.</s>
    <s>Doctoral Consortium - The Doctoral Consortium will discuss on going work of PhD students in an informal and formative atmosphere. Contributions to the consortium should take the form of either:</s>
    <s>a critical literature review of the research topic providing the rationale for the relevance and interest of the research topic; or</s>
    <s>a short paper discussing the research question(s), research objectives, research methodology and work done so far.</s>
    <s>Doctoral Consortium Contributions should have a maximum 2,500 words (4 pages).</s>
    <s>Corporate Showcases &amp; Exhibitions The former enables companies to present recent developments and applications, inform a large and qualified audience of your future directions and showcase companys noteworthy products and services. There will be a time slot for companies to make their presentation in a room. The latter enables companies the opportunity to display its latest offerings of hardware, software, tools, services and books, through an exhibit booth. For further details please contact the publicity chair - secretariat@esociety-conf.org</s>
    <s>This is a blind peer-reviewed conference.</s>
    <s>Important Dates</s>
    <s>- Submission Deadline: 28 October 2011</s>
    <s>- Notification to Authors: 28 November 2011</s>
    <s>- Final Camera-Ready Submission and Early Registration: Until 19 December 2011</s>
    <s>- Late Registration: After 19 December 2011</s>
    <s>- Conference: Berlin, Germany, 10 to 13 March 2012</s>
  </text>
</page>
