<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.ixda.org/node/29624</url>
  <title>Creativity &amp; Cognition Conference Call for Papers | IxDA</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Mar 4, 2011 Second posting of the Call for Papers, we cordially invite submissions to the 8th ACM Conference on Creativity &amp; Cognition (C&amp;C 2011) as well </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Skip to Main Content Area</s>
    <s>Username: *</s>
    <s>Password: *</s>
    <s>Become a member</s>
    <s>Forgot password</s>
    <s>IxDA.orgDiscussionResourcesJob PostsMembersLocal groupsEvents</s>
    <s>Job Board</s>
    <s>Creativity &amp; Cognition Conference Call for Papers</s>
    <s>4 Mar 2011 - 8:58am</s>
    <s>368 reads</s>
    <s>Second posting of the Call for Papers, we cordially invite submissions to the 8th ACM Conference on Creativity &amp; Cognition (C&amp;C 2011) as well as to the related art program, tutorials, workshops, and graduate student symposium.</s>
    <s>Conference: Creativity &amp; Cognition 2011</s>
    <s>Website: http://dilab.gatech.edu/ccc/index.html</s>
    <s>Conference dates: November 3-6, 2011</s>
    <s>Location: Atlanta, Georgia, USA</s>
    <s>Keynote Speakers: We are thrilled to have Guy Claxton (creativity and learning; http://www.guyclaxton.com/), Sara Diamond (creativity and visual arts; http://www.ocad.ca/about ocad/governance/board governors/sara diamond.htm), and Atau Tanaka (creativity and music; http://www.ncl.ac.uk/culturelab/people/profile/atau.tanaka) as three of our keynote speakers. We expect to have additional invited talks from other distinguished speakers as well.</s>
    <s>Award for Best Contribution to Creative Communication: In memory of Emma Candy, and with generous support from Linda Candy and Ernest Edmonds, we are starting a new Award for Best Contribution to Creative Communication for an innovative contribution to concepts and products that combine creativity and communication in ways that influence the way people use digital media in the future. The proposal could be a paper or digital prototype, a scenario, a story, an interactive installation, an artwork or a game. The award is intended to promote designers, artists and technologists who are innovating for a more creative and connected world. It includes a travel allowance and complimentary conference registration. Please see http://research.it.uts.edu.au/creative/emma award for details.</s>
    <s>Please note that the submission deadline has been extended.</s>
    <s>April 25, 2011: Deadline for all submissions</s>
    <s>May 9, 2011: Program Co-Chairs assign 3-4 papers to you for reviewing (we have noted special requests)</s>
    <s>June 6, 2011: Completion of all reviews (this is important)</s>
    <s>June 20, 2011: Program Co-Chairs complete paper selection</s>
    <s>June 27, 2011: Notification to authors</s>
    <s>Conference dates: November 3-6, 2011</s>
    <s>All submissons should be in the ACM SIGCHI format. Please see the conference website (http://dilab.gatech.edu/ccc/index.html) for submission details . Once again, the submission deadline (for all kinds of submissions including proposals for workshop and tutorials) is April 25th, 2011.</s>
    <s>We welcome contributions from researchers and practitioners, from artists and scientists, from designers, educators and decision makers. Please send all inquiries to (acmcc2011@gmail.com).</s>
    <s>C&amp;C 2011 Conference</s>
    <s>Program Co-Chairs:</s>
    <s>Ashok Goel, Georgia Institute of Technology, USA</s>
    <s>Fox Harrell, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, USA</s>
    <s>Brian Magerko, Georgia Institute of Technology, USA</s>
    <s>Yukari Nagai, Japan Advanced Institute of Science and Technology, Japan</s>
    <s>Jane Prophet, Goldsmiths College, University of London, UK</s>
    <s>The broad theme of C&amp;C 2011 is Creativity and Technology. Topics of interest include:</s>
    <s>Creativity in arts, music, story telling, poetry, design, science, etc.</s>
    <s>Everyday creativity</s>
    <s>Individual, collaborative and collective creativity</s>
    <s>Participatory creativity, organizational creativity and creative communities</s>
    <s>Democratizing creativity, do-it-yourself and folk creativity</s>
    <s>Education and training in creativity</s>
    <s>Creativity in education and training</s>
    <s>Embodiment, sensations, perceptions, emotions and behaviors in creativity</s>
    <s>Visual and perceptual representations in creativity</s>
    <s>New materials and processes for creativity</s>
    <s>Emerging technologies and media in creativity</s>
    <s>Digital media and technologies for creativity including graphics, visualization, virtual reality, augmented reality and tangible computing</s>
    <s>Social computing and media in creativity</s>
    <s>Interactive arts, theatre, music, games, story telling, design, science, etc.</s>
    <s>Empirical evaluations by quantitative and qualitative methods</s>
    <s>Case studies and ethnographic analyses</s>
    <s>Reflective accounts of individual and collaborative practice</s>
    <s>Cognitive and cognitive neuroscience models of creativity</s>
    <s>Information-processing and computational models of creativity</s>
    <s>Creative systems, tools and applications</s>
    <s>Social and cultural studies of creativity</s>
    <s>Transdisciplinary metaphors, methods, models</s>
    <s>All submissions will be reviewed by an international program committee. The conference proceedings will be published by ACM.</s>
    <s>C&amp;C 2011 Artworks</s>
    <s>Chair: Fox Harrell, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, USA</s>
    <s>We are interested in computational media art performances, screenings, and demonstrations. We are seeking a wide variety of artworks related to the conference theme of creativity and technology. The exhibition of these works will be juried and presentation of works will be integrated into the conference program. Selected artists will be requested to take part in artist panels to discuss the works in light of conference themes. Performances or screenings should involve interaction with the audience and some time for discussion of the work. Fully realized works will be prioritized over demos, however submission of proposals to present significantly developed demos is encouraged as well.</s>
    <s>Proposals should be a TOTAL of 2 pages and should include title and short description (200-300 words) of the work, as well as any links to your material, a plan for presentation, technology requirements, a short (50 words) bio for each participant and any references. A small number of installation works may also be accepted for exhibition. However priority will be given to performances, screenings, and demos that can be presented in the main conference auditorium.</s>
    <s>C&amp;C 2011 Tutorials</s>
    <s>Chair: Andres Gomez de Silva Garza, ITAM, Mexico</s>
    <s>Creativity and Cognition 2011 is looking for significant Tutorials developing research and education methods related to the conference theme of creativity and technology. A half day plan (3 hours) or a full day plan (6 hours) is available. Submit your tutorial plan 4-8 pages proposal in A4 format by March 25th, 2011.</s>
    <s>The proposals should include the title and an introduction, aims, a framework of your main idea, a plan for Tutorial (please select half day or full day), and a short (50-100 words) bio for each instructor, tutor, and lecturer with references (URL, etc).</s>
    <s>Additionally, the tutorial proposal submissions must include:</s>
    <s>- Explanation how the tutorial will be conducted (e.g., lecture, demonstration, etc.) and provide representative samples or some idea of the materials that will be included in the course notes.</s>
    <s>- The technology requirements list that includes materials and conditions needed to run the tutorial. It should include any supplies required for each participant, restrictions or conditions on offering the tutorial such as an attendance limit, technology support needed to run the tutorial.</s>
    <s>Proposals will be evaluated by review committee on the basis of their value in offering opportunities to conference attendees to learn more about the work done by others interested in the various themes and topics of the conference.</s>
    <s>C&amp;C 2011 Workshops</s>
    <s>Chair: Chien-Sing Lee, Multimedia University, Malaysia.</s>
    <s>New developments often benefit from being presented, discussed, demonstrated, speculated upon, and generally questioned in more informal settings. The workshop portion of the conference provides just such a rich channel for the dynamic exchange of new ideas, creations, and discoveries.</s>
    <s>We invite proposals for full-day and half-day workshops focused on specific topics and questions related to the conference's broader themes. We invite proposals for full-day and half-day workshops focused on specific topics and questions related to the C&amp;C 2011 conference's broader themes. We are particularly interested in topics likely to bridge the conference's many communities around the theme of Creativity and Technology.</s>
    <s>Proposals should be submitted in the conference publications format (up to four pages), and include: A 2-page extended abstract, the objectives and expected outcome of the workshop, the planned activities, the background of the organizer(s), the anticipated number of participants, and the means for soliciting and selecting participants.</s>
    <s>C&amp;C 2011 Graduate Student Symposium</s>
    <s>Chair: Ellen Yi-Luen Do, Georgia Institute of Technology, USA</s>
    <s>The Graduate Student Symposium (GSS) provides a supportive setting for feedback on graduate students' current work and guidance on future directions. GSS participants will meet and discuss their work with each other and a panel of experienced researchers and practitioners in an informal and interactive setting. We welcome applications from graduate students in terminal degree programs, (i.e. doctoral programs in research fields and master programs in the arts) in any of the disciplines and approaches concerned with creativity and cognition.</s>
    <s>Each application should provide a short written paper (no more than two pages in normal ACM SIGCHI archival format) and a brief letter of support from the student's principal adviser. The paper should describe ongoing work and summarize the student's thesis, or highlight a particular aspect. Advisor’s letter of support should indicate that the work has reached the appropriate level of maturity for presentation in this venue. The letter of support should be submitted together with the paper on the conference submission site. Please note that GSC submission, unlike paper submission, is not anonymous.</s>
    <s>Participants will be selected based on their anticipated contributions to the breadth and depth of the intellectual discussions of the symposium. Selected students will be expected to give a short presentation of their work, followed by discussion with the panel and the other student participants. In addition, each student is encouraged to present a poster describing his or her work to the full conference and a 30-second overview of their work as part of the “madness” session. We anticipate that significant financial support from NSF will be available for graduate students to attend the GSS (and thus also the C&amp;C conference).</s>
    <s>We look forward to hearing from you!</s>
    <s>Ashok Goel, General Chair</s>
    <s>Ali Mazalek, Treasurer</s>
    <s>Brian Magerko and Kurt Luther, Local Chairs</s>
    <s>Jim Davies, Evan Barba and Jill Russek, Communication Chairs</s>
    <s>Details at the conference website (http://dilab.gatech.edu/ccc/index.html).</s>
    <s>Please send all inquiries to (acmcc2011@gmail.com).</s>
    <s>Login or register to post comments</s>
    <s>call for papers</s>
    <s>Login or register to tag items</s>
    <s>Related threads</s>
    <s>Creativity &amp; Cognition 2011 Final call for papers</s>
    <s>Call for Papers for Workshops with ACM Conference on Creativity and Cognition</s>
    <s>8th ACM Conference on Creativity &amp; Cognition (C&amp;C 2011)</s>
    <s>Fwd: Call for papers for Cognitive Engineering and Decision-Making</s>
    <s>Registration Open for Creativity &amp; Cognition 2011</s>
    <s>(C) 2004-2010 Interaction Design Association | Contact IxDA | Terms &amp; Policies</s>
  </text>
</page>
