<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://sabr.org/latest/2012-nine-spring-training-conference-call-papers</url>
  <title>2012 NINE Spring Training Conference Call for Papers | SABR</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Sep 2, 2011 Fiesta Resort Conference Center 2100 South Priest Drive Tempe, Arizona. Call for Papers: The 19th Annual NINE Spring Training Conference </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>2012 NINE Spring Training Conference Call for Papers</s>
    <s>NINE: A Journal of Baseball History and Culture announces The 19th Annual NINE Spring Training Conference on the Historical and Sociological Impact of Baseball:</s>
    <s>Wednesday, March 7-Saturday, March 10, 2012</s>
    <s>Fiesta Resort Conference Center</s>
    <s>2100 South Priest Drive</s>
    <s>Tempe, Arizona</s>
    <s>Call for Papers: The 19th Annual NINE Spring Training Conference invites original, unpublished papers that study all aspects of baseball, with particular emphasis on history and social policy implications. Abstracts only, not to exceed 300 words, should be submitted by December 2, 2011, to tstrecker@bsu.edu. Authors will be notified as quickly as possible whether their papers have been accepted. Authors are required to register for the conference and present their work in person.</s>
    <s>Keynote Speaker: Rob Fitts</s>
    <s>Rob Fitts graduated from the University of Pennsylvania and received a Ph.D. from Brown University. Originally trained as an archeologist of colonial America, Fitts left that field in 2000 to focus on his passion, Japanese baseball. He has since published numerous articles and three books on the topic. The first, Remembering Japanese Baseball: An Oral History of the Game , won the Sporting News-SABR Baseball Research Award in 2005. His second book, Wally Yonamime: The Man Who Changed Japanese Baseball , is a biography of the first American to play professional baseball in Japan after World War II. Banzai Babe Ruth: Baseball, Espionage, and Assassination during the 1934 Tour of Japan (forthcoming early in 2012) is the story of the attempt to reconcile the United States and Japan through the tour of Major League all-stars in 1934 and the efforts of fanatical ultra-nationalists to drive the nations apart. The story involves international diplomacy, espionage, attempted murder, and, of course, baseball.</s>
    <s>Featured Guest: Ila Borders</s>
    <s>An all-star Little League prodigy, at age 12 Ila Borders hit 18 home runs. She was named MVP in her junior high and high school years, and in 1994 became the first woman ever awarded a collegiate baseball scholarship. That year, pitching for Southern California College (NAIA), she stepped into history as the first woman to post a complete-game victory in men's collegiate baseball. In 1997, scout Barry Moss recommended Borders to Mike Veeck, who signed her to his St. Paul Saints of the independent Northern League. In 1998, pitching for the Duluth-Superior Dukes of the same league, Borders became the first woman to win a men's professional game since Mamie &quot;Peanut&quot; Johnson of the Negro leagues. Borders ultimately pitched four seasons of professional baseball. She currently works as a firefighter/paramedic in Arizona and coaches baseball for the World Children's Baseball Fair. She is completing a memoir of her life and times in baseball.</s>
    <s>Registration: Conference registration forms are available online on the NINE Website at http://nine.iweb.bsu.edu/registration.htm. The $195 conference registration fee includes the Saturday evening banquet and tickets for two spring training games, if paid prior to January 13, 2012. After January 13, the conference fee will be $205, and game tickets are not guaranteed.</s>
    <s>Send your registration form with your conference fee to:</s>
    <s>Dan and Jean Ardell</s>
    <s>P.O. Box 482</s>
    <s>Corona del Mar, CA 92625</s>
    <s>For further information about conference registration, please contact Jean Ardell at jeanardell@yahoo.com.</s>
    <s>Hotel: Registrants should make their hotel reservations directly with the Fiesta Resort Conference Center on the Web at http://www.fiestaresortcc.com or by phone at (800) 528-6481. Rates are $99/night single or double; $109/night three per room; $119/night four per room. To ensure the conference rate; rooms must be booked before February 15, 2012. Be sure to mention NINE: A Journal of Baseball History &amp; Culture .</s>
    <s>Trey Strecker, Editor</s>
    <s>NINE: A Journal of Baseball History and Culture</s>
    <s>Department of English</s>
    <s>Ball State University</s>
    <s>2000 W. University Ave.</s>
    <s>Muncie, IN 47306-0460</s>
    <s>NINE Web site: http://nine.iweb.bsu.edu</s>
    <s>This page was last updated September 2, 2011 at 11:16 am MST.</s>
    <s>SABR Headlines</s>
    <s>SABR Publications Director Seeks Boston-Area Interns</s>
    <s>This Week in SABR: October 7, 2011</s>
    <s>Amateur Film Shows New York Giants' Final Game at Polo Grounds</s>
    <s>Apply For A Spring 2012 Internship With SABR</s>
    <s>This Week in SABR: September 30, 2011</s>
    <s>SABR Interviews With Heroes of Octobers Past</s>
    <s>Chuck McGill Wins First SABR Fantasy Baseball League</s>
    <s>Retrosheet Creates New Discrepancy Files</s>
    <s>Maris Events Highlight Weekend in New York</s>
    <s>Save the Date: 2012 Jerry Malloy Negro League Conference</s>
    <s>This Week in SABR: September 23, 2011</s>
    <s>Hungry For Music Fundraiser Provides Instruments For Kids</s>
    <s>Commentary and Critiques for the New &quot;Moneyball&quot; Movie</s>
    <s>SABR Member Seeks Donations for Ed Killian Plaque in Racine</s>
    <s>This Week in SABR: September 16, 2011</s>
    <s>Save the Date: 2012 SABR Convention in Minneapolis</s>
    <s>Seamheads.com and The Baseball Gauge Launch Negro Leagues Database</s>
    <s>Set Your DVRs on September 18 for &quot;Behind the Seams: The Stat Story&quot;</s>
    <s>This Week in SABR: September 9, 2011</s>
    <s>This Week in SABR: September 2, 2011</s>
    <s>2012 NINE Spring Training Conference Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Sign Up For Baseball Tour of Cuba in January 2012</s>
    <s>Register Now for 2011 SABR Arizona Fall League Conference</s>
    <s>Introducing the New SABR Bookstore</s>
    <s>Ward Miller monument dedicated in Dixon, Illinois</s>
    <s>Individual Memberships start at just $45/year</s>
    <s>Become A Member Today</s>
    <s>When you join SABR you are making a statement of support for baseball history. You are joining a worldwide community of people who love to read about, talk about and write about baseball.</s>
    <s>First Name:</s>
    <s>Last Name:</s>
    <s>Join Today</s>
    <s>Society for American Baseball Research</s>
    <s>About SABR</s>
    <s>Latest News</s>
    <s>SEARCH SABR:</s>
    <s>SABR 4455 E. Camelback Rd Ste D-140, Phoenix, AZ 85018</s>
    <s>Phone: (800) 969-7227</s>
    <s>Fax: (602) 595-5690</s>
    <s>Contact Us (C) SABR 2011 SABR Store</s>
  </text>
</page>
