<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.asis.org/asist2011/am11cfp.html</url>
  <title>2011 ASIS&amp;T Annual Meeting Call for Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Home &gt;; Conferences &gt;; 2011 Annual Meeting &gt;; Call for Papers ASIST 2011 builds on the success of the 2010 conference structure and will have the </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>ASIS&amp;T - The Information Society for the Information Age</s>
    <s>sign in</s>
    <s>contact us</s>
    <s>site index</s>
    <s>About ASIS&amp;T;</s>
    <s>SIGS &amp; Chapters</s>
    <s>E-Mail Lists</s>
    <s>Home &gt;</s>
    <s>Conferences &gt;</s>
    <s>2011 Annual Meeting &gt;</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Continuing Education</s>
    <s>Upcoming Conferences</s>
    <s>Past Conferences</s>
    <s>Conference Proceedings</s>
    <s>Local Events</s>
    <s>Exhibit in New Orleans</s>
    <s>Annual Meeting Exhibitors</s>
    <s>Click here!</s>
    <s>Important Dates</s>
    <s>1) Papers, Panels, Workshops &amp; Tutorials</s>
    <s>Deadline for submissions: May 31</s>
    <s>Notification to authors: June 28</s>
    <s>Final copy: July 15</s>
    <s>2) Posters, Demos &amp; Videos:</s>
    <s>Deadline for submissions: July 1</s>
    <s>Notification to authors: July 20</s>
    <s>Final copy: July 27</s>
    <s>(All deadlines: midnight, Hawaii Standard Time)</s>
    <s>Submit Here</s>
    <s>74th Annual Meeting of the</s>
    <s>American Society for Information Science and Technology</s>
    <s>Bridging the Gulf:</s>
    <s>Communication and Information in Society, Technology, and Work</s>
    <s>October 9-13, 2011, New Orleans, Louisiana</s>
    <s>Annual Meeting Website Now Available</s>
    <s>How to Submit</s>
    <s>Potential presenters, please use this template to prepare your submission: PDF or Word.</s>
    <s>Submission Site</s>
    <s>Once you have prepared your submission according to the instructions, please deposit it into the submission system: www.softconf.com/asis/AM 2011/</s>
    <s>The ASIST Annual Meeting is the main venue for disseminating research centered on advances in the information sciences and related applications of information technology.</s>
    <s>ASIST 2011 builds on the success of the 2010 conference structure and will have the integrated program that is an ASIST strength. This will be achieved using the six reviewing tracks pioneered in 2010, each with its own committee of respected reviewers to ensure that the conference meets your high expectations for standards and quality. These reviewers, experts in their fields, will assist with a rigorous peer-review process.</s>
    <s>Track 1 Information Behavior</s>
    <s>Chair: Sanda Erdelez, University of Missouri</s>
    <s>Co-Chair: Dania Bilal, University of Tennessee</s>
    <s>Information needs, information seeking, information gaps and sense-making.</s>
    <s>Track 2 Knowledge Organization</s>
    <s>Chair: Diane R. Neal, University of Western Ontario</s>
    <s>Co-Chair: Margaret Kipp, University of Milwaukee</s>
    <s>Indexing, index construction, indexing languages, thesaurus construction, terminology, classification of information in any form, tagging (expert, user-based, automatic), filtering, metadata, standards for metadata, information architecture.</s>
    <s>Track 3 Interactive Information &amp; Design</s>
    <s>Chair: Jim Jansen, Pennsylvania State University</s>
    <s>Co-Chair: Soo Young Rieh, University of Michigan</s>
    <s>How human beings use and communicate with information or computers, design of interactive technologies, algorithms, user interfaces, search &amp; retrieval, personalization &amp; recommenders, navigation, information architecture.</s>
    <s>Track 4 Information and Knowledge Management</s>
    <s>Chair: Robert Sandusky, University of Illinois, Chicago</s>
    <s>Co-Chair: Kenneth R. Fleischmann, University of Maryland</s>
    <s>Information and knowledge creation, transfer and use at the personal, group, organizational and societal levels; expertise, insights, and judgment in organizations; the management of the processes and systems that create, acquire, organize, store, distribute, and use information; knowledge capital; social networking; knowledge sharing and communities of practice; business intelligence; content management, document management; workflow management; collaboration systems; portals; groupware; information and knowledge preservation and storage.</s>
    <s>Track 5 Information Use</s>
    <s>Chair: Mia Lustria, Florida State University</s>
    <s>Co-Chair: Michelle Kazmer, Florida State University</s>
    <s>Nature of information and how information is used to help solve problems and aid decision making; information literacy, reading</s>
    <s>Track 6 Economic, Social, and Political Issues</s>
    <s>Chair: Nadia Caidi, University of Toronto</s>
    <s>Co-Chair: Steven Jackson, University of Michigan</s>
    <s>Copyright issues, policies and laws; information policy; privacy; personal rights vs. freedom of information; surveillance; regulation; international information flow&amp; issues; spam</s>
    <s>Because each of these tracks represents a generic aspect of information science, each may be focused by additional elements such as types of:</s>
    <s>Organizations schools, universities, government, private corporations</s>
    <s>Information by topic, genre, size, medium, etc.</s>
    <s>Technology PDAs, computers, smart phones, wearable technologies, blogs, wikis, ebooks, hypermedia</s>
    <s>Information consumers from kids to seniors, and from grunts to managers, from individuals to groups</s>
    <s>Information workers librarians, database and system developers, information managers, information architects</s>
    <s>Contexts entertainment, edutainment, learning, social, mission critical, etc.</s>
    <s>Research theories and paradigms from uses and gratification to Zipfs Law</s>
    <s>Methods qualitative, qualitative, mixed, modeling, etc.</s>
    <s>Types of Submission:</s>
    <s>The Conference welcomes the following types of submissions:</s>
    <s>1) Papers</s>
    <s>Papers must report original, unpublished recent results substantiated by experimentation, simulation, theoretical development, analysis, or application. These papers should be reports of completed or well-developed projects on topics suitable for publication in scholarly and professional journals. The maximum length for a paper is 10 pages, single-spaced. All submissions will be refereed, and accepted papers will be published in the digital conference proceedings. Authors will choose their preferred track at submission time; the chairs reserve the right to re-track submissions as necessary.</s>
    <s>2) Panels</s>
    <s>Proposals for panels are invited on topics that include emerging cutting-edge research and design, analyses of hot or emerging trends, opinions on controversial issues, analyses of tools and techniques, and contrasting viewpoints from experts in complementary professional areas. Panels are not a substitute for a set of contributed papers, but must have a cohesive theme and promote lively interaction between panelists and audience members. Submit two to four pages that provide an overview of the issues to be discussed by the panel. Proposals should also list panellists who have agreed to participate and indicate the qualifications and contribution that each panelist will offer. Proposals for Pecha Kucha style presentations, are encouraged.</s>
    <s>3) Interactive Showcase</s>
    <s>One evening will be devoted to face-to-face presentations using traditional posters, short videos, or live demonstrations. These formats provide opportunities for interactive discussion and feedback about the work. Submissions are welcomed in areas related to any of tracks. Please submit up to four pages (about 1,250 words) for each form; a revised version of the accepted submissions will appear in the conference proceedings. As with papers, submitters will choose their preferred track at submission time; the chairs reserve the right to re-track submissions as necessary.</s>
    <s>&gt; a) Posters offer a unique opportunity to present late-breaking results, work in progress, or research that is best communicated in an interactive or graphical format. Please note, however, that posters describing work that is simply a proposal will not be accepted.</s>
    <s>&gt; Two types of posters are encouraged: contributed research posters presenting new and promising work or preliminary results of research projects; and contributed best practices posters presenting the results of design projects, practical implementations of an organizations practices or industry innovations. The content of the poster should clearly point out how the application contributes to innovation of thought or design within the field, and how it addresses key challenges, as well as the potential impact on the participants organization and/or practices in the field. Joint submissions from researchers and practitioners showing different perspectives on a single issue are particularly encouraged. Posters are expected to invite questions and discussion in a personal and less formal setting. Submissions for refereeing should be in the form of a proposal of up to four pages (about 1,250 words).</s>
    <s>&gt; b) Demos offer a unique opportunity to present novel technology, including new devices, systems, or applications.. Submissions should describe the technology and list required supporting equipment. We assume that most equipment will be supplied by the demonstrator, and reserve the right to turn down unreasonable requests.</s>
    <s>&gt; c) Videos offer a unique opportunity to present the traditional poster or demo using a different medium. While videos may present research or demo a technology, they may also be used to describe a procedure or showcase a novel implementation. Videos of three to ten minutes must be uploaded to YouTube, and the link supplied in the submission.</s>
    <s>4) Workshops and Tutorials</s>
    <s>Workshops and Tutorials will be held after the conference. The purpose is to provide a more informal setting for the exchange of ideas on a focused topic and suggest directions for future work. As such, they offer a good opportunity for researchers and professionals to present and discuss work with an interested community. Workshops may be mini-focused research presentations, a series of working events, brainstorming and idea sharing, or even teaching/learning a new skill. In particular, SIGS are invited to submit proposals for half-day or full-day events on topics that are pertinent to the goals of the SIG. Proposals that are not SIG related or sponsored are also welcome. Only one submission per SIG is permitted for a workshop, and additional participation fees will apply.</s>
    <s>For more information, please contact:</s>
    <s>Conference Chairs</s>
    <s>Suzie Allard (sallard@utk.edu)</s>
    <s>Lynn Silipigni Connaway (connawal@oclc.org)</s>
    <s>Local arrangements and logistics</s>
    <s>Richard Hill (rhill@asis.org)</s>
    <s>American Society for Information Science and Technology</s>
    <s>1320 Fenwick Lane, Suite 510, Silver Spring, Maryland 20910, USA</s>
    <s>Tel. 301-495-0900 / Fax: 301-495-0810 / E-mail: asis@asis.org</s>
    <s>disclaimer | copyright</s>
  </text>
</page>
