<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://aaahq.org/calls/default.cfm</url>
  <title>Calls for Submissions</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Submissions are invited for the The 18th Annual Midyear Conference of the International Theoretical and empirical papers in all areas of business, finance, marketing, ATA 2012 Midyear Meeting Combined Call for Submissions—The 24th </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>!American Accounting Association</s>
    <s>AAA Home</s>
    <s>About AAA</s>
    <s>AAA Newsroom</s>
    <s>Sections / Regions</s>
    <s>Calls For Submissions</s>
    <s>Faculty Development</s>
    <s>Career Center</s>
    <s>Links &amp; Organizations</s>
    <s>Contact AAA Staff</s>
    <s>Frequently Asked</s>
    <s>!Calls For Submissions</s>
    <s>2012 International Accounting Section Midyear Conference Submissions are invited for the The 18th Annual Midyear Conference of the International Accounting Section of the American Accounting Association. The meeting will be held at the beautiful Hilton Tapatio Cliffs Resort in Phoenix, AZ during February 23-25, 2012.</s>
    <s>Deadline: October 15, 2011</s>
    <s>2012 Winter Hawaii Global Conference on Business and Finance (GCBF) Theoretical and empirical papers in all areas of business, finance, marketing, management, accounting, MIS, public administration, economics, business law, business education, agribusiness, health care administration and related fields are welcome.</s>
    <s>Deadline: November 7, 2011</s>
    <s>2012 Forensic and Investigative Accounting Section Meeting Submissions are invited for the Third Annual Midyear Forensic and Investigative Accounting Conference to be held March 30-31, 2012, at the Loop Campus of DePaul University in Chicago, IL.</s>
    <s>Deadline: November 15, 2011</s>
    <s>2012 American Taxation Association Midyear Meeting ATA 2012 Midyear Meeting Combined Call for Submissions—The 24th annual American Taxation Association (ATA) Midyear Meeting will be held in New Orleans, LA on February 24-25, 2012. We invite submissions to the following four research sessions:</s>
    <s>JATA Conference-deadline 9/30/11</s>
    <s>JLTR Conference-deadline 11/01/11</s>
    <s>New Faculty/Doctoral Student Session-deadline 11/01/11</s>
    <s>Research-in-Process Session-deadline 12/01/11</s>
    <s>Deadline: December 1, 2011</s>
    <s>Glen McLaughlin Prize for Research in Accounting Ethics Each year the Steed School of Accounting at the University of Oklahoma solicits submissions for the annual Glen McLaughlin Prize for research in accounting ethics. The prize includes an award of $15,000 for the best unpublished paper on ethics in any area of accounting.</s>
    <s>Deadline: December 1, 2011</s>
    <s>2012 Government and Nonprofit Section Midyear Conference Papers are invited for the 2012 Government and Nonprofit Section Midyear Conference of the American Accounting Association will be held at the Hilton Mission Valley Hotel in beautiful San Diego, CA on March 2-3, 2012.</s>
    <s>Deadline: December 5, 2011</s>
    <s>Journal of Information Systems Special Issue JIS will publish a special section in the Fall 2012 issue entitled “IT Governance, Risk and Value.”</s>
    <s>Deadline: December 31, 2011</s>
    <s>The 3rd Global Accounting and Organisational Change Conference 2012 The GAOCR network is committed to high-quality research on contemporary issues in organisational and accounting change. It aims to provide a platform for international researchers and practitioners from multiple disciplines to disseminate information on organisational and accounting systems change.</s>
    <s>Deadline: January 6, 2012</s>
    <s>2012 Mid-Atlantic Region Meeting Accounting educators, students and professionals are invited to submit completed manuscripts and ideas for panels for the 2012 AAA Mid-Atlantic Regional Meeting. Papers may encompass any topical area of accounting and may be theoretical or practice-oriented.</s>
    <s>Deadline: January 9, 2012</s>
    <s>2012 AAA Annual Meeting Submissions are invited for the 2012 AAA Annual Meeting to be held August 4-8, 2012, in Washington, DC. The theme for the meeting is &quot;Seeds of Innovation.&quot; This theme focuses on the broad need for greater innovation in accounting scholarship.</s>
    <s>Deadline: January 11, 2012</s>
    <s>2012 Western Region Meeting Submissions are invited for the 2012 Western Region meeting to be held April 19-21, 2012, at the Hilton Downtown Vancouver, in Vancouver, Washington. (Easy access from the Portland, Oregon International Airport.)</s>
    <s>Deadline: January 16, 2012</s>
    <s>18th Annual International Symposium on Audit Research Submissions are invited for the 18th annual International Symposium on Audit Research (ISAR) which will be held on June 16 and 17, 2012 in Tokyo, Japan.</s>
    <s>Deadline: January 31, 2012</s>
    <s>The International Journal of Accounting Symposium Papers are invited for the 2012 annual The International Journal of Accounting symposium to be held in Niagara Falls, Ontario, Canada on July 5-7, 2012.</s>
    <s>Deadline: January 31, 2012</s>
    <s>International Symposium on Management Accounting and Control in the Age of Globalization The 8th International Symposium on Management Accounting and Control (ISMAC) will be held at Cardiff University, Cardiff, UK on 18-19 June 2012.</s>
    <s>Deadline: February 1, 2012</s>
    <s>3rd International Symposium on Accounting Information Systems The Department of Accounting, University of Melbourne, Australia is pleased to announce the third ISAIS commencing in the morning of June 28, followed by a half day on June 29, 2012.</s>
    <s>Deadline: February 15, 2012</s>
    <s>Sustainability Accounting and Management Policy Journal Special Issue on Sustainability Accounting for the Industrial Use of Biomass</s>
    <s>Deadline: February 29, 2012</s>
    <s>Issues in Accounting Education —Special Edition The American Accounting Association requests submissions for a special edition of Issues in Accounting Education, to be devoted to the pedagogy and content of the accounting courses in the Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.) degree.</s>
    <s>Deadline: March 1, 2012</s>
    <s>2012 Costa Rica Global Conference on Business and Finance (GCBF) You are invited to participate in The 2012 Costa Rica Global Conference on Business and Finance (GCBF) in San Jose, Costa Rica.</s>
    <s>Deadline: March 15, 2012</s>
    <s>Research in Accounting in Emerging Economies Special Issue on &quot;Accounting in Latin America&quot;</s>
    <s>Deadline: March 31, 2012</s>
    <s>OR Spectrum —Special Issue OR Spectrum invites papers for a special issue on Operations Research and Accounting in Supply Chain Coordination.</s>
    <s>Deadline: March 31, 2012</s>
    <s>Production and Operations Management — Special Issue POM is requesting papers for a special issue on &quot;Information and Incentive Issues in Supply Chains&quot;. The formation and coordination of supply chains are prominent and evolving areas of research in a variety of fields, including accounting, economics, and finance.</s>
    <s>Deadline: April 15, 2012</s>
    <s>IMA Educational Case Journal (IECJ) The IMA Educational Case Journal (IECJ), published quarterly by the Institute of Management Accountants (IMA), is dedicated to enhancing case research through the publication of teaching cases and research related to case writing or teaching with cases in the field of management accounting and related areas.</s>
    <s>International Journal of Accounting and Financial Reporting (IJAFR) This journal publishes theoretical, empirical and experimental papers that significantly contribute to the disciplines of accounting and finance.</s>
    <s>Journal of Governmental and Nonprofit Accounting The Government and Nonprofit section of the American Accounting Association announces a new academic journal, the Journal of Governmental &amp; Nonprofit Accounting (JOGNA). JOGNA's objectives are to promote, publish, and elevate the quality of research in the governmental and nonprofit accounting areas.</s>
    <s>Studies in Accounting Research Studies in Accounting Research (SAR) is a prestigious monograph series of the AAA that provides an outlet for seminal and innovative research not bounded by the usual space and topic constraints present in our journals. SAR is of significant benefit to authors in exploring a topic in great depth and as a resource for other researchers. Interested individuals are encouraged to either submit a proposal or a completed work.</s>
    <s>Accounting and the Public Interest Submissions are invited for Accounting and the Public Interest, an online-only academic journal published by the Public Interest Section of the American Accounting Association.</s>
    <s>Journal of Emerging Technologies in Accounting The Journal of Emerging Technologies in Accounting is the academic journal of the Artificial Intelligence/Emerging Technologies Section of the American Accounting Association. The purpose of the section is to improve and facilitate the research, education, and practice of advanced information systems, cutting-edge technologies, and artificial intelligence in the fields of accounting, information technology, and management advisory systems.</s>
    <s>Journal of International Accounting Research The Journal of International Accounting Research publishes articles that increase our understanding of the development and use of international accounting and reporting practices or attempt to improve extant practices.</s>
    <s>The ATA Journal of Legal Tax Research The American Taxation Association announces a new electronic journal. The ATA Journal of Legal Tax Research publishes creative and innovative studies employing legal research methodologies that meet the objectives and standards set forth by the ATA and the journal’s editorial board.</s>
    <s>(C) 2010 American Accounting Association All rights reserved.</s>
  </text>
</page>
