<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.kon.org/CFP/cfp_urc.html</url>
  <title>Call for Papers: Undergraduate Research Conference</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Undergraduate Research Community (URC). Call for Undergraduate Student Research Papers for presentation at the. Undergraduate Research Conference </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Kappa Omicron Nu</s>
    <s>Research Journal</s>
    <s>Special Editions</s>
    <s>Eye Deceptions</s>
    <s>George D. Green</s>
    <s>Historical Analysis of the American Civil Liberties Union</s>
    <s>Interconnected through Art: The Artist, The Land, The Community</s>
    <s>Selected Topics in Athletic Training</s>
    <s>Current and Potential Practices in Athletic Training</s>
    <s>High School Edition</s>
    <s>Volume 10 - 2011</s>
    <s>Volume 9 - 2010</s>
    <s>Volume 8 - 2009</s>
    <s>Volume 7 - 2008</s>
    <s>Volume 6 - 2007</s>
    <s>Volume 5 - 2006</s>
    <s>Volume 4 - 2005</s>
    <s>Volume 3 - 2004</s>
    <s>Volume 2 - 2003</s>
    <s>Volume 1 - 2002</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Undergraduate Research Journal for the Human Sciences</s>
    <s>Undergraduate Research Conference</s>
    <s>Planning Conference</s>
    <s>Priority Issues</s>
    <s>Faculty Development</s>
    <s>Institutional Plan</s>
    <s>URC News Vol.1 1</s>
    <s>URC News Vol.1 2</s>
    <s>URC News Vol.2 1</s>
    <s>URC News Vol.2 2</s>
    <s>URJHS Blog</s>
    <s>RSS Feed</s>
    <s>Javascript is disabled in your browserUse footer menu.</s>
    <s>Undergraduate Research Community (URC)</s>
    <s>Call for Undergraduate Student Research Papers</s>
    <s>for presentation at the</s>
    <s>Undergraduate Research Conference</s>
    <s>East Lansing, Michigan</s>
    <s>August 9 - 12, 2012</s>
    <s>See www.kon.org/our-centennial.html for conference details.</s>
    <s>&gt; Undergraduate students in the human sciences are eligible to submit research manuscripts, papers, and reports for presentation at the 2012 Undergraduate Research Community for the Human Sciences Research Conference.</s>
    <s>&gt; Research not only bridges the gap between knowledge and experience but has the benefit of laying the groundwork for career exploration and development. The opportunity for undergraduates to participate in a national conference is an added value to the overall education experience and to the process of self-discovery.</s>
    <s>&gt; Themes</s>
    <s>&gt;Integrative, cross specialization research</s>
    <s>&gt;Service Learning research</s>
    <s>&gt;Traditional research in the specializations (research manuscripts, research papers, research reports.) See Guidelines for Submissions.</s>
    <s>&gt; Criteria For Selection - The following six criteria will be used in selecting the papers and reports to be presented:</s>
    <s>&gt;Relevance to the human sciences</s>
    <s>&gt;Scholarly presentation</s>
    <s>&gt;Justification for the study</s>
    <s>&gt;Logical organization</s>
    <s>&gt;Mastery of the subject</s>
    <s>&gt;Appropriate documentation</s>
    <s>&gt; Specifications - Manuscripts, papers, and reports must meet the following specifications:</s>
    <s>&gt;Manuscripts, papers, and reports submitted for consideration may describe student projects or research from seminars, independent studies, research assistantships, or class projects in the student's major, and must be completed between January 1, 2011 and June 1, 2012. See Volumes 1 - 12 of the Undergraduate Research Journal for models of manuscripts, papers, and reports.</s>
    <s>&gt;Manuscripts, papers, and reports should be from four to six pages in length and must be typed, double-spaced, on one side only of white 8 1/2 X 11 paper.</s>
    <s>&gt;List keywords (5-8) on the cover page. The main purpose of keywords is to enable successful searching in a database for the main message of your paper. When selecting keywords always think about how any reader might interrogate the database.</s>
    <s>&gt;Only manuscripts, papers, and reports from completed research projects will be considered for the award. Manuscripts, papers, and reports may be submitted once.</s>
    <s>&gt;Students who completed their degrees in August 2011 and December 2011 and have graduated are still eligible to be considered for this opportunity.</s>
    <s>&gt;APA guidelines (other style manuals may be used)</s>
    <s>&gt;Link to URC APA Guidelines for Authors</s>
    <s>&gt;A Modified Presubmission Checklist</s>
    <s>&gt;Link to Purdue University APA Guidelines for Authors</s>
    <s>&gt; Application and Review Procedures - Three copies of each manuscript, paper, and report must be submitted to:</s>
    <s>&gt;&gt; &gt; URC Call for Papers</s>
    <s>4990 Northwind Drive, Suite 140, East Lansing, MI 48823-5031</s>
    <s>(T) 517.351.8335 - (F) 517.351.8336 - dmitstifer@kon.org.</s>
    <s>&gt;Manuscripts, papers, and reports must be postmarked no later than June 1, 2012.</s>
    <s>&gt;A cover page must be attached to one copy of the application to identify the author's name, address, phone number, e-mail address, name of college/university, name of faculty mentor, name of faculty member who served as the writing adviser, student status (e.g., junior), and parent's address and telephone for emergency contact. No identification of the author or institution should appear on the pages of the application.</s>
    <s>&gt;In the case of multiple authorsstudent authors are preferred; a professor as a last author is acceptable.</s>
    <s>&gt;A committee composed of leaders from the human sciences will review submitted applications. Selection of 6-8 papers for presentation will be completed and authors notified by June 15, 2012. Authors whose submissions are not selected for presentation may be offered the opportunity to exhibit a poster.</s>
    <s>&gt;Applicants should understand that selection carries the obligation of presenting the manuscript, paper, or report.</s>
    <s>&gt; Presentation at URC Research Conference - The students whose manuscripts, papers, and reports are selected will present at the URC Research Conference in Summer 2012. Oral presentations will be 8-10 minutes in length with some time for questions and answers. Presentations may include 4 - 8 transparencies or PowerPoint slides for visual support of major concepts and findings. Presenters are responsible for expenses incurred in attending the research conference. The top two presenters will be awarded a plaque and monetary gift. See evaluation form.</s>
    <s>&gt; Presenters will have the opportunity to submit papers for publication in the electronic undergraduate research journal.</s>
    <s>!Hit Counter 7/1/04</s>
    <s>!URC RESOURCES:</s>
    <s>Research Journal: Vol. 1 Vol. 2 Vol. 3 Vol. 4 Vol. 5 Vol. 6 Vol. 7 Vol. 8 Vol. 9 Vol. 10</s>
    <s>High School Edition</s>
    <s>Call for Papers 1 ¦ Call for Papers 2 ¦ Inventory ¦ News</s>
    <s>Planning Conference ¦ Priorities ¦ Faculty Development ¦ Priority Issues ¦ Institutional Plan ¦ URC Home</s>
  </text>
</page>
