<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.ajbs.org/index.php%3Fpr%3DCall_for_Papers</url>
  <title>AJBS Conference Call for Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Papers submitted for presentation at the AJBS conference presentation are double-blind peer reviewed. Accepted papers are considered for publication in a </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>AJBS Conference Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Home Page</s>
    <s>About AJBS</s>
    <s>Conference Attendee Information</s>
    <s>Conference Program Overview</s>
    <s>Conference Program - Detail</s>
    <s>Member Benefits</s>
    <s>Purchase Proceedings</s>
    <s>Renew or Join</s>
    <s>Membership Status</s>
    <s>Current Leadership</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Paper Submission Deadline: Extended to March 4, 2011</s>
    <s>AJBS will hold its 24th annual meeting, in cooperation with the Academy of International Business (AIB), in Nagoya, Japan. The AJBS conference will take place on June 24th (Friday) and 25th (Saturday), with the AIB conference following on June 26th 28th. This years AJBS conference is organized by the Program Chair, Toshihiro Kanai of Kobe University, Japan, and the Conference Co-chairs, Norihiko Takeuchi of Aoyama Gakuin University, Japan and John Volkmar of Otterbein University, USA.</s>
    <s>The AJBS annual conference provides an opportunity for discussion of current developments and research on a range of business, public policy, and teaching issues related to Japan. We welcome scholars, students, and practitioners from all disciplinary backgrounds who are interested in Japanese business issues. Papers submitted for presentation at the AJBS conference presentation are double-blind peer reviewed. Accepted papers are considered for publication in a special issue of the organizations affiliated journal, Asian Business &amp; Management .</s>
    <s>The co-location of the AJBS and AIB conferences provides a unique opportunity. With one trip (to Japan!), you can attend both the most prestigious professional meeting dealing with international business and an intimate conference that focuses specifically on issues associated with Japanese business. The AJBS conference provides additional opportunities for journal publication and best paper awards, as detailed below.</s>
    <s>Authors may submit papers to either or both of the AJBS and AIB conferences. AJBS will consider submissions that have already been presented elsewhere, but not those previously published in a journal or book. You are encouraged to consider submitting a paper to AJBS tailored to the specialized audience at the AJBS conference, as well as a modified version to AIB that is appropriate for the wider audience in attendance there.</s>
    <s>Paper submission: The submission deadline for 2011 AJBS conference is Friday, March 4, 2011. Please submit papers as email attachments in MS-Word format to Norihiko Takeuchi (ntake@busi.aoyama.ac.jp). (Note: If you do not have MS-Word, use a basic text format. Please do not submit papers in PDF format.) Paper submission guidelines are available on the AJBS website ( http://www.ajbs.org) . Following the double-blind review process, authors will be notified about decisions by early April, 2011.</s>
    <s>Conference Registration: Registration for the AJBS conference reflects a specially-discounted combined (AJBS plus AIB) conference fee, and includes a one-year membership to AJBS (if you are not already a member) and a one-year subscription to Asian Business &amp; Management .</s>
    <s>Asian Business &amp; Management : In 2003 AJBS established a partnership with the journal Asian Business &amp; Management ( ABM ), published by Palgrave Macmillan (http://www.palgrave-journals.com/abm/index.html). As in recent years, the editor of ABM , together with the AJBS conference committee, will select approximately six papers from the 2011 conference program to be considered for publication in a special volume of the journal. At the time of submission, please indicate whether you wish your paper to be considered for publication in the special issue of ABM .</s>
    <s>Palgrave Macmillan AJBS Best Paper Award: Palgrave Macmillan generously sponsors a Best Paper prize at the annual AJBS meeting. A committee will review the finalist papers and select the winning paper.</s>
    <s>For further information: Details regarding the Nagoya meeting venue and AIB conference are available at http://aib.msu.edu/events/2011. For questions regarding the AJBS conference and submissions, please contact one of the Conference Co-chairs Norihiko Takeuchi (ntake@busi.aoyama.ac.jp) or John Volkmar (mailto:jvolkmar@otterbein.edu) For questions or comments regarding AJBS or conference registration, please contact the AJBS Executive Director, Diane Bird (ajbs@ajbs.org) or the AJBS President Elizabeth Rose, (Elizabeth.Rose@hse.fi).</s>
    <s>CFP NAGOYA 2011.doc 108.5K</s>
    <s>back to top</s>
    <s>[Home Page | About AJBS | Conference Attendee Information | Conference Program Overview | Conference Program - Detail | Member Benefits | Purchase Proceedings | Renew or Join | Membership Status | Current Leadership ]</s>
    <s>Content (C)2005 | Design (C) 2008 eDisc CC</s>
  </text>
</page>
