<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.sigmod2011.org/calls_papers_pods_research.shtml</url>
  <title>The 2011 ACM SIGMOD/PODS Conference: Athens, Greece - Call ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Call for Papers: PODS Research. The PODS symposium series, held in conjunction with the SIGMOD conference series, provides a premier annual forum for the </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>!sigmod pods logo</s>
    <s>Conference Officers</s>
    <s>SIGMOD PC</s>
    <s>SIGMOD Demo PC</s>
    <s>SIGMOD Industry PC</s>
    <s>Repeatability PC</s>
    <s>PODS PC</s>
    <s>Web Streaming and Other Media</s>
    <s>Affiliated Conferences &amp; Workshops</s>
    <s>Exhibitor Information</s>
    <s>Visit Athens</s>
    <s>Previous Conferences</s>
    <s>ACM SIGMOD Online</s>
    <s>SIGMOD 2011 Proceedings</s>
    <s>PODS 2011 Proceedings</s>
    <s>SIGMOD/PODS 2012</s>
    <s>SIGMOD Program</s>
    <s>Schedule at a Glance</s>
    <s>SIGMOD Program</s>
    <s>-Printable Version</s>
    <s>Keynote 1: J. Hamilton</s>
    <s>Keynote 2: A. Ailamaki</s>
    <s>Industry Keynotes</s>
    <s>Research Papers</s>
    <s>Industry Papers</s>
    <s>Demo Papers</s>
    <s>Undergraduate Posters</s>
    <s>PODS Program</s>
    <s>Schedule at a Glance</s>
    <s>PODS Program</s>
    <s>-Printable Version</s>
    <s>Keynote: T. Milo</s>
    <s>Tutorial 1: S. Muthukrishnan</s>
    <s>Tutorial 2: M. Arenas and J. Perez</s>
    <s>Research Papers</s>
    <s>Invited Talks</s>
    <s>30th Anniversary</s>
    <s>For Attendees</s>
    <s>Conference Banquet</s>
    <s>Conference Hotel</s>
    <s>Travel Info</s>
    <s>Visitor Information</s>
    <s>Visa Information</s>
    <s>Student Travel Grants</s>
    <s>East Europe Grants</s>
    <s>Calls For Submissions</s>
    <s>Important Dates and Submission</s>
    <s>Calls for Submissions</s>
    <s>Call for Papers: PODS Research</s>
    <s>The PODS symposium series, held in conjunction with the SIGMOD conference series, provides a premier annual forum for the communication of new advances in the theoretical foundations of database systems (see http://www.sigmod.org/the-pods-pages). For the 30th edition, original research papers providing new insights in the specification, design, or implementation of data-management tools are called for. We especially welcome papers addressing such insights in emerging database environments and applications.</s>
    <s>Topics of Interest</s>
    <s>Topics that fit the interests of the symposium include the following (as they pertain to databases):</s>
    <s>languages for semi-structured data (including XML and RDF);</s>
    <s>search query languages (including techniques from information retrieval);</s>
    <s>distributed and parallel aspects of databases (including cloud computing);</s>
    <s>dynamic aspects of databases (updates, views, real-time and sensor data, approximate query answering, data streams);</s>
    <s>incompleteness, inconsistency, and uncertainty in databases;</s>
    <s>schema and query extraction;</s>
    <s>data integration;</s>
    <s>data exchange;</s>
    <s>metadata management;</s>
    <s>semantic-Web data and ontologies;</s>
    <s>data mining and machine learning techniques for databases;</s>
    <s>constraints (specification, reasoning, mining, constraint databases);</s>
    <s>privacy and security;</s>
    <s>Web services;</s>
    <s>automatic verification of database-driven systems;</s>
    <s>model theory, logics, algebras and computational complexity;</s>
    <s>data modeling;</s>
    <s>data structures and algorithms for data management;</s>
    <s>design, semantics, and optimization of query and database languages;</s>
    <s>domain-specific databases (multi-media, scientific, spatial, temporal, text).</s>
    <s>Best Paper Award: An award will be given to the best submission, as judged by the PC.</s>
    <s>Best Student Paper Award: There will also be an award for the best submission, as judged by the PC, written exclusively by a student or students. An author is considered as a student if at the time of submission, the author is enrolled in a program at a university or institution leading to a doctoral/master's/bachelor's degree.</s>
    <s>The PC reserves the right to give both awards to the same paper, not to give an award, or to split an award among several papers. Papers authored or co-authored by PC members are not eligible for an award.</s>
    <s>Submission Guidelines</s>
    <s>Submitted papers should be at most twelve pages, including bibliography, using reasonable page layout and font size of at least 9pt (note that the SIGMOD style file does not have to be followed). Additional details may be included in an appendix, which, however, will be read at the discretion of the PC. Papers longer than twelve pages (excluding the appendix) or in font size smaller than 9pt risk rejection without consideration of their merits.</s>
    <s>The submission process will be through the Website. Note that, unlike the SIGMOD conference, PODS does not use double-blind reviewing, and therefore PODS submissions should be eponymous (i.e., the names and affiliations of authors should be listed on the paper).</s>
    <s>The results must be unpublished and not submitted elsewhere, including the formal proceedings of other symposia or workshops. Authors of an accepted paper will be expected to sign copyright release forms, and one author is expected to present it at the conference.</s>
    <s>Submission instructions.</s>
    <s>PODS CfP</s>
    <s>PODS call for papers in PDF format.</s>
  </text>
</page>
