<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.itsmfi.org/content/itsmf-norway-2012-conference-call-papers</url>
  <title>itSMF Norway 2012 Conference - Call for Papers | itSMF ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>itSMF Norway 2012 Conference - Call for Papers. Posted August 15th, 2011 by ChrisR. in. Chapter Event &middot; Norway. The itSMF Norway 2012 Conference is </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Skip to Main Content</s>
    <s>About Us</s>
    <s>IEB News</s>
    <s>Chapter Info</s>
    <s>Chapter News</s>
    <s>ITIL® V3 Qualification Guidance</s>
    <s>The purpose of this document is to inform all parties interested in ITIL qualifications ..Read More</s>
    <s>Link to: Official ITIL Website**</s>
    <s>User login</s>
    <s>Username: *</s>
    <s>Password: *</s>
    <s>Create new account</s>
    <s>Request new password</s>
    <s>Recent posts</s>
    <s>itSMF Norway 2012 Conference - Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Posted August 15th, 2011 by ChrisR</s>
    <s>Chapter Event</s>
    <s>The itSMF Norway 2012 Conference is taking place on 14th &amp; 15th March 2012 at the Clarion Hotel at Oslo Airport.</s>
    <s>Would you like to be a speaker? - or do you know anyone who ought to give a presentation?</s>
    <s>We want to hear from you if you would like to give a presentation at Scandinavia's largest IT Service Management conferenceOr if you know of anyone we ought to invite to give a talk.</s>
    <s>We are looking for speakers who can share their knowledge and practical experience of IT Service Management and address issues such as how to get started, what strategies bring success, what mistakes have we learned the most from, etc. We are particularly on the lookout for good examples of users' practical experiences. Our participants would also like to hear some less than successful stories - especially if something can be learned from them.</s>
    <s>As in previous years, the conference will include plenum presentations, parallel sessions and workshops aimed at:</s>
    <s>• those of you just getting started with ITIL and IT Service Management</s>
    <s>• those of you looking to learn from the practical experience of others</s>
    <s>• those of you seeking a greater understanding, professional refreshers and inspiration</s>
    <s>• top management and IT services managers</s>
    <s>We are looking for presentations covering all aspects of ITIL and Service Management, and in particular:</s>
    <s>• Practical experience in the application of ITIL, Service Management and Lean</s>
    <s>• The environmental benefits of good processes (Green IT)</s>
    <s>• Business strategy, the IT area and IT governance</s>
    <s>• Gains realisation and financial management</s>
    <s>• Transition area processes</s>
    <s>• The relationship between development and day-­‐to-­‐day operations</s>
    <s>• Continuous service improvement</s>
    <s>• Personnel and restructuring; change management</s>
    <s>• Knowledge management </s>
    <s>The deadline for receiving submissions is 3rd October 2011</s>
    <s>For further details please download the attached PDF or if you have any questions, please contact: Silje Endsjø (E-Mail: silje.endsjo@itsmf.no / tel. +47 22 36 48 94).</s>
    <s>Call for paper itSMF Norway Conference2012 english.pdf</s>
    <s>284.31 KB</s>
    <s>Qualifications News</s>
    <s>The ITIL V3 Managing across the Lifecycle (MALC) Survey</s>
    <s>ITIL® V3 Master Qualification</s>
    <s>Publications News</s>
    <s>itSMF International Publications Survey</s>
    <s>itSMF UK and TSO announce a new edition of the Foundation Handbook</s>
    <s>Future Events</s>
    <s>itSMF Spain 2011 Conference</s>
    <s>24 October 2011</s>
    <s>itSMF UK 2011 Conference</s>
    <s>07 November 2011</s>
    <s>itSMF Czech Republic 2011 Conference - How to draw the business in IT management</s>
    <s>09 November 2011</s>
    <s>itSMF France 2011 Conference</s>
    <s>29 November 2011</s>
    <s>8th itSMF Japan Conference &amp; itSMF Japan EXPO 2011</s>
    <s>30 November 2011</s>
    <s>Seminar: Service Level Management: Achieving and Maintaining Service Excellence using Service Levels</s>
    <s>07 December 2011</s>
    <s>itSMF Norway 2012 Conference - Simply the best with ITIL</s>
    <s>14 March 2012</s>
    <s>itSMF Belgium 2012 Conference - Live the Business</s>
    <s>15 March 2012</s>
    <s>Details, and more events</s>
    <s>itSMF® International is a not-for-profit organisation and a prominent player in the on-going development and promotion of IT Service Management &quot;best practice&quot;, ITIL standards and qualifications.</s>
    <s>*August 15th, 2011: 2011-08-15T11:40:27+0000</s>
  </text>
</page>
