<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.ieeeisi.org/call_for_papers.html</url>
  <title>Call For Papers | 2011 IEEE International Conference on ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>papers in English must be submitted electronically via the conference Web site. The accepted papers from ISI 2010 and its affiliated workshops will be published </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Conference Program</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Important Dates</s>
    <s>Hotel &amp; Location</s>
    <s>Beijing Attractions</s>
    <s>Hosts &amp; Sponsors</s>
    <s>Organizing Committee</s>
    <s>Program Committee</s>
    <s>Contact Information</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>IEEE International Conference on Intelligence and Security Informatics (ISI 2011)</s>
    <s>!arrowJuly 10-12, 2011 Beijing, China</s>
    <s>THEME: Cyber-Physical-Social System Security</s>
    <s>HOST: The Chinese Academy of Sciences and University of Arizona</s>
    <s>Intelligence and Security Informatics (ISI) research is an interdisciplinary research field involving academic researchers in information technologies, computer science, public policy, bioinformatics, medical informatics, and social and behavior studies as well as local, state, and federal law enforcement and intelligence experts, and information technology industry consultants and practitioners to support counterterrorism and homeland security missions of anticipation, interdiction, prevention, preparedness and response to terrorist acts. The annual IEEE International ISI Conference series (http://www.isiconference.org/) was started in 2003, and the first eight meetings were held in Tucson, AZ (twice); Atlanta, GA; San Diego, CA; New Brunswick, NJ; Taipei, Taiwan; Dallas, TX; and Vancouver, Canada. Proceedings of these ISI meetings and workshops have been published by IEEE Press and in the Springer Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNCS) series.</s>
    <s>!arrowISI 2011 will be organized in three main streams focusing on</s>
    <s>Information Sharing and Data/Text Mining,</s>
    <s>Infrastructure Protection and Emergency Responses,</s>
    <s>Terrorism Informatics, and</s>
    <s>Enterprise Risk Management and Information Systems Security</s>
    <s>!arrowFor information see Topics, instructions and template information can soon be found on the submissions page.</s>
    <s>In conjunction with ISI 2011, several workshops will be held on July 10, 2011. The currently committed ones include (1) the 2011 Pacific Asia Workshop on Intelligence and Security Informatics (PAISI), (2) the International Workshop on Social Computing (SoCo), and (3) the International Workshop on Biosurveillance and Biosecurity (BioSecure). In addition, the First International Symposium on System Informatics and Engineering, which will be held on July 11-13, 2011, in Qingdao, China, is also an event affiliated with ISI 2011. Workshop proposals are welcome.</s>
    <s>Important Dates</s>
    <s>The paper submission due date for the main ISI 2011 event is March 15, 2011. Notification of acceptance: April 22, 2011 ; Camera ready copy due: April 29, 2011 . The due date for Tutorial/ Workshop proposals is March 1, 2011.</s>
    <s>Paper Submission</s>
    <s>Submission file formats are PDF and Microsoft Word. Required Word/LaTeX templates (IEEE two-column format) can be found at the conference Web site. Long (6,000 words, 6 pages max.) and short (3000 words, 3 pages max.) papers in English must be submitted electronically via the conference Web site. The accepted papers from ISI 2010 and its affiliated workshops will be published by the IEEE Press in a formal Proceedings. IEEE ISI Proceedings are EI-indexed. Authors who wish to present a poster and/or demo may submit a 1-page extended abstract, which, if selected, will appear in Proceedings. The selected IEEE ISI 2011 best papers will be invited for contribution to the new Springer Security Informatics journal.</s>
    <s>Proposals for tutorials and special-topic workshops in any areas of Intelligence and Security Informatics research and practice are welcome. Such events will be an integral part of the ISI-2010 conference program. Proposals in PDF or Microsoft Word not exceeding 3 pages should be emailed to the conference organizing committee at zeng@email.arizona.edu by February 10, 2011 and contain the following information.</s>
    <s>Title of tutorial/workshop</s>
    <s>Preferred duration</s>
    <s>Information about instructor(s)/organizer(s)</s>
    <s>Objectives to be achieved</s>
    <s>Scope of topics to be covered</s>
    <s>Target audience and evidence of interest (for tutorials)</s>
    <s>Target audience and the list of potential presenters/contributors (for workshops)</s>
    <s>© 2010-2011 hosted by the Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences</s>
  </text>
</page>
