<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://theritualyear.wordpress.com/2010-conference/</url>
  <title>2011 conference call for papers | The Ritual Year</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>CALL FOR PAPERS. SEVENTH ANNUAL CONFERENCE OF THE SIEF WORKING GROUP ON THE RITUAL YEAR 60th ANNIVERSARY OF THE INSTITUTE </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>The Ritual Year</s>
    <s>Skip to content</s>
    <s>2011 conference call for papers</s>
    <s>The Ritual Year 1 (2006)</s>
    <s>The Ritual Year 2</s>
    <s>Committee &amp; Advisory Board</s>
    <s>Contacting The Ritual Year</s>
    <s>Diary &amp; Information</s>
    <s>2011 conference call for papers</s>
    <s>CALL FOR PAPERS</s>
    <s>SEVENTH ANNUAL CONFERENCE OF THE SIEF WORKING GROUP ON THE RITUAL YEAR</s>
    <s>60th ANNIVERSARY OF THE INSTITUTE OF SLOVENIAN ETHNOLOGY SRC SASA (1951 – 2011)</s>
    <s>Researchers and Performers Co-Designing Heritage</s>
    <s>to be held in Ljubljana, Slovenia</s>
    <s>on 10th – 13th November 2011</s>
    <s>Dear Colleague,</s>
    <s>In the name of the Institute of Slovenian Ethnology, Scientific Research Center, Slovenian Academy of Sciences and Arts, and the SIEF Working Group on The Ritual Year, we have the honour to invite you to Ljubljana (Slovenia) for the seventh annual conference of the ritual year working group.</s>
    <s>Researchers and Performers Co-designing Heritage</s>
    <s>In this conference, we would like to focus on the triad: performances, performers, and researchers. Researchers so far have discovered that all these parts of the triad in the field are interconnected and in interplay. But researchers are not the only ones researching the folk culture: performers also study, read the folklore studies, and seek contacts with researchers. In this frame, we would like to research and test Ronald Hutton’s thesis about reactivity and reflexivity as an important part of the researcher-performer relationship. The most recent issues are the question of designing and performing cultural heritage on the one hand, and the frame of UNESCO’s definition on the other.</s>
    <s>The conference will bring together the researchers’ and the performers’ points of view in order to explore the ways they shape and co-design the rituals, both in theory and in practice. Academic and non-academic interpretations will be compared to improve our understanding of ritual performances as cultural heritage. The role of institutions (for cultural heritage) organizing the study of folklore for performers and providing direct contact between researchers and performers will also be explored.</s>
    <s>The following issues will specially be discussed:</s>
    <s>-  contacts between researchers and performers and their viewpoints,</s>
    <s>-  negotiation strategies and transfer of knowledge between performers and researchers,</s>
    <s>-  reflexivity and reactivity, main characteristics of the researchers-performers relationship?</s>
    <s>-  performers as domestic researchers and as a link between performances and researchers,</s>
    <s>-  performers, performances, researchers, and the UNESCO designation of cultural heritage,</s>
    <s>-  cultural institutions, training the folklore performers,</s>
    <s>-  etc.</s>
    <s>Papers are invited on:</s>
    <s>A. The interplay and transfer of knowledge between performers and researchers.</s>
    <s>B. Co-designing ritual performance, co-designing cultural heritage.</s>
    <s>C. Any other subject concerning the theory or practice of the ritual year is also welcome.</s>
    <s>Studies connected with modern rituals as well as comparative studies are welcome. These and many other topics related to the ritual year will be discussed during the conference.</s>
    <s>The language of presentations at the conference will be English, but discussion may take place also in other languages with the help of colleagues prepared to offer instant translation.</s>
    <s>Proposals for contributions to this conference are invited from all around the world. The presentations will normally be allowed 30 (20+10) minutes, including discussion.</s>
    <s>If you are interested in offering a paper, please send the following information to both of the addresses below:</s>
    <s>Laurent Sébastien Fournier : laurent.fournier@univ-nantes.fr</s>
    <s>Jurij Fikfak: jurij.fikfak@zrc-sazu.si</s>
    <s>1. Paper title and the section (A, B or C) into which it falls.</s>
    <s>2. An abstract in English of 100-120 words.</s>
    <s>3. Name (with your family name in capital letters), affiliation, postal address, e-mail address, phone and fax numbers.</s>
    <s>The deadline for submission of titles is 1 September 2010, of abstracts 1 February 2011.</s>
    <s>The Conference Committee will respond with acceptance or rejection of your paper in April 2011.</s>
    <s>Selected film/movie productions will be presented. More details will be given in the first circular, but those interested are welcome to send suggestions to the organizers when submitting the abstract.</s>
    <s>Conference Programme.</s>
    <s>The first evening on November 10th: plenary lecture and reception.</s>
    <s>On November 11th: excursion to wine areas in the southern part of Slovenia, visiting some museums, talking to local wine producers and representatives, with light dinner and wine ceremonial.</s>
    <s>On November 12th and 13th: conference sessions.</s>
    <s>The Institute of Slovenian Ethnology, Scientific Research Center, Slovenian Academy of Sciences and Arts (http://isn.zrc-sazu.si/) was established in 1951 as the central institution for archiving, collecting, and researching folk culture. The first three research themes were folk narrative (Milko Matičetov), rituals, and folk theatre (Niko Kuret).</s>
    <s>The Ritual Year Working Group (www.theritualyear.com) was established in 2004 under the aegis of SIEF, Société Internationale d’Ethnologie et de Folklore (www.siefhome.org). The Executive Board consists of Emily Lyle (President), Irina Sedakova (Secretary) and Aude Le Borgne (Treasurer).</s>
    <s>The conference will take place at Novi trg 4, Ljubljana</s>
    <s>http://www.itis.si/Page Map.aspx?X=462040&amp;Y=100501&amp;n=ZNANSTVENORAZISKOVALNI%20CENTER%20SAZU%20ZALO%C5%BDBA%20ZRC&amp;a=Novi%20trg%202,%20Ljubljana&amp;p=&amp;t=&amp;r=0.6838028435853297&amp;pid=4636970</s>
    <s>Accommodation: Our suggestion is Hotel Emonec , single use 55€, double use 80€, breakfast included. Please note that a whole range of other hotels between 60€ and 100€ can be found in Ljubljana. There are also some alternative solutions, hostels between 30€ and 50€: http://www.tripadvisor.com/Hotels-g274873-c3-Ljubljana-Hotels.html</s>
    <s>Excursion would be about 60€ per person (light dinner is included).</s>
    <s>Conference fee would be about 80€ per person including the costs of publication.</s>
    <s>In the neighbourhood there are a lot of nice restaurants, cafés, etc.</s>
    <s>There are some possibilities to get the accommodation through the academy exchange; you should investigate the possibility at your domestic academy and send the application to the organizers with a short abstract before September 1st 2010.</s>
    <s>Papers from the conference will go through a peer review process:</s>
    <s>Papers on the main theme will be published in 2012 in Performers and Researchers Co-Designing Heritage (Ritual year 7) as a special edition (supplementa) within Institute of Slovenian Ethnology publications. Other papers will be published in the journal Traditiones .</s>
    <s>Further information will follow.</s>
    <s>We look forward to see you in Slovenia !</s>
    <s>Assist. Prof. Laurent Sébastien FOURNIER, PhD Assist. Prof. Jurij Fikfak, PhD</s>
    <s>University of Nantes (France) ZRC-SAZU Ljubljana (Slovenia)</s>
    <s>laurent.fournier@univ-nantes.fr jurij.fikfak@zrc-sazu.si</s>
    <s>Comments are closed.</s>
    <s>Search for:</s>
    <s>Recent Posts</s>
    <s>Autumn Meeting information</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Photos from 2010 Conference</s>
    <s>2011 Conference</s>
    <s>Conference Information</s>
    <s>Log in</s>
    <s>Entries RSS</s>
    <s>Comments RSS</s>
    <s>Conference Photos</s>
    <s>More Photos</s>
    <s>2011 conference call for papers</s>
    <s>The Ritual Year 1 (2006)</s>
    <s>The Ritual Year 2</s>
    <s>Committee &amp; Advisory Board</s>
    <s>Contacting The Ritual Year</s>
    <s>Diary &amp; Information</s>
    <s>Andres' photo gallery, 2010 Conference</s>
    <s>August 2010</s>
    <s>June 2010</s>
    <s>April 2010</s>
    <s>Email Subscription</s>
    <s>Enter your email address to subscribe to this blog and receive notifications of new posts by email.</s>
    <s>Join 5 other followers</s>
    <s>Category Cloud</s>
    <s>Conference Information Photos Uncategorized</s>
    <s>Andres' photo gallery, 2010 Conference</s>
    <s>The Ritual Year</s>
    <s>Theme: Twenty Ten Blog at WordPress.com.</s>
    <s>Follow The Ritual Year</s>
    <s>Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.</s>
    <s>Join 5 other followers</s>
    <s>Powered by WordPress.com</s>
    <s>*RSS: Really Simple Syndication</s>
  </text>
</page>
