<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.himss.org/ASP/proposalsHome.asp</url>
  <title>Annual Conference Call for Proposals - HIMSS</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Our Annual Conference Education Committee (ACEC), consisting of 12 appointed volunteers from all membership constituencies, carefully designs the program </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Visit these other HIMSS sites: select one HIMSS Europe HIMSS Asia Pacific HIMSS Middle East HIMSS Analytics HIMSS Foundation Government Health IT News</s>
    <s>Member Center</s>
    <s>Advocacy &amp; Public Policy</s>
    <s>Vendor Center</s>
    <s>Press Room</s>
    <s>HIMSS Blog</s>
    <s>Home | About HIMSS | Contact Us | Member Login</s>
    <s>Skip Top Navigation</s>
    <s>News &amp; Research</s>
    <s>HIMSS News</s>
    <s>Corporate Member News</s>
    <s>Healthcare IT News</s>
    <s>Government Health IT News</s>
    <s>Industry Research</s>
    <s>HIMSS Analytics</s>
    <s>HIMSS State Dashboard</s>
    <s>Free Industry Reports</s>
    <s>Grant Research</s>
    <s>Topics &amp; Tools</s>
    <s>Meaningful Use</s>
    <s>Electronic Health Record</s>
    <s>Healthcare Reform</s>
    <s>Patient Safety &amp; Quality Outcomes</s>
    <s>Ambulatory IS</s>
    <s>More Topics </s>
    <s>Professional Development</s>
    <s>Professional Certification</s>
    <s>Davies Award</s>
    <s>Stage 7 Award</s>
    <s>Member Advancement</s>
    <s>Career Services</s>
    <s>HLA Competency Directory</s>
    <s>Emerging Professionals</s>
    <s>Conference &amp; Events</s>
    <s>HIMSS Calendar of Events</s>
    <s>HIMSS12 Annual Conference &amp; Exhibition</s>
    <s>World of Health IT</s>
    <s>HIMSS AsiaPac</s>
    <s>Europe Health IT Leadership Summit</s>
    <s>Middle East Health IT Leadership Summit &amp; Conference</s>
    <s>National Health IT Week</s>
    <s>HIMSS Virtual Conference &amp; Expo</s>
    <s>Government Health IT Conference &amp; Exhibition</s>
    <s>Revenue Cycle Summit</s>
    <s>Annual Conference Call for Proposals</s>
    <s>Annual Conference Call for Reviewers</s>
    <s>Individual Membership</s>
    <s>Online Membership</s>
    <s>Affiliate Membership</s>
    <s>Corporate Membership</s>
    <s>Organizational Affiliate</s>
    <s>REC Affiliate Membership</s>
    <s>Special Interest Groups</s>
    <s>Users Groups</s>
    <s>HIMSS EHRA</s>
    <s>Communities of Profession</s>
    <s>HIMSS Latino Community</s>
    <s>Nursing Informatics Community</s>
    <s>Physician Community</s>
    <s>Senior Executive Community</s>
    <s>ME-PI Community</s>
    <s>Federal Health Community</s>
    <s>HIMSS Store</s>
    <s>Professional Development &gt; Education &gt; HIMSS Annual Conference &gt;</s>
    <s>2012 Annual HIMSS Conference &amp; Exhibition Call for Proposals</s>
    <s>2012 Annual HIMSS Conference &amp; Exhibition Call for Proposals</s>
    <s>The HIMSS12 Call for Proposal is now closed .</s>
    <s>View the HIMSS12 Open Forum recording. The open forum provides additional information and discussion regarding how to submit a HIMSS 12 Call for Proposal.</s>
    <s>Jointly sponsored byand !, the Annual HIMSS Conference &amp; Exhibition provides world-class health IT and management systems education. Our Annual Conference Education Committee (ACEC), consisting of 12 appointed volunteers from all membership constituencies, carefully designs the program to meet the needs of our audience.</s>
    <s>Each year, HIMSS's Annual Conference offers over 200 general education sessions that are selected from a peer-reviewed process. To ensure that our program's content is timely, relevant, and optimally targeting our attendees' needs, the ACEC selects from the submissions received during the &quot;Call for Proposals&quot; and may supplement programming by inviting speakers to fill any gaps identified.</s>
    <s>And in response to the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 which includes billions of dollars in Medicare and Medicaid incentive payments to providers and hospitals who demonstrate &quot;Meaningful Use&quot; of certified health IT products as defined through the publication of proposed rules in March 2010, HIMSS' welcomes and will give preference to abstracts that demonstrate the adoption of healthcare information technology in support of the roadmap towards meaningful use. For HIMSS12, our focus continues on the &quot;demonstration&quot; of what has been accomplished.</s>
    <s>&quot;In addition, HIMSS will give preference to abstracts that demonstrate the adoption and optimal use of healthcare information technology and management systems. Our real-world, practical focus is on what stakeholders have accomplished in care coordination &amp; outcomes improvement; workflow, administrative and cost-efficiencies; etc. We are particularly interested in case studies highlighting best practices; beneficial uses of IT for patient and population health; increased effectiveness and efficiency in the provision and payment of care; leadership; challenges, opportunities, and unintended consequences; and change management.  These will make for excellent sessions that will equip our attendees to realize transformative change through the best use of IT and management systems.&quot;</s>
    <s>In the late spring of each year, HIMSS receives many general education session proposals via the online Call for Proposal process. Using ACEC appointees as subject matter leaders, HIMSS engages over 200 volunteer subject matter experts to review all of the proposals. All HIMSS members are welcomed and encouraged to volunteer as a reviewer.</s>
    <s>To ensure a fair assessment, every single proposal is evaluated by a minimum of three volunteer reviewers. Led by ACEC members, review teams meet throughout the summer months to evaluate proposals. Proposals are evaluated based upon several criteria, and an observer from the Postgraduate Institute for Medicine (PIM) ensures that our process and selections exceed the standards required for continuing medical and nursing education credits.</s>
    <s>As a result of this thorough evaluation process, the ACEC selects initial proposals in early Fall. To ensure the optimal timeliness and relevance of the subject, speakers are immediately notified of the ACEC's decision. Those selected are provided with nearly four months to submit a first-draft presentation. At the end of the calendar year, ACEC appointees review the drafts to make sure that the most up-to-date and relevant information is included in each presentation. PIM also performs its final assessment at this juncture, assigning CME and/or CNE credits, as appropriate.</s>
    <s>One month prior to Annual Conference, final presentations are due to HIMSS. Within this ever changing dynamic industry of health IT and management systems, this process presents the best practice on ensuring optimal, world-class education sessions.</s>
    <s>HIMSS12 Call for Proposals Deadlines 2011-2012</s>
    <s>March 21 - HIMSS12 Call for Proposals and Call for Reviewers open via Web site</s>
    <s>April - How to Submit a Call for Proposal</s>
    <s>May 23 - HIMSS12 Call for Proposals and Call for Reviewers Close</s>
    <s>May 27 - Reviewers notified of acceptance and assigned duties</s>
    <s>June 6 - Reviewers read and evaluate proposals via review site</s>
    <s>August 1-12 - Reviewers and ACEC members discuss via audio conference proposal selections</s>
    <s>August - ACEC Committee members meet to schedule final program selection</s>
    <s>September - October - Speaker orientation webinars for speakers and reviewers</s>
    <s>September - October - Accepted proposal objectives sent to CE provider for review</s>
    <s>October - Revised objectives sent back to speakers (if needed)</s>
    <s>November 7 - Conflict of Interest forms and Publication Forms due</s>
    <s>November 14 - First draft of e-sessions materials due</s>
    <s>November 14 - 28 - E-sessions reviewed</s>
    <s>November 28 - Dec 5 - E-session presentation revision (if necessary)</s>
    <s>December 5 - 12 - E-session review by CE provider</s>
    <s>December 12 - E-sessions to recording studio</s>
    <s>December 19 - First draft of presentation materials due to reviewer and HIMSS</s>
    <s>Dec 19, 2011 - Jan 3, 2012 - Review of presentations; comments sent back to presenters</s>
    <s>January 3 - 16 - Presenter revision of presentations (if necessary)</s>
    <s>January 17 - Final speaker presentation materials due</s>
    <s>January 17 - All presentations to CE provider for review</s>
    <s>February 20 - 24 - 2012 Annual HIMSS Conference &amp; Exhibition, Las Vegas</s>
    <s>If you have any questions regarding involvement in this process, please feel free to email your questions to Deb Clough, Manager of Annual Conference Education, at dclough@himss.org.</s>
    <s>Share |</s>
    <s>(C) Healthcare Information and Management Systems | Privacy Policy | Advertise</s>
    <s>HIMSS, 33 West Monroe Street, Suite 1700, Chicago, IL 60603-5616</s>
    <s>Phone: (312) 664-4467 Fax: (312) 664-6143</s>
    <s>Contact the Webmaster</s>
  </text>
</page>
