<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.apsanet.org/content_18327.cfm</url>
  <title>Teaching and Learning Conference Call for Proposals | APSA</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Teaching and Learning Conference Call for Proposals during which paper presenters and conference discussants can interact on a sustained basis focused </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>!Founded 1903</s>
    <s>Login or create account</s>
    <s>About APSA</s>
    <s>Core Objectives**</s>
    <s>Leadership &amp; Governance**</s>
    <s>APSA Staff Directory**</s>
    <s>Centennial Center for Political Science**</s>
    <s>Assn &amp; Discipline News**</s>
    <s>What is Political Science?**</s>
    <s>Employment at APSA**</s>
    <s>Individual Members**</s>
    <s>Departmental Members**</s>
    <s>Organized Section Membership**</s>
    <s>Frequently Asked Questions**</s>
    <s>Membership News**</s>
    <s>Annual Meeting**</s>
    <s>Teaching and Learning Conference**</s>
    <s>Africa Workshops**</s>
    <s>Conference for Chairs**</s>
    <s>Other Conferences in Political Science**</s>
    <s>Conference Papers**</s>
    <s>Future APSA Annual Meetings**</s>
    <s>Past APSA Annual Meetings**</s>
    <s>Congressional Fellowship Program**</s>
    <s>Education and Professional Programs**</s>
    <s>Departmental Services**</s>
    <s>International Programs**</s>
    <s>Minority and Diversity Programs**</s>
    <s>Small Research Grant**</s>
    <s>Teaching and Learning Conference**</s>
    <s>Constitution Day**</s>
    <s>Civic Education**</s>
    <s>Internationalizing the Undergraduate Curriculum in Political Science**</s>
    <s>Service Learning**</s>
    <s>Teaching Awards**</s>
    <s>Order Form</s>
    <s>APSA Journals**</s>
    <s>Career Publications**</s>
    <s>Publishing, Research, and the Discipline**</s>
    <s>Teaching Publications**</s>
    <s>Publications for Departments**</s>
    <s>Permissions Requests**</s>
    <s>Task Force Reports**</s>
    <s>APSA Governance Reports**</s>
    <s>Online Job Lists**</s>
    <s>Articles and Books**</s>
    <s>Job Candidate Questions to Ask (JCQ) Program**</s>
    <s>Careers In Political Science**</s>
    <s>American Politics**</s>
    <s>Canadian Politics and Elections**</s>
    <s>Graduate Students**</s>
    <s>Political Science Organizations**</s>
    <s>Professional Journals and Publications**</s>
    <s>Grants in the Discipline**</s>
    <s>Research in Progress**</s>
    <s>Discussion Lists**</s>
    <s>Data on the Profession**</s>
    <s>Key Issues**</s>
    <s>Booklist: Upcoming Publications**</s>
    <s>Conference Papers</s>
    <s>Join/Renew NowContributeContact APSA</s>
    <s>Teaching and Learning Conference</s>
    <s>The 2012 APSA Teaching and Learning Conference will be held in Washington, DC, February 17-19, 2012.</s>
    <s>Early registration will open in mid October 2011. Like presenters, discussants register for and follow a single track and should stay with their chosen track for the duration of the conference. Space in each track is limited; discussant slots are available on a first-come-first-serve basis until filled.</s>
    <s>The deadline to submit a proposal has passed.</s>
    <s>Login to submit</s>
    <s>Forgot password or login? New user?</s>
    <s>Using a working-group model, the conference provides a forum to develop models on teaching and learning as well as to discuss broad themes and values affecting political science education. The conference is organized into 12 tracks constructed around specific themes, during which paper presenters and conference discussants can interact on a sustained basis focused on a track theme. In addition to the working groups, the conference features workshops that focus on practical issues related to teaching. Proposals are welcome for paper presentations and workshop presentations on the themes listed below for each category.</s>
    <s>Paper Themes</s>
    <s>The meeting consists of 12 tracks**constructed around these themes:</s>
    <s>Civic Engagement</s>
    <s>Conflict and Conflict Resolution (new)</s>
    <s>Core Curriculum/General Education</s>
    <s>Diversity, Inclusiveness, and Equality</s>
    <s>Curricular and Program Assessment</s>
    <s>Graduate Education</s>
    <s>Integrating Technology into the Classroom</s>
    <s>Internationalizing the Curriculum</s>
    <s>Simulations and Role Play</s>
    <s>Teaching and Learning at Community College (new)</s>
    <s>Teaching Political Theory and Theories</s>
    <s>Teaching Research Methods</s>
    <s>Within the working groups, paper presenters report on their original research as part of a sustained and extended presentation, conversation, and discussion. Individuals interested in applying to present should submit a substantive proposal on an idea or model for teaching and learning in political science as it relates to one of the themes listed above.</s>
    <s>We especially welcome papers that incorporate the scholarship of teaching and learning (SoTL), methods of assessment, the use of technology, strategies for professional development, innovations in diversity and inclusiveness, and experiential learning (across all tracks). All papers should include original research, literature reviews, evaluation, hypothesis testing, analysis of results or other critical assessment.</s>
    <s>Paper Guidelines</s>
    <s>Each selected paper presentation:</s>
    <s>can have a maximum of two (2) presenting authors (although the number of non-presenting authors can exceed that)</s>
    <s>will be allotted an approximate 12-minute block for the author(s) to present--co-authors may divide or share presentation time but the total time for each presentation will not exceed 12 minutes.</s>
    <s>**(Themes may be split into more than one conference track.)</s>
    <s>Workshop Themes**</s>
    <s>Workshops focus on practical issues related to teaching and allow participants to interact with political scientists outside of their assigned conference track. The call for workshops includes the following themes:</s>
    <s>Civic Education and Engagement</s>
    <s>Classroom and Program Assessment</s>
    <s>Integrating Technology in the Classroom</s>
    <s>Professional Development</s>
    <s>Scholarship of Teaching and Learning</s>
    <s>Teaching Campaigns and Elections (new)</s>
    <s>Open Call</s>
    <s>Workshops present the participants with an opportunity to acquire a new pedagogical outlook or knowledge on a particular topic within teaching and learning. It is recommended that workshop presenters be prepared to present an interactive workshop that emphasizes audience involvement and demonstrations.</s>
    <s>The workshops are offered as an addition to the traditional working group model. Attendees will have the opportunity to attend at least two workshops in addition to their participation in a themed track.</s>
    <s>Workshop Guidelines</s>
    <s>Each selected workshop presentation:</s>
    <s>has no presenter maximum</s>
    <s>will be allotted an approximate 90-minute block ( the length of a track session ) to present.</s>
    <s>must be interactive</s>
    <s>Submit a Proposal</s>
    <s>When you are ready to submit a working group or workshop presentation proposal, login to MyAPSA and in the Teaching and Learning Conference area, select the &quot;Submit a proposal&quot; link.</s>
    <s>Log in to submit a proposal:</s>
    <s>New user? Forgot password or login?</s>
    <s>Review Process</s>
    <s>Paper and workshop proposals will be reviewed and selected in a peer-review process.</s>
    <s>Notification, Track Assignment and Paper Archive</s>
    <s>Notices for accepted and rejected paper and workshop presentations will be distributed via email in early October. Accepted paper presentations will be assigned to a specific track. Paper author(s) and workshop presenter(s) will have until the mid-October to accept or decline the invitation to present. Author(s) were required to post materials related to their presentation (i.e., completed papers, PowerPoint presentations, webpages, simulations, etc.) online by January 2011, so that all participants may review them prior to the meeting and fellow track participants may prepare comments.</s>
    <s>Registration and Attendance</s>
    <s>In keeping with the working group model, all meeting participants and discussants are expected to remain with their assigned track for the duration of the entire conference. Presenters are joined in these tracks by discussants.</s>
    <s>Registration will open in mid-October.</s>
    <s>Exhibit Information</s>
    <s>Exhibit, advertisiting and sponsorship opportunities are available.</s>
    <s>Questions? Please contact teaching@apsanet.org.</s>
    <s>(C) Copyright 2011 American Political Science Association (APSA)</s>
    <s>1527 New Hampshire Ave, NW Washington, DC 20036-1206</s>
    <s>Ph: (202) 483-2512 Fx: (202) 483-2657 E-Mail: apsa@apsanet.org</s>
  </text>
</page>
