<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://asq.org/conferences/stem-agenda/call-for-papers/index.html</url>
  <title>2011 ASQ STEM Agenda Conference - Call for Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>If you have a question, contact Conference@asqedu.org. Student Papers are welcome! National policy makes STEM a priority because the fields of science, </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>2011 ASQ STEM Agenda Conference</s>
    <s>July 19-20, 2011 • University of Wisconsin - Stout • Menomonie Wisconsin</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>General Information</s>
    <s>Travel Information</s>
    <s>Support/Exhibit Opportunities</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Submittal of Abstracts and Papers and Peer-Review Process for Papers</s>
    <s>Key Dates</s>
    <s>Papers Due May 10, 2011</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>!Advancing the STEM agenda in Education, the WOrkplace, and Society</s>
    <s>Advancing the STEM Agenda in Education, the Workplace and Society</s>
    <s>Co-Sponsored by the ASQ Education Division and the University of Wisconsin-Stout</s>
    <s>The Call for Abstracts are CLOSED. All authors who have submitted abstracts have been contacted as to the status of their abstracts. If you have a question, contact Conference@asqedu.org.</s>
    <s>Student Papers are welcome!</s>
    <s>National policy makes STEM a priority because the fields of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics are the basis of the evolving knowledge society.  The workplace is looking for qualified graduates and professionals in these fields in order to advance the technological advances that have made the United States the leader in so many areas.  Government sees participation and graduation in STEM courses as a means of fostering greater individual opportunities for gainful employment and advancement to go along the re-invigoration of the economy.  Finally, education at the K-12 and higher education levels is considering issues of curriculum content and linkage, instructional techniques, teacher preparation, transitions, and participation (how to improve student interest and engagement in these fields, and especially among underrepresented groups). </s>
    <s>Submit a paper and join us to network and advance ideas in support of STEM initiative in schools, colleges and universities and the workplace.</s>
    <s>Conference Tracks:      </s>
    <s>K-12 STEM          </s>
    <s>Higher Education STEM</s>
    <s>STEM Workforce Transition</s>
    <s>Who should apply?</s>
    <s>The conference invites teachers, education administrators, faculty members and students from education and the STEM fields, government officials and others to share their work, research or ideas. A complimentary conference registration will be given to the primary author of the paper, after the author(s)' paper is accepted in the peer-review process for one of the three conference tracks. Submitting an abstract is required prior to the submission of the paper for the peer-review.</s>
    <s>Papers are due by May 10, 2011.</s>
    <s>ASQ | (C) Copyright | Privacy Policy | Contact ASQ</s>
  </text>
</page>
