<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://igpa.uillinois.edu/press/march-conference-call-for-papers</url>
  <title>Call for Papers: IGPA/Chicago Fed conference on health care policy ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>The Health Policy and Social Policy programs at IGPA, in cooperation with the Chicago Federal Researve Bank, are planning a conference on health care policy </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>!Institute of Government and Public Affairs</s>
    <s>Sign Up For IGPA Updates Connect with IGPA</s>
    <s>About IGPA</s>
    <s>Contact Us</s>
    <s>IGPA Team</s>
    <s>Advisory Committee</s>
    <s>Wolff Internship</s>
    <s>Careers in Child and Family Policy</s>
    <s>Conference of Women Legislators</s>
    <s>Jane Addams Hull House</s>
    <s>Latino Caucus</s>
    <s>Union League Club</s>
    <s>United Counties Council</s>
    <s>By Research Area</s>
    <s>By Name</s>
    <s>Press Room</s>
    <s>In The News</s>
    <s>Latest Research</s>
    <s>For Reporters</s>
    <s>Flash Index</s>
    <s>Fiscal Futures</s>
    <s>Chicago Area Study</s>
    <s>Illinois Economic Review</s>
    <s>Trends in Racial Attitudes</s>
    <s>Opinion Monitor</s>
    <s>IGPA Annual Report</s>
    <s>Policy Forum</s>
    <s>Bazzani Lecture</s>
    <s>Douglas Ethics Award</s>
    <s>NEW Leadership Illinois</s>
    <s>IGPA State Summit</s>
    <s>Family Impact Seminars</s>
    <s>2011 Seminar</s>
    <s>2010 Seminar</s>
    <s>2009 Seminar</s>
    <s>Study Centers</s>
    <s>Regional Economics Applications Laboratory</s>
    <s>Office of Public Leadership</s>
    <s>Center for Prevention Research and Development</s>
    <s>Center for Public Safety and Justice</s>
    <s>Call for Papers: IGPA/Chicago Fed conference on health care policy</s>
    <s>The Health Policy and Social Policy programs at IGPA, in cooperation with the Chicago Federal Researve Bank, are planning a conference on health care policy next March in Chicago. The organizers have issued a call for papers to be presented at the conference.</s>
    <s>CALL FOR PAPERS</s>
    <s>The Institute of Government and Public Affairs of the University of Illinois</s>
    <s>The Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago</s>
    <s>New Perspectives on Health and Health Care Policy</s>
    <s>March 22-23, 2010</s>
    <s>The Institute of Government and Public Affairs of the University of Illinois and the Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago are hosting a conference, &quot;New Perspectives on Health and Health Care Policy,&quot; to be held March 22-23, 2010 at the Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago.</s>
    <s>Submission Deadline: November 1, 2009</s>
    <s>We invite scholars who are engaged all areas of health and health policy research to submit their work, though we are especially interested in topics that are under-researched or that present new ways to think about a particular problem. A few examples of priority research areas are:</s>
    <s>Cost shifting: What are the mechanisms by which hospitals shift costs between payers and what evidence is there to support claims that the uninsured impose significant costs on private payers?</s>
    <s>Prevention and primary care: What procedures and treatments are truly preventive and cost-effective, and does primary care deliver such treatment? Is primary care a substitute or complement with specialty and tertiary care?</s>
    <s>Insurance markets and competition: Is the health insurance market competitive? What effects would a so-called &quot;public option&quot; have on the private market? What effects would insurance market reform have on the long-term trajectory of health insurance costs and coverage?</s>
    <s>Early determinants of adult health: What is the relative importance of cognitive factors, non-cognitive factors and early health to adult health?</s>
    <s>Medical technology and research: What effect will comparative effectiveness research and electronic medical records have on the quality and cost of health care, and health?</s>
    <s>The conference will include a panel discussion on the current state of health care policy that features David Cutler, Otto Eckstein Professor of Applied Economics in the Department of Economics and Kennedy School of Government; and Mark Pauly, Bendheim Professor and Professor of Health Care Systems, Business and Public Policy, Insurance and Risk Management, and Economics at the Wharton School of the University of Pennsylvania</s>
    <s>Selection Process:</s>
    <s>Approximately 8-10 papers will be selected. The organizing committee will give priority to original research with direct public policy application. Participants will be selected on the basis of papers or extended abstracts of approximately 500 words. The conference will take place at the Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago and will run from roughly 1pm on March 22 to 2pm on March 23. The conference will pay travel and lodging expenses for one author of each paper.</s>
    <s>Submission Deadline: November 1, 2009</s>
    <s>Notification: November 15, 2009</s>
    <s>Please email your submissions to: lubotsky@illinois.edu</s>
    <s>Organizing Committee:</s>
    <s>Robert Kaestner, University of Illinois</s>
    <s>Darren Lubotsky, University of Illinois</s>
    <s>Bhashkar Mazumder, Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago</s>
    <s>Related Content</s>
    <s>Director Robert Rich comments on performance-based funding for universities</s>
    <s>IGPA's Jim Nowlan discusses prospects for Quinn vetoes in upcoming session</s>
    <s>IGPA's Kent Redfield comments on impact of Costello departure from Congress</s>
    <s>Search the webSearch igpa.uillinois.eduSearch igpa.uillinois.edu/library</s>
    <s>IGPA Site IGPA Library</s>
    <s>The State of the Illinois Economy</s>
    <s>Flash Index improves</s>
    <s>Upcoming Events</s>
    <s>Paul H. Douglas Education Lecture: Alan Simpson</s>
    <s>October 18, 2011 • 4:30pm</s>
    <s>IGPA Seminar on Social Science and Policy</s>
    <s>October 19, 2011 • 12:00pm</s>
    <s>Young Illini in Government and Politics: Brian Colgan</s>
    <s>October 24, 2011 • 7:00pm</s>
    <s>See More Events</s>
    <s>The Institute of Government and Public Affairs at the University of Illinois</s>
    <s>Urbana: 217-333-3340 Chicago: 312-996-6188 Springfield: 217-206-7080</s>
    <s>Copyright (C) 2009-2011, The Board of the Trustees of the University of Illinois</s>
    <s>This site is best viewed with Google Chrome, Firefox 3.x (or higher), IE 7.x (or higher), or Safari.</s>
    <s>Contact the Webmaster - Privacy Statement</s>
  </text>
</page>
