<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.amiaconference.com/2011/proposals_call.htm</url>
  <title>AMIA 2011 Conference: Call For Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>AMIA 2011. AMIA: Call For Sessions and Workshops Proposals. The AMIA Conference Committee invites submissions for session proposals for the 2011 </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>&gt; AMIA 2011</s>
    <s>AMIA: Call For Sessions</s>
    <s>and Workshops Proposals</s>
    <s>&gt; The AMIA Conference Committee invites submissions for session proposals for the 2011 Annual Conference in Austin, Texas.</s>
    <s>An important goal for the 2011 Conference is to present a balanced program - one that includes a wide variety of topics, cutting-edge discussions of technology, a balance of theory and practice, and invite new ideas and concepts that may stimulate additional interest, involvement and educational benefit. The program should address topics of concern to diverse perspectives and constituencies and to archivists at all levels of experience.</s>
    <s>&gt; The Conference Committee encourages papers, panels and posters on all issues to do with audiovisual archives.</s>
    <s>&gt; Please submit a developed proposal, including the names and contact information for each of the proposed speakers and an indication of their agreement to participate. Proposal submissions are adjudicated utilizing a Peer Review process. Incomplete session proposals that include only some of the speakers or that are missing information about speaker participation delete this are very difficult to assess when compared to complete proposals.</s>
    <s>&gt; Proposal submissions may include the following formats:</s>
    <s>REPORT/PAPER PRESENTATION. Fully prepared papers/reports of 15-30 minutes each and a comment-and-discussion period.</s>
    <s>PANEL DISCUSSION. Session consisting of a panel of three to four individuals (with a moderator or commentator making a total of no more than five participants) who informally discuss a variety of theories or perspectives on the given topic. 60 or 90 minute sessions.</s>
    <s>&gt; POSTER. Presentation to an audience who is walking through a hallway or exhibit. During poster sessions, the presenter usually stands next to the poster, allowing for attendees to engage in one-on-one discussions with the presenter.</s>
    <s>OTHER. If your proposed session is neither a Presentation nor Panel Discussion, you will be asked to describe your proposed format.</s>
    <s>WORKSHOP [Submit via Workshop Proposal Form only]: Limited-enrollment session of half day or full day, usually designed to teach or refine skills.</s>
    <s>SESSION REQUIREMENTS</s>
    <s>&gt; The Proposal Form will ask for you to list any other requirements for your session. This may list include special av equipment, handouts, flipcharts, travel funding for speakers. It must include all requests - this will be the only opportunity to make special requests of this type.</s>
    <s>If you are requesting additional funding of any kind it is important that you note whether or not you will be able to proceed with the session should the funding you have requested not be available. You will be asked to provide a detailed estimate of each expense requested.</s>
    <s>Please note: Speakers or other participants in the program must register and secure institutional or personal funding. AMIA travel funding is extremely limited, and while you may request funding for speakers it is important that your proposal is not reliant on travel funding. Important note about travel funding - acceptance of your proposal does not constitute agreement to funding.</s>
    <s>PLEASE NOTE</s>
    <s>The Conference Committee's task is to have a global vision to ensure a stimulating, balanced and professional program that will meet the diverse needs of our members. The Committee is unable to accept all proposals submitted; and, some individuals who propose sessions may be asked to revise their proposals to help meet the wider needs of the program.</s>
    <s>&gt; PROPOSAL DEADLINES</s>
    <s>&gt; AMIA Sessions</s>
    <s>&gt; May 10, 2011</s>
    <s>&gt; Workshops</s>
    <s>&gt; May 10, 2011</s>
    <s>PROPOSAL FORMS</s>
    <s>Once you've submitted your proposal you should see a &quot;Thank You For Submitting&quot; acknowledgement. If do not see the acknowledgement, please contact us.</s>
    <s>Because of the information necessary to complete the form, we recommend that you download a copy of the form (Session Proposal Form or Workshop Proposal form) so that you may review and prepare to fill out the online submission. All submissions must be made through the online system.</s>
    <s>All submissions must be made through the online system. Downloaded forms are for informational purposes only. If you have difficulty with the online submission process, please contact us.</s>
    <s>&gt; For more information about information requested on the proposal form, click here.</s>
    <s>&gt; !</s>
    <s>&gt; !</s>
    <s>&gt; You will be notified about your proposal no later than June 25, 2011.</s>
    <s>Thank you</s>
    <s>Copyright 2010. Association of Moving Image Archivists.</s>
  </text>
</page>
