<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.concurringopinions.com/archives/2011/04/classcrits-conference-call-for-papers.html</url>
  <title>Concurring Opinions » ClassCrits Conference Call for Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Apr 15, 2011 ClassCrits Conference Call for Papers. posted by The group has announced a call for papers for a September conference; here is the notice: </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Home | About | RSS Feed | Contact and Publicity Guidelines | Comment Policy</s>
    <s>the Law, the Universe, and Everything</s>
    <s>Slip Opinions</s>
    <s>Law comics: first copyright, now health. (fp)</s>
    <s>Zero-sum economics. (fp)</s>
    <s>The assault on breathing (safely). (fp)</s>
    <s>Should bankers fear SarBox and the Martin Act? (fp)</s>
    <s>Wake up, WaPo; SEC can't be saved by one person. (fp)</s>
    <s>Sheff on mutual mistake. (fp)</s>
    <s>America's banks support the troops. (fp)</s>
    <s>Job opportunities for countries without an EPA. (fp)</s>
    <s>Robert George goes off the deep end. Splash(kw)</s>
    <s>Accountancy firms finally meet their match? (fp)</s>
    <s>Our Podcast</s>
    <s>Subscribe to Law Talk</s>
    <s>Posts by Author</s>
    <s>Select Author Abigail MoncrieffAdam BenforadoAdam KolberAdam SteinmanAdam ThiererAlan ChenAlex KreitAlexander TsesisAlfred BrophyAlfred YenAlice RistrophAlicia KellyAllison DannerAmanda FrostAmanda PustilnikAmy KapczynskiAndrew MartinAndrew SutterAndrew TaslitzAngela Onwuachi-WilligAni SatzAnita KrishnakumarAnn BartowAnna SuAnup MalaniAnupam ChanderAri WaldmanBarbara van SchewickBD VitharanaBernadette MeylerBetsy MasielloBetty TorresBill Burke-WhiteBob HillmanBob SableBoston College Law ReviewBoston University Law ReviewBrandon BartelsBrannon DenningBrian FryeBrian KaltBruce BoydenBruce GreenCalifornia Law ReviewCarissa HessickCaroline Mala CorbinCarrie Menkel-MeadowCharles SullivanChimene KeitnerChristine FarleyChristine HurtColumbia Law ReviewCorey YungCornell Law ReviewCourtney JoslinCraig LivermoreDaithi Mac SithighDan FillerDaniel SoloveDanielle CitronDarian IbrahimDarren HutchinsonDave HoffmanDavid BollierDavid FagundesDavid FontanaDavid GrayDavid OpderbeckDavid PostDavid RobinsonDavid SchraubDavid SkoverDavid UdellDavid ZaringDeborah HellmanDeven DesaiDonald BramanDoug DePeppeDouglas NeJaimeDuke Law JournalEduardo PenalverElaine ChiuElizabeth NowickiElizabeth WeeksEmily ZackinEmory Law JournalEric GoldmanEric MullerEric ZumbachErica HashimotoErik LillquistErwin ChemerinskyFlorida Law ReviewFordham Law ReviewFrancesca BignamiFrank PasqualeFrank WuGaelle KrikorianGaia BernsteinGeoffrey RappGeorge ConkGeorge Washington Law ReviewGeorgetown Law JournalGerard MaglioccaGlenn CohenGordon HullGreg LastowkaGwendolyn MajetteHarry LewisHarvard Law ReviewHastings Law JournalHeather GarretsonHeidi KitrosserHelen NortonHervé Le CrosnierHosea HarveyHoward WassermanIowa Law ReviewIra LupuJack BalkinJack ChinJack LondenJacqueline LiptonJames B. SpetaJames GrimmelmannJamison ColburnJason MazzoneJaya Ramji-NogalesJeanne CharnJeff JonasJeffrey HarrisonJeffrey KahnJeffrey LipshawJeffrey SelbinJenia TurnerJennifer CollinsJennifer HendricksJeremy BlumenthalJessica EricksonJessica SilbeyJim BaillieJim GreinerJo-Ann WallaceJoel ReidenbergJohn DuffyJohn IpJohn JacobiJohn PollockJonathan HafetzJonathan LipsonJon SiegelJonathan ZittrainJoseph BlocherJoey FishkinJoseph LiuJosh BlackmanJosh ChafetzJoshua FairfieldJoy MosesJudd SneirsonJune CarboneJune Carbone and Naomi CahnKaimipono D. WengerKatherine StrandburgKathleen BoozangKevin JohnsonKevin MaillardKevin QuinnKim FerzanKristen OsengaKristin JohnsonLaura AbelLaura ApplemanLaura DeNardisLaura HeymannLawrence CunninghamLawrence SolumLea ShaverLeslie GriffinLinda McClainLisa FairfaxLori RinghandUniversity of Toronto Law JournalMarc PoirierMarc RoarkMarcus BoonMarcy PeekMargaret LewisMargaret MonsellMark AlexanderMark EdwardsMark GraberMark HallMarty GuggenheimMarvin AmmoriMary Anne FranksMary Schmid MerglerMatthew DowdMatthew ListerMatthew Reid KrellMatthew SagMax MinznerMaxine EichnerMelissa WatersMeredith HarbachMichael AbramowiczMichael FroomkinMichael HeiseMichael KangMichael MadisonMichael MillemannMichael PittsMichael SerotaMichael SirkinMichael ZimmerMichelle AdamsMichelle AndersonMichelle HarnerMichigan Law ReviewMiguel SchorMike DiminoMike O'SheaMike SeidmanMinnesota Law ReviewMiriam CherryMolly LandNancy KimNancy Levit and Douglas O. LinderNaomi CahnNate OmanNathaniel GleicherNeil BuchananNeil RichardsNicole HuberfeldNorman ReimerNorthwestern University Law ReviewNotre Dame Law ReviewNYU Law ReviewOlivier SylvainOrin KerrPaul ButlerPaul HorwitzPaul OhmPaul SecundaPeter EdelmanPeter McCormickPeter SmithPhilippe AigrainQuinn NortonRachel GodsilRafael PardoRebecca SandefurRichard SaverRichard ZorzaRick SwedloffRobert AhdiehRobert PercivalRobert SchapiroRobert TsaiRoberto VerzolaRonald K.L. CollinsRussell EnglerRussell KorobkinRyan CaloSalil MehraSam KaminSam YospeSamuel BrunsonSarah LawskySarah WaldeckSasha RomanoskyScott BurrisScott MossScott PeppetShavar JeffriesSherrilyn IfillShruti RanaSolangel MaldonadoSonia KatyalSonja StarrSouthern California Law ReviewSpencer WallerStanford Law ReviewStefan Bird-PollanSteph TaiStephen GaloobSteve Eppler-EpsteinSteve VladeckSteven BellovinStuart ShiffmanSusan KuoSusan ScafidiTamara RelisTaunya BanksTed EisenbergTexas Law ReviewThomas ClancyThomas CrockerTim WuTimothy GlynnTimothy ZickTina RasnowTristin GreenTuan SamahonUCLA Law ReviewUniversity of Chicago Law ReviewUniversity of Illinois Law ReviewUniversity of Pennsylvania Law ReviewVanderbilt Law ReviewVickie WilliamsVirginia Law ReviewViva MoffatWashington University Law ReviewWilliam &amp; Mary Law ReviewWilliam BirdthistleWilliam McGeveranWilliam ShieberWoodrow HartzogYale Law JournalYoungjae LeeZephyr Teachout</s>
    <s>Select Category Accounting (36) Administrative Announcements (332) Administrative Law (139) Admiralty (14) Advertising (34) Agricultural Law (5) Amazon (4) Anonymity (77) Antitrust (28) Architecture (50) Articles and Books (187) Asides (324) Bankruptcy (55) Behavioral Law and Economics (118) Bioethics (31) Blogging (318) Book Reviews (158) Bright Ideas (34) Capital Punishment (26) Civil Procedure (58) Civil Rights (199) Conferences (76) Constitutional Law (581) Constitutional Redemption Symposium (24) Consumer Protection Law (88) Contract Law &amp; Beyond (253) Corporate Finance (70) Corporate Law (241) Corruption (27) Courts (15) Criminal Law (248) Criminal Procedure (130) Culture (353) Current Events (642) Cyber Civil Rights (66) Cyberlaw (164) DRM (19) Economic Analysis of Law (362) Education (81) Election Law (10) Empirical Analysis of Law (146) Employment Law (75) Environmental Law (41) Estates and Trusts (7) Evidence Law (9) Family Law (75) Feminism and Gender (120) Financial Institutions (29) First Amendment (239) Food (21) Google &amp; Search Engines (149) Google and Search Engines (2) Government Secrecy (20) Health Law (249) History of Law (94) Humor (191) Immigration (33) Indian Law (2) Insurance Law (9) Intellectual Property (350) International &amp; Comparative Law (115) Interviews (13) Jurisprudence (79) Just for Fun (15) Law and Humanities (108) Law and Inequality (140) Law and Psychology (55) Law Practice (141) Law Professor Blogger Census (16) Law Rev (Boston College) (21) Law Rev (Boston University) (11) Law Rev (California) (6) Law Rev (Chicago) (9) Law Rev (Columbia) (35) Law Rev (Cornell) (21) Law Rev (Duke) (26) Law Rev (Emory) (13) Law Rev (Fordham) (11) Law Rev (Georgetown) (19) Law Rev (GW) (20) Law Rev (Harvard) (18) Law Rev (Hastings) (4) Law Rev (Illinois) (20) Law Rev (Indiana) (1) Law Rev (Iowa) (15) Law Rev (Michigan) (35) Law Rev (Minnesota) (24) Law Rev (Northwestern) (15) Law Rev (Notre Dame) (7) Law Rev (NYU) (11) Law Rev (Penn) (30) Law Rev (S Cal) (10) Law Rev (Stanford) (12) Law Rev (Texas) (7) Law Rev (Toronto) (5) Law Rev (UCLA) (21) Law Rev (Vanderbilt) (34) Law Rev (Virginia) (23) Law Rev (Wash U) (3) Law Rev (Wisconsin) (1) Law Rev (Wm &amp; Mary) (13) Law Rev (Yale) (61) Law Rev Contents (288) Law Rev Forum (129) Law School (341) Law School (Hiring &amp; Laterals) (104) Law School (Law Reviews) (97) Law School (Rankings) (76) Law School (Scholarship) (190) Law School (Teaching) (197) Law Student Discussions (19) Law Talk (38) Legal Ethics (62) Legal Theory (140) LGBT (15) Media Law (47) Military Law (5) Movies &amp; Television (24) Philosophy of Social Science (71) Political Economy (1) Politics (399) Privacy (573) Privacy (Consumer Privacy) (122) Privacy (Electronic Surveillance) (139) Privacy (Gossip &amp; Shaming) (157) Privacy (ID Theft) (43) Privacy (Law Enforcement) (158) Privacy (Medical) (52) Privacy (National Security) (163) Property Law (64) Psychology and Behavior (23) Race (60) Religion (77) Reparations (6) Science Fiction (14) Second Amendment (6) Securities (81) Securities Regulation (49) Social Network Websites (97) Sociology of Law (100) Supreme Court (245) Symposium (Access to Knowledge) (15) Symposium (Future of Internet) (29) Symposium (Health Care Fragmentation) (11) Symposium (Money Talks) (14) Symposium (The Master Switch) (7) Symposium (Turner v. Rogers) (23) Symposium (What Difference Representation) (21) Tax (67) Teaching (43) Technology (342) Tort Law (88) Trade (6) Uncategorized (1293) Web 2.0 (98) Weird (128) Wiki (41) Wills, Trusts, and Estates (12)</s>
    <s>Select Month October 2011 (38) September 2011 (102) August 2011 (108) July 2011 (100) June 2011 (112) May 2011 (99) April 2011 (109) March 2011 (130) February 2011 (117) January 2011 (98) December 2010 (100) November 2010 (95) October 2010 (100) September 2010 (113) August 2010 (103) July 2010 (102) June 2010 (113) May 2010 (127) April 2010 (158) March 2010 (151) February 2010 (102) January 2010 (166) December 2009 (146) November 2009 (109) October 2009 (103) September 2009 (110) August 2009 (105) July 2009 (85) June 2009 (115) May 2009 (176) April 2009 (153) March 2009 (116) February 2009 (105) January 2009 (126) December 2008 (123) November 2008 (124) October 2008 (170) September 2008 (192) August 2008 (107) July 2008 (129) June 2008 (82) May 2008 (101) April 2008 (114) March 2008 (126) February 2008 (131) January 2008 (125) December 2007 (157) November 2007 (144) October 2007 (133) September 2007 (100) August 2007 (111) July 2007 (109) June 2007 (82) May 2007 (69) April 2007 (83) March 2007 (119) February 2007 (76) January 2007 (78) December 2006 (72) November 2006 (101) October 2006 (81) September 2006 (62) August 2006 (99) July 2006 (90) June 2006 (127) May 2006 (120) April 2006 (85) March 2006 (93) February 2006 (83) January 2006 (109) December 2005 (109) November 2005 (129) October 2005 (125) August 2005 (1) July 2005 (1) June 2005 (2) May 2005 (1)</s>
    <s>Recent Comments</s>
    <s>A.J. Sutter on Republic of China Centennial</s>
    <s>L on What Exactly is Wrong With Polygamy?</s>
    <s>Flynn on Starbucks' Secret Menu</s>
    <s>Jeff harrison on Spousal Hiring and Gender</s>
    <s>Bruinrefugee on The Devil's Dictionary on Occupy Wall Street</s>
    <s>Margaret Lewis on Republic of China Centennial</s>
    <s>Shag from Brookline on The Devil's Dictionary on Occupy Wall Street</s>
    <s>Timothy Zick on Public Protest 1.0</s>
    <s>Bruinrefugee on The Moral Authority of Occupy Wall Street</s>
    <s>Danielle Citron on Public Protest 1.0</s>
    <s>Ted G. on What to do when seeing famous Social Security Numbers</s>
    <s>bruinrefugee on The Devil's Dictionary on Occupy Wall Street</s>
    <s>A.J. Sutter on Republic of China Centennial</s>
    <s>harwellwells on Basic Research</s>
    <s>Joe on Reviewing The Oral Argument in Hosanna-Tabor (Part Three)</s>
    <s>About the Blog</s>
    <s>Concurring Opinions is a multiple authored, general interest legal blog.</s>
    <s>(Image: Wikicommons)</s>
    <s>ClassCrits Conference Call for Papers</s>
    <s>posted by Frank Pasquale</s>
    <s>The ClassCrits blog has a number of interesting posts up recently. The group has announced a call for papers for a September conference; here is the notice:</s>
    <s>&gt; ClassCrits IV, “Criminalizing Economic Inequality”</s>
    <s>&gt; This workshop, the fourth meeting of ClassCrits, takes as its theme the criminalization of economic inequality. The dominance of “free market” economic theory and policy has been accompanied in the U.S. by increasing reliance on the criminal justice system to make and enforce economic policy. The criminal justice system is increasingly used to control persons and groups whose participation in formal markets is marginal at best. Many aspects of traditional immigration law have morphed into “crimmigration”, appropriating domestic criminal law enforcement tools and redefining whole communities of workers and their families as “illegal people.” States and municipalities have criminalized the lives of homeless people, including those who are mentally ill.</s>
    <s>&gt; International markets in heroin, cocaine, and marijuana are the targets of a “war on drugs” fought through criminal justice (and military) methods. Criminal law is used to deter and punish sex trafficking, and the criminal justice system buttresses, or substitutes for, welfare policy. At the same time, corporate wrongdoing has been lightly punished, if at all, and the drumbeat against “government” as the enemy of the people continues unabated. In this sense, economic inequality has not been “criminalized” at all. Quite the opposite, powerful interests encourage American citizens to see economic inequality as natural and good. Criminalizing Economic Inequality will provide an opportunity for legal scholars, economists, policymakers, activists, and others to critically examine the relationship between state power and market power in upward redistribution and the continued spread of laissez-faire ideology.</s>
    <s>Proposals are due May 6th to classcrits@gmail.com. Anyone familiar with the work of Glenn Greenwald or Matt Taibbi will find much of interest here. I hope to attend the conference and get more involved in this important group. One need only compare the treatment of one loan applicant and the total lack of prosecutions of top financial executives to see the enduring relevance of the conference themes.</s>
    <s>!April 15, 2011 at 1:13 pmPosted in: Civil Rights, Conferences, Current Events, Financial Institutions Print This Post</s>
    <s>Responses (3)</s>
    <s>1. Associate - April 15, 2011 at 3:01 pm</s>
    <s>Most adherents of &quot;laissez-faire ideology&quot; favor decriminalizing drugs and ending militaristic policing.</s>
    <s>2. Frank - April 15, 2011 at 4:11 pm</s>
    <s>Associate, I do agree that Radley Balko (and others listed here: http://balkin.blogspot.com/2011/02/reducing-mass-incarceration-its-not.html ) have developed a libertarian critique of (and activism against) penal excess.</s>
    <s>However, I also think that it is largely left-leaning politicians in the US (like Jim Webb) who've tried to improve things politically…and who reap lots of political flack from a &quot;tough on crime&quot; right.</s>
    <s>Admittedly, at this point, the two parties are so close together on war/crime issues that the Joe Arpaio route to electoral success may be just as plausible for Dems as for Republicans.</s>
    <s>3. Martha McCluskey - April 18, 2011 at 2:02 pm</s>
    <s>Certainly there are some interesting convergences between right and left thinking on criminal law and policy. Nonetheless, proponents of free-market economics have often also been in the forefront of campaigns to criminalize the poor or workers -- I'm thinking of the rhetoric and law reforms focusing on punishing &quot;welfare fraud&quot; and &quot;workers' compensation fraud&quot;. One problem is that professed libertarians like Richard Esptein back strong government power to crack down on &quot;fraud&quot;, as consistent with or necessary to a laissez-faire vision. But then that view of &quot;fraud&quot; allows for plenty of ideological bias and double standards -- the self-dealing deceptive actions of financial industry executives or in corporate tax evasion can seem like productive innovation, not theft. Further, the prevailing free market theory (pre-crisis at least) that corporate fraud is self-correcting and so need not be addressed by government seems not to have applied equally to non-rich human beings engaged in similar actions.</s>
    <s>Leave a Reply</s>
    <s>Name, required</s>
    <s>Email (will not be published), required</s>
    <s>Website (if present)</s>
    <s>Please note: JavaScript is required to post comments. Spam protection by WP Captcha-Free</s>
    <s>« Previous post</s>
    <s>Next post »</s>
    <s>Daniel J. Solove</s>
    <s>Kaimipono Wenger</s>
    <s>Dave Hoffman</s>
    <s>Frank Pasquale</s>
    <s>Deven Desai</s>
    <s>Danielle Citron</s>
    <s>Lawrence Cunningham</s>
    <s>Sarah Waldeck</s>
    <s>Jaya Ramji-Nogales</s>
    <s>Solangel Maldonado</s>
    <s>Gerard Magliocca</s>
    <s>Jennifer Hendricks</s>
    <s>Margaret Lewis</s>
    <s>Amanda Pustilnik</s>
    <s>Olivier Sylvain</s>
    <s>Timothy Zick</s>
    <s>Previous Guests</s>
    <s>Michael Abramowicz</s>
    <s>Michelle Adams</s>
    <s>Robert Ahdieh</s>
    <s>Marvin Ammori</s>
    <s>Michelle Anderson</s>
    <s>Laura Appleman</s>
    <s>Taunya Lovell Banks</s>
    <s>Ann Bartow</s>
    <s>Steven Bellovin</s>
    <s>Adam Benforado</s>
    <s>Gaia Bernstein</s>
    <s>Francesca Bignami</s>
    <s>Josh Blackman</s>
    <s>Joseph Blocher</s>
    <s>Jeremy Blumenthal</s>
    <s>Kathleen Boozang</s>
    <s>Bruce Boyden</s>
    <s>Donald Braman</s>
    <s>Al Brophy</s>
    <s>Neil H. Buchanan</s>
    <s>Bill Burke-White</s>
    <s>Scott Burris</s>
    <s>Paul Butler</s>
    <s>Ryan Calo</s>
    <s>Naomi Cahn</s>
    <s>Anupam Chander</s>
    <s>Miriam Cherry</s>
    <s>Jack Chin</s>
    <s>Glenn Cohen</s>
    <s>Jennifer Collins</s>
    <s>Caroline Mala Corbin</s>
    <s>Thomas Crocker</s>
    <s>Allison Danner</s>
    <s>Brannon Denning</s>
    <s>Deven Desai</s>
    <s>Mike Dimino</s>
    <s>Mark Edwards</s>
    <s>Maxine Eichner</s>
    <s>Jessica Erickson</s>
    <s>David Fagundes</s>
    <s>Lisa Fairfax</s>
    <s>Joshua Fairfield</s>
    <s>Christine Haight Farley</s>
    <s>Kim Ferzan</s>
    <s>Dan Filler</s>
    <s>Mary Anne Franks</s>
    <s>Michael Froomkin</s>
    <s>Amanda Frost</s>
    <s>Brian Frye</s>
    <s>Timothy Glynn</s>
    <s>Rachel Godsil</s>
    <s>Eric Goldman</s>
    <s>David Gray</s>
    <s>Craig Green</s>
    <s>Tristin Green</s>
    <s>Jonathan Hafetz</s>
    <s>Meredith Harbach</s>
    <s>Michelle Harner</s>
    <s>Jeffrey Harrison</s>
    <s>Hosea Harvey</s>
    <s>Erica Hashimoto</s>
    <s>Carissa Hessick</s>
    <s>Laura Heymann</s>
    <s>Robert Hillman</s>
    <s>Christine Hurt</s>
    <s>Darian Ibrahim</s>
    <s>Sherrilyn Ifill</s>
    <s>John Ip</s>
    <s>Shavar Jeffries</s>
    <s>Kevin Johnson</s>
    <s>Kristin Johnson</s>
    <s>Jeff Jonas</s>
    <s>Courtney Joslin</s>
    <s>Dan Kahan</s>
    <s>Jeffrey Kahn</s>
    <s>Brian Kalt</s>
    <s>Sam Kamin</s>
    <s>Michael Kang</s>
    <s>Chimène Keitner</s>
    <s>Alicia Kelly</s>
    <s>Orin Kerr</s>
    <s>Nancy Kim</s>
    <s>Heidi Kitrosser</s>
    <s>Adam Kolber</s>
    <s>Russell Korobkin</s>
    <s>Alex Kreit</s>
    <s>Anita S. Krishnakumar</s>
    <s>Susan Kuo</s>
    <s>Greg Lastowka</s>
    <s>Sarah Lawsky</s>
    <s>Youngjae Lee</s>
    <s>Erik Lillquist</s>
    <s>Jeff Lipshaw</s>
    <s>Jonathan Lipson</s>
    <s>Jacqueline Lipton</s>
    <s>Matthew Lister</s>
    <s>Joseph Liu</s>
    <s>Michael Madison</s>
    <s>Kevin Noble Maillard</s>
    <s>Solangel Maldonado</s>
    <s>Jason Mazzone</s>
    <s>Linda McClain</s>
    <s>William McGeveran</s>
    <s>Salil Mehra</s>
    <s>Carrie Menkel-Meadow</s>
    <s>Max Minzner</s>
    <s>Viva Moffat</s>
    <s>Scott Moss</s>
    <s>Eric Muller</s>
    <s>Jaya Ramji-Nogales</s>
    <s>Helen Norton</s>
    <s>Elizabeth Nowicki</s>
    <s>Paul Ohm</s>
    <s>Angela Onwuachi-Willing</s>
    <s>Michael O'Shea</s>
    <s>David Opderback</s>
    <s>Kristen Osenga</s>
    <s>Rafael Pardo</s>
    <s>Marcy Peek</s>
    <s>Eduardo Peñalver</s>
    <s>Robert Percival</s>
    <s>Michael J. Pitts</s>
    <s>Marc Poirier</s>
    <s>David Post</s>
    <s>Shruti Rana</s>
    <s>Geoffrey Rapp</s>
    <s>Neil Richards</s>
    <s>Lori Ringhand</s>
    <s>Alice Ristroph</s>
    <s>Marc Roark</s>
    <s>Sasha Romanosky</s>
    <s>Tuan Samahon</s>
    <s>Susan Scafidi</s>
    <s>David Schraub</s>
    <s>Paul Secunda</s>
    <s>Jonathan Siegel</s>
    <s>Jessica Silbey</s>
    <s>Peter Smith</s>
    <s>Judd Sneirson</s>
    <s>Adam Steinman</s>
    <s>Charles Sullivan</s>
    <s>Rick Swedloff</s>
    <s>Steph Tai</s>
    <s>Andrew Taslitz</s>
    <s>Robert Tsai</s>
    <s>Jenia Turner</s>
    <s>Steve Vladeck</s>
    <s>Ari Waldman</s>
    <s>Spencer Weber Waller</s>
    <s>Howard Wasserman</s>
    <s>Melissa Waters</s>
    <s>Frank Wu</s>
    <s>Alfred Yen</s>
    <s>Corey Yung</s>
    <s>David Zaring</s>
    <s>Timothy Zick</s>
    <s>Michael Zimmer</s>
    <s>Jonathan Zittrain</s>
    <s>Concurring Opinions is a</s>
    <s>general-interest legal blog</s>
    <s>operated by Concurring</s>
    <s>Opinions LLC, a Pennsylvania</s>
    <s>Limited Liability Corporation.</s>
    <s>Above the Law</s>
    <s>Access to Justice</s>
    <s>ACS Blog</s>
    <s>Becker-Posner Blog</s>
    <s>Chicago Law Faculty Blog</s>
    <s>Crime &amp; Federalism</s>
    <s>CrimProf Blog</s>
    <s>Crooked Timber</s>
    <s>Dorf on Law</s>
    <s>Election Law</s>
    <s>Emergent Chaos</s>
    <s>The Faculty Lounge</s>
    <s>Feminist Law Profs</s>
    <s>Freakonomics Blog</s>
    <s>Freedom to Tinker</s>
    <s>Google Blogoscoped</s>
    <s>How Appealing</s>
    <s>Juris Novus</s>
    <s>Just Books</s>
    <s>Law and Humanities Blog</s>
    <s>Law and Letters</s>
    <s>Law Librarian Blog</s>
    <s>Legal Profession Blog</s>
    <s>Legal Theory Blog</s>
    <s>Legal Times Blog</s>
    <s>Leiter Reports</s>
    <s>Brian Leiter's Law School Reports</s>
    <s>Lessig Blog</s>
    <s>Madisonian Theory</s>
    <s>Media Law Blog</s>
    <s>Mirror of Justice</s>
    <s>The Moderate Voice</s>
    <s>National Security Advisors</s>
    <s>Opinio Juris</s>
    <s>Point of Law</s>
    <s>Property Prof Blog</s>
    <s>Red Tape Chronicles</s>
    <s>The Right Coast</s>
    <s>Schneier on Security</s>
    <s>Security Dilemmas</s>
    <s>Sentencing Law and Policy</s>
    <s>Simple Justice</s>
    <s>The Situationist</s>
    <s>Susan Crawford</s>
    <s>Talking Points Memo</s>
    <s>TaxProf Blog</s>
    <s>TeachPrivacy Blog</s>
    <s>Tech &amp; Marketing Law</s>
    <s>Truth on the Market</s>
    <s>Volokh Conspiracy</s>
    <s>WorkPlace Prof Blog</s>
    <s>WSJ Law Blog</s>
    <s>The Yin Blog</s>
    <s>(C) Concurring Opinions</s>
    <s>Powered by WordPress</s>
  </text>
</page>
