<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.isaca.org/Education/Call-for-Papers/Pages/default.aspx</url>
  <title>Call for Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>ISACA empanels a Conference Development Task Force for each of the education The task forces identify all the specific elements within the Call for Papers </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>ISACA: Serving IT Governance Professionals</s>
    <s>Chinese (Simplified)</s>
    <s>Chinese (Traditional)</s>
    <s>PeopleSite ContentConversations</s>
    <s>Advanced Search</s>
    <s>About ISACA</s>
    <s>Knowledge Center</s>
    <s>What We Offer &amp; Who We Serve</s>
    <s>@ISACA Newsletter</s>
    <s>Licensing and Promotion</s>
    <s>ISACA TV</s>
    <s>Press Room</s>
    <s>IT Governance</s>
    <s>Contact Us</s>
    <s>Professional Membership</s>
    <s>Student Membership</s>
    <s>Academic Membership</s>
    <s>Local Chapter Information</s>
    <s>Join Today</s>
    <s>Professional Growth</s>
    <s>Global Community</s>
    <s>Advance Your Career</s>
    <s>What is CISA</s>
    <s>What is CISM</s>
    <s>What is CGEIT</s>
    <s>What is CRISC</s>
    <s>How to Become</s>
    <s>How to Become</s>
    <s>How to Become</s>
    <s>How to Become</s>
    <s>Register for the</s>
    <s>Register for the</s>
    <s>Register for the</s>
    <s>Register for the</s>
    <s>Prepare for the Exam</s>
    <s>Prepare for the Exam</s>
    <s>Prepare for the Exam</s>
    <s>Prepare for the Exam</s>
    <s>Taking the Exam</s>
    <s>Taking the Exam</s>
    <s>Taking the Exam</s>
    <s>Taking the Exam</s>
    <s>Apply for Certification</s>
    <s>Apply for Certification</s>
    <s>Apply for Certification</s>
    <s>Apply for Certification</s>
    <s>Maintain Your CISA</s>
    <s>Maintain Your CISM</s>
    <s>Maintain Your CGEIT</s>
    <s>Maintain Your CRISC</s>
    <s>Why Certify</s>
    <s>How to Earn CPE</s>
    <s>Maintain Your Certification</s>
    <s>Write an Exam Question</s>
    <s>US DoD Information</s>
    <s>Exam Registration</s>
    <s>Online Learning</s>
    <s>Upcoming Events</s>
    <s>COBIT Education</s>
    <s>On-Site Training</s>
    <s>Exam Review Courses</s>
    <s>Exhibit &amp; Sponsor Opportunities</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Browse Knowledge Center topics</s>
    <s>      Where networking and knowledge intersect.</s>
    <s>BMIS (Information Security)</s>
    <s>COBIT (IT Governance &amp; Control)</s>
    <s>ITAF (IT Assurance\Audit)</s>
    <s>Research (Deliverables\Projects)</s>
    <s>Risk IT (IT Risk Management)</s>
    <s>Standards (Assurance\Audit\Control)</s>
    <s>Val IT (Value Delivery)</s>
    <s> Featured Resources</s>
    <s>Career Centre</s>
    <s>Legislative Reporting</s>
    <s>Current Issue</s>
    <s>Past Issues</s>
    <s>Author Blog</s>
    <s>CPE Quizzes</s>
    <s>Submit an Article</s>
    <s>IT Control Objectives for Cloud Computing</s>
    <s>Oracle E-Business Suite</s>
    <s>Top Sellers</s>
    <s>CISM Review Manual 2011</s>
    <s>IT Control Objectives for Sarbanes-Oxley</s>
    <s>The Risk IT Framework</s>
    <s>Sharepoint Deployment &amp; Governance Using COBIT 4.1</s>
    <s>CISA Review Manual 2011</s>
    <s>Board Briefing on IT Governance, 2nd Edition</s>
    <s>Security, Audit and Control Features SAP ERP, 3rd Edition</s>
    <s>My ISACA</s>
    <s>Join ISACA</s>
    <s>Shopping Cart</s>
    <s>SITE MAINTENANCE NOTIFICATION</s>
    <s>Sign In</s>
    <s>!Skip Navigation LinksISACA &gt; Education &gt; Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Online Learning</s>
    <s>Upcoming Events</s>
    <s>COBIT Education</s>
    <s>On-Site Training</s>
    <s>Exam Review Courses</s>
    <s>Exhibitor and Sponsorship Opportunities</s>
    <s>Call for Papers</s>
    <s>Follow us:</s>
    <s>ISACA Call for Papers Process </s>
    <s>(Please note: the following information is specific to education events ISACA produces at the International Headquarters level. Local ISACA Chapter events are not subject to this procedure. Please contact the Local ISACA Chapters for additional information regarding local education events.)</s>
    <s>ISACA issues specific Calls for Papers for each of the education events it produces at the International Headquarters level. The Call for Papers clearly identifies specific:</s>
    <s>Target audiences</s>
    <s>Learning objectives</s>
    <s>Education delivery methods</s>
    <s>Event structure</s>
    <s>Possible topics</s>
    <s>Instructions on how to submit a proposal</s>
    <s>ISACA empanels a Conference Development Task Force for each of the education events. These task forces are comprised of member-volunteers who demonstrate subject matter expertise and competencies in education program development. The task forces identify all the specific elements within the Call for Papers (listed above). The task force members then review the proposals, vet the speakers and make final selections. Task force members work with the selected speaker throughout the session development process to ensure compliance with the stated objectives and avoid overt commercialism and other detractions for the ISACA education mission.</s>
    <s>Learning Objectives and Education Mission </s>
    <s>ISACA believes the three objectives of a good education event are: 1) learning; 2) networking; and 3) motivation1. Continuing professional education is best accomplished in a setting that encourages dialogue, discussion and debate both formally within the sessions and informally. ISACA includes longer refreshment breaks and lunches, receptions, and social events to encourage peer-to-peer networking and provide opportunities for informal communication. None of this means anything unless the attendee is motivated to utilise new knowledge and maintain relationships with new contacts. ISACA endeavours to create an environment that is inspiring and renewing to encourage the professional to implement new and exciting ideas and share with colleagues.</s>
    <s>ISACA seeks innovated session proposals that not only speak to the technical issues, but also provide context. Speakers should offer real-world examples, “war stories”, case studies, successes and failures, examples of actual tools and working papers used (including mapping to ISACA frameworks where appropriate), and insights on emerging issues. Sessions should be designed to encourage interactive audience participation by including small group discussions, exercises and other activities to interject energy and promote dialogue. ISACA is not looking for lectures and demonstrations but rather innovative and exciting sessions. ISACA expects learning objectives for proposed sessions to reflect actions and abilities the attendees can employ from participating in the session. The learning objectives must be clear and measurable. Learning objectives need to complete the following sentence: “After completing this session, the participant will be able to…”.</s>
    <s>The audience needs to realize the full value of meeting face-to-face as well as quantifiable return on travel and registration costs. The speaker must provide additional resources such as bibliographies, white papers, relevant articles, tools, guides, sample programs and other information that extends the learning beyond the session and adds value to the event. Presentation material including additional resources is subject to quality review by the Conference Development Task Force and must be ready in its final form approximately 10 weeks prior to the event. Please carefully consider if selected as a speaker whether you would be able to comply with the deadline. ISACA receives criticism for missing documentation.</s>
    <s>Industry-specific sessions are welcome to make guidance more specific. Proposals from a team or a panel are welcome in order to share multiple perspectives on a topic. Speakers are expected to have read and be familiar with portions of COBIT, Val IT, Risk IT, and other ISACA thought leadership that are relevant to their presentations. Speakers should consider how presentation content supports CISA, CISM, CGEIT and the new CRISC knowledge objectives.</s>
    <s>How to Submit a Proposal</s>
    <s>Potential speakers must complete an official ISACA session proposal form for each proposed topic. The session proposal form will serve to document the speaker’s vision of the proposed session and how he/she intends to treat the various issues of the topic. The Conference Development Task Force can only make its speaker selections after a comprehensive review of the session proposal documentation and bona fides. It is important to include a full biographical sketch and detailed list of speaking engagements.</s>
    <s>** Special note to public relations firms and internal marketing departments submitting proposals on behalf of a potential speaker : You must provide the direct contact information for the speaker. The speaker must be aware of the submission and be able to accept the commitment of presenting at the event if selected. ISACA must be able to correspond with the speaker directly. ISACA understands third parties and other interested persons often need to be included in any communications and will endeavour to keep everyone informed.</s>
    <s>How Speakers Are Chosen</s>
    <s>Proposals are reviewed by a Conference Development Task Force comprised of member-volunteers who demonstrate subject matter expertise and competencies in education program development. The task force members vet the potential speaker, not the speaker’s company or organisation. ISACA expects the speaker to honour his or her commitment to present the proposed session at the subject event.</s>
    <s>The proposals are evaluated in whole or in part on the following criteria:</s>
    <s>Subject matter relevance and timeliness</s>
    <s>Clearly stated learning objectives and purpose</s>
    <s>Practical application of material</s>
    <s>Technical accuracy</s>
    <s>Context of the issues including real-world case studies, examples, and stories</s>
    <s>Potential for audience interactive participation</s>
    <s>Speaker presentation skills and experience</s>
    <s>Speaker subject matter knowledge and expertise</s>
    <s>Speaker industry leadership</s>
    <s>Education focus devoid of overt and covert commercialism</s>
    <s>Overall quality of the written proposal </s>
    <s>Benefits of Speaking</s>
    <s>ISACA is an international professional organisation with more than 86,000 constituents in more than 70 countries. ISACA is a leading provider of knowledge, certifications, community, advocacy and education on information systems assurance and security, enterprise governance of IT, and IT-related risk and compliance. ISACA education conferences, training weeks and webinars are recognized as the premier events throughout the industry. Speakers associated with ISACA education events are similarly recognised as industry leaders and subject matter experts.</s>
    <s>All selected speakers receive a complimentary registration to the event (not including optional workshops).</s>
    <s>Speakers gain increased visibility throughout the ISACA international community.</s>
    <s>Speakers and their companies and organisations are included in promotional information sent to regional and international constituents via hard copy brochures and other marketing material, the ISACA web site, press releases and other publicity outlets.</s>
    <s>Speakers are able to include contact information and company and organisation logos on approved presentation material.</s>
    <s>Speakers have the opportunity to network with peers and other professionals at specifically designed points throughout the event.</s>
    <s>Speakers can prove their value, expertise, knowledge and acumen by presenting relevant and timely subjects in an effective manner. This often leads to business development.</s>
    <s>Speaker Expense Reimbursement</s>
    <s>ISACA is a not-for-profit organization serving the IT assurance, information security management and IT governance communities. Most speakers and their companies recognize the importance of being part of ISACA’s educational events and embrace a philanthropic spirit by funding travel and lodgings. ISACA educational events provide speakers the opportunity to demonstrate their expertise, knowledge and experience as well as to network with constituents for business development purposes. In appreciation for all the hard work and effort, ISACA offers a full complimentary conference registration (not including workshops) to all speakers. In addition, ISACA recognizes speakers and their companies as “conference supporters” in conference literature distributed to delegates. Travel reimbursement is available upon request and is awarded on a case-by-case basis to speakers who meet specific criteria.</s>
    <s>How to Receive More Information</s>
    <s>ISACA posts its Calls for Papers on the respective education event web page. To receive direct notification of an open Call for Papers, please send an email to conference@isaca.org with the following information:</s>
    <s>Subject line: “ISACA Call for Papers”</s>
    <s>Business title</s>
    <s>Company or organization name</s>
    <s>Mailing address</s>
    <s>Email address</s>
    <s>Contact telephone number</s>
    <s>Geographic area of interest (e.g. North America, Europe, Asia, Latin America, Africa, Oceania)</s>
    <s>General topics of interest (e.g. IT audit, compliance, information security, et cetera)</s>
    <s>Short biographical sketch</s>
    <s>List of previous speaking engagements</s>
    <s>1 Meeting Architecture, a Manifesto by Maarten Venneste pages 56 and 57</s>
    <s>Quick Links</s>
    <s>I want to </s>
    <s>My Bookmarks</s>
    <s>Saved Searches</s>
    <s>Access COBIT online</s>
    <s>Earn CPE credits</s>
    <s>Find sponsor and exhibit opportunities</s>
    <s>Register for an e-symposia</s>
    <s>View upcoming events</s>
    <s>Please Login to View Your Quick Links.</s>
    <s>Please Login to View Your Quick Links.</s>
    <s>(C) 2011 ISACA. All Rights Reserved</s>
    <s>Site Map</s>
    <s>Contact Us</s>
    <s>Press Room</s>
    <s>Terms of Use</s>
    <s>ISACA PRIVACY POLICY – YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS</s>
  </text>
</page>
