<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.uksg.org/event/conference12/cfp</url>
  <title>2012 Annual Conference: Call for Papers | UKSG</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Suggestions may be for plenary sessions or for the smaller breakout sessions. Review previous annual conference presentations. The call for papers has now </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Home ›</s>
    <s>2012 Annual Conference: Call for Papers</s>
    <s>The call for papers has now closed. Thank you for all your suggestions; the programme will be published towards the end of 2011.</s>
    <s>We are inviting suggestions for topics and speakers at UKSG's 35th Annual Conference, which will be held in Glasgow, UK from 26-28 March 2012.</s>
    <s>The conference is attended by librarians, publishers and their suppliers / intermediaries, and addresses initiatives, technologies, standards and processes relating to the knowledge community.</s>
    <s>Full details of our international audience and feedback from previous conferences</s>
    <s>Suggestions should be in the format of a brief synopsis and ideas for speakers to talk on that topic. You may propose others as speakers and we will contact them should the topic be picked up by our planning committee. Suggestions may be for plenary sessions or for the smaller breakout sessions.</s>
    <s>Review previous annual conference presentations</s>
    <s>The call for papers has now closed. Thank you for all your suggestions; the programme will be published towards the end of 2011.</s>
    <s>How to Join</s>
    <s>About UKSG</s>
    <s>Events and Training</s>
    <s>Research and Projects</s>
    <s>Useful Links &amp; Resources</s>
    <s>Contact Us</s>
    <s>Search this site:</s>
    <s>Upcoming events</s>
    <s>UKSG Practical Project Management: London(Event)(14 days)</s>
    <s>UKSG Money Matters: An Introduction to Financial Planning: London(Event)(25 days)</s>
    <s>UKSG One-Day Conference: London(Event)(34 days)</s>
    <s>UKSG E-Resources Technical Update: London(Event)(42 days)</s>
    <s>Sitemap | Webmaster | Contact Us | Terms &amp; Conditions | (C) UKSG 2011</s>
  </text>
</page>
