<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://www.coaltechnologies.com/pages/call_for_papers.html</url>
  <title>Coal Technology Association Call for Papers</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>CALL FOR PAPERS. The 37th International Technical Conference on Clean Coal &amp; Fuel Systems. The Clearwater clean coal conference. Theme: Technological </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>&gt; COALTECHNOLOGIESASSOCIATES</s>
    <s>&gt; CLEARWATER CLEAN COAL CONFERENCE</s>
    <s>CALL FOR PAPERS</s>
    <s>&gt; The 37th International Technical Conference on Clean Coal &amp; Fuel Systems</s>
    <s>&gt; The Clearwater clean coal conference</s>
    <s>&gt; Theme: Technological Solutions for Energy Challenges</s>
    <s>&gt; Domestic Keynote Address: The Future of Coal</s>
    <s>&gt; Darlene Radcliffe, Duke Energy</s>
    <s>&gt; and</s>
    <s>&gt; International Keynote Address: An Update and Future of Chinese Clean Coal</s>
    <s>&gt; Prof. Yue Guangxi, Tsinghua University</s>
    <s>&gt; June 3 to 7, 2012</s>
    <s>&gt; Sheraton Sand Key, Clearwater, Florida, USA</s>
    <s>&gt; !</s>
    <s>&gt; Five Days – The Hottest Topics – The World’s KEY PLAYERS, Leading Experts and &quot;Super Scientists&quot; –</s>
    <s>&gt; The Most Comprehensive Program on Coal Technologies –</s>
    <s>&gt; From “Dawn to Dusk” – Representatives from 6 Continents</s>
    <s>&gt; For 5-1/2 days in 2011 the world’s experts were in Clearwater, Florida, to share their knowledge and expertise on coal technologies. The issues on the front burners of the electric utility industry were spotlighted. All in attendance had a firm grasp on the major issues facing the industry today and tomorrow in the tutorials, panels and technical sessions that delved into critical energy topics. To see the Call for Papers click here CFP 2012.pdf</s>
    <s>&gt; The Clearwater Clean Coal Conference has earned a reputation as one of the premiere conferences on coal technologies as it grows in size and scope since its inception in 1975. This technical conference and networking event – where utility executives and world-leading experts present 150 technical presentations in the major areas of interest – is sponsored by Coal Technologies Associates, and the American Society of Mechanical Engineers' Power Division.</s>
    <s>&gt; The Conference Committee is now seeking papers for the 2012 conference for presentation in the 30 technical sessions that will be offered at the conference. In addition, to these technical sessions, 10 Short Courses, 12 Panels, a Coal Workshop and an Exhibit Center are also on the agenda. Go to the Program Announcement to see all of the agenda items.</s>
    <s>&gt; Proposed Conference Agenda</s>
    <s>&gt; Sunday, June 3, 2012</s>
    <s>&gt; Short Courses -- Noon to 6:15 p.m.:</s>
    <s>· Computational Fluid Dynamics Fundamentals</s>
    <s>Stefano Orsino, ANSYS Fluent</s>
    <s>· Tampa Electric Co. – topic to be determined.</s>
    <s>· Fundamentals of Ash Deposition for Utility Boilers and Solutions</s>
    <s>Chris J. Zygarlicke, Energy &amp; Environmental Research Center, et al</s>
    <s>· Coal Fired Industrial Furnace Optimization</s>
    <s>Mr. Allan Runstedtler, CANMET Energy</s>
    <s>· Oxy-fuel Technology Fundamentals</s>
    <s>Reed Hendershot, Air Products, and</s>
    <s>Dr. Lawrence Bool, Praxair, Inc.</s>
    <s>· Coal: From the Earth to the Atmosphere</s>
    <s>Dr. Edmundo Vasquez, Clyde Bergemann; Tony Widenman, Detroit Edison; and Ronald Affolter, U.S. Geological Survey</s>
    <s>· Low Nox Burner Issues Resolution</s>
    <s>Alan Paschedag, Siemens Environmental Systems &amp; Services and</s>
    <s>J. J. Letcavits, American Electric Power</s>
    <s>· Drying High-Moisture Coals</s>
    <s>Dr. Nenad Sarunac, Energy Research Center, Lehigh University and Mark Ness, Great River Energy</s>
    <s>· Process Flow Models</s>
    <s>Mike Mendez, Aspen Technology</s>
    <s>· Coal Gasification</s>
    <s>Dr. Ronald Breault, National Energy Technology Laboratory, U.S. Department of Energy</s>
    <s>&gt; Monday, June 4, 2012</s>
    <s>&gt; 8:00 a.m. – Plenary Session</s>
    <s>· Welcome – Barbara A. Sakkestad, Coal Technologies Associates</s>
    <s>· Introduction – Prof.-Dr. Klaus R.G. Hein, Monash University, Australia, Conference Committee Co-Chairman</s>
    <s>· International Keynote Address, Prof. Yue Guangxi, Tsinghua University</s>
    <s>· Panel: Worldwide Regulatory Outlook – Christ Smyrniotis, Fuel Tech</s>
    <s>11:30 a.m. – Luncheon – Planning for Your Future</s>
    <s>1:00 p.m. – Plenary Session</s>
    <s>· Overview, Dr. Lawrence Bool, Praxair, Inc., Conference Committee Co-Chair</s>
    <s>· Domestic Keynote Address, The Future of Coal: Darlene Radcliffe, Director, Environmental Technology and Fuel Policy, Duke Energy</s>
    <s>· Panel: Domestic Regulatory Outlook – Chris Smyrniotis, Fuel Tech</s>
    <s>4:00 p.m. – Plenary Session</s>
    <s>· Panel: Global Climate Change Panel, Dr. Robert Romanosky,</s>
    <s>National Energy Technology Laboratory, U.S. Department of Energy</s>
    <s>7:00 p.m. – Welcome in the Exhibit Center</s>
    <s>&gt; Tuesday, June 5, 2012</s>
    <s>&gt; 8:00 a.m. – Two Concurrent Panels</s>
    <s>· Cyclic Operation of Coal Based Power Plants for Managing Large Scale Penetration of Intermittent Renewables, Janos Beer, MIT; and</s>
    <s>· Gasification and Conversion, Dave Osborne, Xstrata Coal</s>
    <s>10:00 a.m. – Break</s>
    <s>10:30 a.m. – Five Concurrent Sessions</s>
    <s>12:30 p.m. – Jeopardy at Lunch</s>
    <s>2:00 p.m. – Plenary Session:</s>
    <s>· Oxyfuel, Ligang Zheng, CANMET, Canada and</s>
    <s>Terry Wall, University of Newcastle, Australia</s>
    <s>4:00 p.m. – Break</s>
    <s>4:30 p.m. – Five Concurrent Sessions</s>
    <s>6:30 p.m. – Beach Party</s>
    <s>&gt; Wednesday, June 6, 2012</s>
    <s>&gt; 8:00 a.m. – Two Concurrent Panels</s>
    <s>· Biomass Utilisation, Les Marshall, Ontario Power; and</s>
    <s>· Advances in Computational Fluid Dynamics, Edmundo Vasquez, Clyde Bergemann</s>
    <s>10:00 a.m. – Break</s>
    <s>10:30 a.m. – Five Concurrent Sessions</s>
    <s>12:30 p.m. – Themed Luncheon</s>
    <s>2:00 p.m. – Two Concurrent Panels</s>
    <s>· Post-Combustion Capture: Ready for Commercial Deployment, Yewen Tan, CANMET, and Lisa Rimpf, The Babcock &amp; Wilcox Co.; and</s>
    <s>· Potential Application and Cost Implication of Fuels in Technology Operation, Klaus Hein and Ashwani Gupta</s>
    <s>4:00 p.m. – Break</s>
    <s>4:30 p.m. – Five Concurrent Sessions</s>
    <s>7:00 p.m. – Banquet in honor of Prof. Adel Sarofim</s>
    <s>&gt; Thursday, June 7, 2012</s>
    <s>&gt; 8:00 a.m. – Two Concurrent Panels</s>
    <s>· Utilization of Low Rank Coals – Present Status and Future Chances, Klaus Hein and Chris Zygarlicke; and</s>
    <s>· CO2 in the Future, Dr. Klaus Lackner, Columbia University</s>
    <s>&gt; Friday, June 8, 2012</s>
    <s>&gt; 7:00 a.m. – Polk Power Plant Tour</s>
    <s>&gt; THE CONFERENCE COMMITTEE</s>
    <s>&gt; The dedicated efforts and expertise of each Committee member result in the excellent Technical Program offered each year. The Committee reaches out to all segments of the energy industry so that the state-of-the-art (and beyond) in coal utilization is presented. Through their hard work, we continue to provide a world-renowned conference each year.</s>
    <s>&gt; This year's Conference Committee members are:</s>
    <s>&gt; Air Products &amp; Chemicals, Mark D’Agostini</s>
    <s>American Electric Power , J.J. Letcavits</s>
    <s>ASME Power Div.: Dr. Ashwani Gupta, University of Maryland</s>
    <s>Arizona State University, Dr. Andrew V.G. Chizmeshya</s>
    <s>The Babcock &amp; Wilcox Company, Hamid Sarv</s>
    <s>Babcock Power, Inc., Bonnie Courtemanche, P.E.</s>
    <s>CanmetENERGY, Canada, Dr. Ligang Zheng</s>
    <s>Clyde Bergemann, Dr. Edmundo Vásquez</s>
    <s>Columbia University, Dr. Klaus Lackner</s>
    <s>Government Contracting Specialists, Philip W. Winkler</s>
    <s>Detroit Edison, Anthony Widenman</s>
    <s>Doosan Babcock Energy Limited, Scotland, Gerry Hesselmann</s>
    <s>Energy &amp; Environmental Research Center, University of North Dakota, Christopher Zygarlilcke</s>
    <s>Foster Wheeler North America Corp., Horst Hack</s>
    <s>Fuel Tech Inc., Chris Smyrniotis</s>
    <s>Gas Technology Institute, Howard Meyer</s>
    <s>Illinois Clean Coal Institute, Joseph Hirschi</s>
    <s>Leonardo Technologies, Inc., Massood Ramezan</s>
    <s>Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Dr. Janos M. Beer</s>
    <s>Northeastern University, Yiannis Levendis</s>
    <s>Ontario Power Generation, Canada, Les Marshall</s>
    <s>Pennsylvania State University, EMS Energy Institute, Bruce G. Miller</s>
    <s>Praxair, Inc., Dr. Lawrence Bool</s>
    <s>Savannah River National Laboratory, Steve Xiao</s>
    <s>Siemens Environmental Systems &amp; Services, Alan Paschedag</s>
    <s>Tampa Electric Co., Yogesh M. Patel</s>
    <s>Technische Universität Hamburg-Harburg, Germany, Dr. Alfons Kather</s>
    <s>Tsinghua University, People's Republic of China, Prof. Yao Qiang</s>
    <s>University of Alberta , Prof. Rajender Gupta</s>
    <s>University of Newcastle, Australia, Dr. Terry Wall</s>
    <s>University of Stuttgart, Germany, Prof.-Dr. Klaus R.G. Hein (Co-chairman)</s>
    <s>University of Utah, Presidential Professor Adel F. Sarofim</s>
    <s>U. S. Geological Survey, Ron Affolter</s>
    <s>Xstrata Coal, Australia, Dave Osborne</s>
    <s>&gt; BACKGROUND -- Nearly 300 professionals representing nearly all the major players in the electric utility industry in the United States were in Clearwater, Florida, USA for the 36th International Technical Conference on Clean Coal &amp; Fuel Systems (informally known as “the Clearwater Clean Coal Conference”) from June 5 to 9, 2011. The Clearwater Clean Coal Conference has earned a reputation as one of the premiere conferences on coal technologies as it grows in size and scope since its inception in 1975.</s>
    <s>&gt; The Clearwater Clean Coal Conference offers participants 150 technical presentations in four days (Monday through Thursday from 8:00 a.m. to 6:00 p.m. in five concurrent sessions). Buffet style luncheons, and a fabulous beach reception on Tuesday night offer networking opportunities with 300 conference participants. Pre-conference tutorials held on Sunday provide opportunities to learn about state-of-the-art and cutting-edge technologies. In addition, panels on the important energy issues of the day are also scheduled on the four-day agenda.</s>
    <s>&gt; Buffet style luncheons, and a fabulous beach reception on Tuesday night offer networking opportunities with 300 conference participants. Twelve tutorials held on Sunday and Monday provide opportunities to learn about state-of-the-art and cutting-edge technologies.</s>
    <s>&gt; An Exhibit Center showcasing 24 booths also provide opportunities to highlight accomplishments and achievements. The conference is held every year in Clearwater, Florida, at the Sheraton Sand Key Resort. We expect warm and sunny days with temperatures during the day in the 80’s. To take advantage of our glorious beach locale we offer all lunches out on the beach under our spacious tent.</s>
    <s>&gt; THEMED LUNCHEON – A conference favorite is the Themed Luncheon on Wednesday. Industry leaders host tables of 8 where a specific topic is chosen by the host for discussion during lunch. Lunch this day is expanded to 90 minutes to allow sufficient time for as much discussion as possible.</s>
    <s>&gt; Best Student Paper Award – Over the years the conference has benefitted from the many excellent papers given by students. To give these exceptional students well-deserved recognition, the Conference Committee now awards the best paper from a student with the Clearwater Coal Conference Best Student Paper Award. Guidelines for Student Papers 2012.pdf</s>
    <s>&gt; Student Recruitment – In addition, the Conference will facilitate students meeting with potential employers at the conference. Through a specific site in the Exhibit Center, we will notify students of those companies who are seeking candidates and facilitate their getting together. In addition, we are exploring the possibility of organizing one of the luncheons along the lines of the Themed Luncheon where we will have &quot;seniors&quot; and &quot;juniors&quot; seated at luncheon tables to facilitate the exchange of information and ideas. More information on this will be available in early 2011. To further encourage student participation the Conference Committee offers a reduced registration fee of $395 for students currently enrolled in a college or university.</s>
    <s>&gt; INTERNATIONAL PROGRAMS – TECHNICAL DEVELOPMENTS – POLICY ISSUES</s>
    <s>&gt; Papers from the international community are strongly encouraged. In the 2011 conference 23 countries were represented at the conference. In addition, one-third of all attendees were from the international community. The international papers were related to energy/environmental developments throughout the world. The Committee also encourages papers that deal specifically with the topics covered in the Keynote Session, Panels, Tutorials and Plenary Sessions</s>
    <s>&gt; CALL FOR PAPERS</s>
    <s>2012 CLEARWATER COAL CONFERENCE – ABSTRACT REQUIREMENTS</s>
    <s>The abstract (one page in length), required by January 21, 2012, must be submitted via email and include:</s>
    <s>The Proposed Paper with Exact Title and one page of information (no equations and no figures). The abstract must summarize the objective and current status of the work; and provide the committee with an accurate scope of the paper. Please indicate under which Technical Topics To Be Presented this paper falls. You should also indicate the name of the session chair if this also pertains to your paper.</s>
    <s>Principal Presenter Listing (name, title, company, address, phone, FAX and email). Email addresses are required since this will be the primary mode of communication.</s>
    <s>Complete Listings for all Co-Authors (name, title, company, address, phone, FAX and email).</s>
    <s>&gt; The Principal Presenter must provide the information and is the person to whom all correspondence will be sent and who must meet the deadlines and obligations of the conference, which include: making a presentation at the 2012 conference; submitting a manuscript; and paying a conference fee.</s>
    <s>&gt; The Principal Presenter is eligible for a discount and must remit the non-refundable registration fee of $795 before February 10, 2012. There is no reimbursement for time spent or expenses incurred in preparing manuscripts or illustrations, or for transportation to, and expenses at the conference.</s>
    <s>&gt; The Clearwater Clean Coal Conference does not provide financial support to authors. The registration fee covers one technical paper; authors submitting more than one paper must include an additional $100 per paper.</s>
    <s>&gt; Notification of acceptance will be made by February 10, 2012. A manuscript for inclusion in the Proceedings and for distribution on CD-Rom (not to exceed 12 pages in length, with illustrative material) is required by April 16, 2012.</s>
    <s>&gt; Instructions for preparation of manuscripts (Proceedings and CD-Rom) will be sent with letters of acceptance. Presentations will be scheduled in Panels, Technical and/or Poster Sessions, as determined by the Conference Committee. The one-page abstract should be sent via email to BarbaraSak@aol.com .</s>
    <s>&gt; To encourage the participation of students, the Conference Committee is offering a reduced registration of $395. In addition, one student paper will be awarded the Best Student Paper at the 2012 Clearwater Clean Coal Conference. The student will be evaluated in the quality of the paper, grasp of the topic presented and quality of the presentation at the conference. The student must be present to win.</s>
    <s>&gt; Complete details on participation (important dates, fees, etc.) may be found in the Guidelines for Authors. Guidelines for Speakers 2012.pdf</s>
    <s>&gt; TECHNICAL TOPICS TO BE COVERED AT THE 2012 CLEARWATER COAL CONFERENCE</s>
    <s>&gt; The program covers innovative and evolving technologies in a forum that encourages the exchange of information on power generation and policy issues. The State-of-the-Art in coal utilization will be presented in up-to-date technical papers, tutorials, plenary sessions and panels, covering cutting-edge developments on a range of timely topics. The presentations will deal with technical solutions to problems; specific strategies; projects; innovations; industry trends; and/or regulatory compliance.</s>
    <s>&gt; ADVANCED POWER CYCLES for electric utility applications at new and existing power plants, such as:</s>
    <s>&gt;Hydrogen from Coal</s>
    <s>&gt;Clean Coal Power Plant Initiative</s>
    <s>&gt;Oxy-Fuel Technology</s>
    <s>&gt;Computer Simulations &amp; Virtual Power Plants</s>
    <s>&gt;Advanced Instrumentation, Sensors and Control Systems</s>
    <s>&gt;Systems Analysis and Integration</s>
    <s>&gt;Turbine Systems for Advanced Power Plants</s>
    <s>&gt;Advanced Materials Development &amp; Performance</s>
    <s>&gt;Advanced Power Systems</s>
    <s>&gt;Integrated Gasification Combined Cycle (IGCC)</s>
    <s>&gt;Clean Transportation Fuels from Coal</s>
    <s>&gt;NOx Control</s>
    <s>&gt;Clean Coal Demos and Pilot Projects</s>
    <s>&gt;Coal Compatible Fuel Cells</s>
    <s>&gt;Gas and Steam Turbines</s>
    <s>&gt;Coal Combustion (PC, fluidized bed)</s>
    <s>&gt;Advanced Gas Separations and Gas Cleaning</s>
    <s>&gt;Chemical Looping</s>
    <s>&gt; ENVIRONMENTAL &amp; HEALTH ASPECTS</s>
    <s>&gt;Fine particulate matter (PM 2.5); NOx, SO2 and SO3 Emissions</s>
    <s>&gt;Mercury Emissions Control</s>
    <s>&gt;CO2 Capture, Storage and Sequestration</s>
    <s>&gt;Global Climate Change</s>
    <s>&gt;Costs of Environmental Controls</s>
    <s>&gt;CO2 Capture-Ready Technology</s>
    <s>&gt; PRODUCTS &amp; BY-PRODUCTS</s>
    <s>&gt;Fossil Fuel Carbon Products/By-Products</s>
    <s>&gt;By-Product Issues</s>
    <s>&gt;Ash Utilization</s>
    <s>&gt;Ash Disposal &amp; Emulsions</s>
    <s>&gt; RESOURCE UTILIZATION ISSUES</s>
    <s>&gt;Availability and Recoverability of Clean and Compliant Coal Resources</s>
    <s>&gt;Coal Quality and Trace Elements from the Mine to the Stack</s>
    <s>&gt;Advances in Mining Technology</s>
    <s>&gt;Clean Transportation Fuels from Coal</s>
    <s>&gt;CO2 Transportation Pipelines</s>
    <s>&gt;Biomass &amp; Refuse Derived Fuels</s>
    <s>&gt;Coal (including conventional slurries; coal water fuels; coal fines; and coal logs)</s>
    <s>&gt;Mine Tailings; Ash Disposal &amp; Emulsions</s>
    <s>&gt;Beneficiation, Preparation and Utilization of Coal-based Fuels</s>
    <s>&gt; THE UTILITY PERSPECTIVE</s>
    <s>&gt;Upgrading Existing Plants</s>
    <s>&gt;Impact of Deregulation</s>
    <s>&gt;Regulatory and/or Permitting Issues</s>
    <s>&gt;Economic and Financial Perspectives (including carbon credits)</s>
    <s>&gt;Distributed Generation</s>
    <s>&gt;Issues Regarding Utilization of Powder River Basin Coal</s>
    <s>&gt;Operational Issues</s>
    <s>&gt;Utility Water Use</s>
    <s>&gt;On-line Boiler Monitoring</s>
    <s>&gt;Coal Quality/Performance Predictions</s>
    <s>&gt;Advances in Coal Blending/Switching</s>
    <s>&gt;Power Plant Reliability</s>
    <s>ENDORSING ORGANIZATIONS</s>
    <s>WHO WILL ATTEND</s>
    <s>American Public Power Association</s>
    <s>China Coal Research Institute, Ministry of Coal Industry, People's Republic of China</s>
    <s>Edison Electric Institute</s>
    <s>Illinois Department of Commerce and Economic Opportunity: Office of Coal Development &amp; Marketing</s>
    <s>International Energy Agency: Coal Research</s>
    <s>Japan Coal Energy Center</s>
    <s>National Mining Association</s>
    <s>National Rural Electric Cooperative Association</s>
    <s>Ohio Coal Development Office</s>
    <s>U.S. Department of Commerce, Export Assistance</s>
    <s>U. S. Geological Survey</s>
    <s>Utility Plant Managers</s>
    <s>Utility Fuel Purchasers</s>
    <s>Operations &amp; Maintenance Providers</s>
    <s>Independent Power Producers</s>
    <s>Government Officials</s>
    <s>Fuel Suppliers</s>
    <s>Academicians and Students</s>
    <s>Project Developers</s>
    <s>Financial Managers</s>
    <s>Coal Technology Companies</s>
    <s>Materials Handling Specialists</s>
    <s>R &amp; D Firms</s>
    <s>A &amp; E Firms</s>
    <s>Coal Producers &amp; Mining Companies</s>
    <s>Environmental Consultants/Emissions Controls Specialists</s>
    <s>Materials &amp; Equipment Suppliers</s>
    <s>Pipeline Companies</s>
    <s>&gt; SHERATON SAND KEY RESORT</s>
    <s>&gt; Sand Key is one of the 20 Best Beaches, according to many travel and tourism organizations. Directly on this beautiful beach is the Sheraton Sand Key, a 390-room luxury hotel. Each of the hotel’s newly refurbished rooms overlooks either the Gulf of Mexico or Clearwater Bay. Its seven secluded acres of white sandy beach set a tropical holiday mood for registrants to meet and discuss timely topics with colleagues from all over the globe.</s>
    <s>&gt; CONFERENCE HEADQUARTERS</s>
    <s>&gt; Sheraton Sand Key</s>
    <s>1160 Gulf Boulevard</s>
    <s>Clearwater, Florida</s>
    <s>Phone: 727-595-1611</s>
    <s>FAX: 727-596-8488</s>
    <s>$179/night – Single or Double</s>
    <s>Visit http://www.beachsand.com for information about the Sheraton Sand Key</s>
    <s>&gt; Overflow Hotels</s>
    <s>&gt; We're working with a number of properties on Clearwater Beach who have very competitive rates and are within walking distance (approximately 1 mile) to the Sheraton Sand Key (for those who like to walk).</s>
    <s>&gt; Ramada Inn Gulfview</s>
    <s>521 S. Gulfview Blvd.</s>
    <s>Clearwater, Florida 33767</s>
    <s>Phone: 727/447-6461</s>
    <s>FAX: 727/443-5888</s>
    <s>Email: info@ramadagulfview.com</s>
    <s>&gt; Sands Point Motel &amp; Suites</s>
    <s>433 Coronado Drive</s>
    <s>Clearwater Beach, Florida 33767</s>
    <s>Phone: 727-446-5608 or 1-800-433-2362</s>
    <s>FAX: 727-442-7892</s>
    <s>Email: sandspointmotel@msn.com</s>
    <s>Web: www.SandsPointMotel.com</s>
    <s>Rates: $65/day to $550/week</s>
    <s>&gt; CONFERENCE ATTIRE</s>
    <s>&gt; We're encouraging all speakers and attendees to adopt a business casual dress, i.e., no jackets or ties. This covers speakers, session chairmen, panel and tutorial chairs and speakers. Almost all of the food functions are outside and a business casual dress will make the long conference day and the outdoor functions more comfortable.</s>
    <s>&gt; COAL: RISING TO NEW CHALLENGES</s>
    <s>&gt; The 35th International Technical Conference on</s>
    <s>&gt; Clean Coal &amp; Fuel Systems Agenda</s>
    <s>&gt; June 6 to 10, 2010</s>
    <s>&gt; Clearwater, Florida, USA</s>
    <s>&gt; Our Best Student Paper Award winner was Aaron Fuller, University of Stuttgart.</s>
    <s>&gt; To see all of the panels, tutorials, technical sessions, exhibitors, etc. click 2010 Program Announcement.pdf</s>
    <s>&gt; COAL: WORLD ENERGY SECURITY</s>
    <s>&gt; The 34th International Technical Conference on</s>
    <s>&gt; Clean Coal &amp; Fuel Systems Agenda</s>
    <s>&gt; May 31 - June 4, 2009</s>
    <s>&gt; Clearwater, Florida, USA</s>
    <s>&gt; To see all of the panels, tutorials, technical sessions and exhibitors, just click 2009 Official Prog.pdf</s>
    <s>&gt; Our Best Student Paper Award Winners were:</s>
    <s>&gt; Laura Bradley of Pennsylvania State University and Charles Reid, University of Utah.</s>
    <s>&gt; The 33rd International Technical Conference on Coal Utilization &amp; Fuel Systems</s>
    <s>June 1 – 5, 2008</s>
    <s>Sheraton Sand Key, Clearwater, Florida, USA</s>
    <s>&gt; was successfully concluded in Clearwater, Florida. To see the Official Program and Exhibit Directory for this conference just click here 2008 Official Program.pdf</s>
    <s>&gt; Presented by</s>
    <s>&gt;Coal Technology Association &amp;</s>
    <s>&gt;American Society of Mechanical Engineers – Power Division http://www.asme.org/divisions/power</s>
    <s>&gt; Coal Technologies Associates</s>
    <s>12548 Granite Ridge Drive</s>
    <s>North Potomac, MD USA 20878</s>
    <s>&gt; Attention: Barbara A. Sakkestad</s>
    <s>&gt; Phone: 301/330-2256</s>
    <s>&gt; E-mail: BarbaraSak@aol.com</s>
    <s>!Hit Counter</s>
  </text>
</page>
