<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://sf2011.meego.com/news/meego-2011-conference-call-papers</url>
  <title>MeeGo 2011 Conference Call For Papers | MeeGo Conference San ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>MeeGo 2011 Conference Call For Papers. Submitted by Dirk Hohndel on Tue, 2011-03-01 17:10. Following up on the success of the Dublin conference, the </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Jump to Navigation</s>
    <s>MeeGo Conference San Francisco May 23-25, 2011</s>
    <s>Register for the conference!</s>
    <s>MeeGo 2011 Conference Call For Papers</s>
    <s>Submitted by Dirk Hohndel on Tue, 2011-03-01 17:10</s>
    <s>Following up on the success of the Dublin conference, the global developer community around MeeGo is set to reunite in San Francisco for the MeeGo Conference Spring 2011.</s>
    <s>From application developers to platform designers, hardware vendors to open source enthusiasts, anyone engaged in MeeGo is invited to contribute and participate at the San Francisco Regency Hyatt, California, USA, from May 23rd-25th, 2011.</s>
    <s>We are inviting proposals for presentations in a wide variety of areas:</s>
    <s>Device/Product development</s>
    <s>App development</s>
    <s>Platform development</s>
    <s>MeeGo project, process, and progress</s>
    <s>We also welcome submissions on any other MeeGo related topics. Be creative, the program committee will look at each and every submission, to create a vibrant and interesting conference. This includes community and open source related proposals, as well as commercial or proprietary developments around MeeGo. Proposals are due by March 18 at 11:59 PM Pacific Time. Learn more about the requirements and other details by visiting the call for papers page.</s>
    <s>Login or register to post comments</s>
    <s>Follow &amp; Share</s>
    <s>meego.com Home</s>
    <s>About MeeGo</s>
    <s>Privacy Policy</s>
    <s>Terms of Service</s>
    <s>Linux is a registered trademark of Linus Torvalds.</s>
    <s>MeeGo is a registered trademark of The Linux Foundation.</s>
    <s>Other names and brands may be claimed as the property of others.</s>
    <s>Built on COD, the open source conference and event management solution.</s>
  </text>
</page>
