<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://britishlibrary.typepad.co.uk/digitisedmanuscripts/2011/03/royal-conference-call-for-papers.html</url>
  <title>Royal Conference Call for Papers - Medieval and Earlier Manuscripts</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Mar 3, 2011 In 1757 King George II presented the approximately 2000 manuscripts of the royal library to the recently founded British Museum.</s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Medieval and Earlier Manuscripts</s>
    <s>The Medieval and Earlier Manuscripts Blog is written by curators in the British Library's Department of History and Classics. It publicises all aspects of the Library's work on western manuscripts produced before 1600, including our digitisation and cataloguing projects, exhibitions and publications.</s>
    <s>bl.uk Latest Royal Digitised manuscripts Illuminated manuscripts !RSS Subscribe</s>
    <s>!Detail from Harley MS 4425, Roman de la Rose</s>
    <s>Detail from Harley MS 4425, Roman de la Rose</s>
    <s>From our curators in the MEM team</s>
    <s>October 2011</s>
    <s>September 2011</s>
    <s>August 2011</s>
    <s>July 2011</s>
    <s>June 2011</s>
    <s>May 2011</s>
    <s>April 2011</s>
    <s>March 2011</s>
    <s>February 2011</s>
    <s>January 2011</s>
    <s>Featured manuscripts</s>
    <s>Greek Manuscripts</s>
    <s>Illuminated manuscripts</s>
    <s>Labours of the month</s>
    <s>Recent Posts</s>
    <s>The Royal Exhibition on Facebook</s>
    <s>More Greek manuscripts go online</s>
    <s>The Spy's Choirbook</s>
    <s>Register now for the Royal Conference</s>
    <s>A Calendar Page for October</s>
    <s>Royal events at the British Library</s>
    <s>Beowulf in Hungarian and French and Telugu </s>
    <s>John Lydgate's Lives of Saints</s>
    <s>Dialogue de la duchesse de Bourgogne</s>
    <s>Bookmark and share this blog with digg, del.icio.us, etc:</s>
    <s>Powered by TypePad</s>
    <s>« A Calendar Page for March | Main | Not Just Pretty Faces »</s>
    <s>03 March 2011</s>
    <s>Royal Conference Call for Papers</s>
    <s>In 1757 King George II presented the approximately 2,000 manuscripts of the royal library to the recently founded British Museum. These manuscripts, collected by the kings and queens of England from the 9th to the 16th centuries, form the unique collection held by the British Library, known simply as 'Royal.' The Royal Collection preserves the medieval and Renaissance libraries of the kings and queens of England, and includes within these illuminated manuscripts most of the surviving medieval paintings owned by them.</s>
    <s>From 11 November to 11 March 2012, approximately 150 Royal manuscripts will be featured in a major exhibition at the British Library. The research for this exhibition has been funded by a grant from the Arts and Humanities Research Council. The research team is headed by Dr Scot McKendrick, Head of History and Classics, the British Library, and Professor John Lowden, Courtauld Institute of Art, University of London.</s>
    <s>As part of this project the British Library will hold an international conference in December 2011 to encourage collaboration on these manuscripts and discussion of contextual issues of power, stylistic influence, political motivations and rivalries with Europe, public and private devotion, education and knowledge, and artistic production in a variety of media.</s>
    <s>Scholars from all disciplines are invited to submit proposals for twenty-minute papers. We hope to have sessions on the historical context and formation of the Royal collection, conservation and preservation issues, buildings and royal palaces, and inventories and medieval libraries, in addition to papers devoted to illuminated manuscripts in the Royal collection. Papers that treat renowned Royal manuscripts and those focusing on lesser-known manuscripts are equally welcome. The conference proceedings will be published by British Library Publications.</s>
    <s>If you would like to take part, please send a short abstract and a concise CV by 31 May 2011 to Dr Kathleen Doyle, Curator of Illuminated Manuscripts, kathleen.doyle@bl.uk, or The British Library, 96 Euston Road, London, NW1 2DB.</s>
    <s>Catalogue of Illuminated Manuscripts</s>
    <s>Posted at 04:37 PM in Illuminated manuscripts, Medieval, Projects, Royal | Permalink</s>
    <s>You can follow this conversation by subscribing to the comment feed for this post.</s>
    <s>Verify your Comment</s>
    <s>Previewing your Comment</s>
    <s>Posted by: |</s>
    <s>This is only a preview. Your comment has not yet been posted.</s>
    <s>Your comment could not be posted. Error type:</s>
    <s>Your comment has been saved. Comments are moderated and will not appear until approved by the author. Post another comment</s>
    <s>The letters and numbers you entered did not match the image. Please try again.</s>
    <s>As a final step before posting your comment, enter the letters and numbers you see in the image below. This prevents automated programs from posting comments.</s>
    <s>Having trouble reading this image? View an alternate.</s>
    <s>Post a comment</s>
    <s>Comments are moderated, and will not appear until the author has approved them.</s>
    <s>Comment below or sign in with TypePad Facebook Twitter and more </s>
    <s>You are currently signed in as (nobody). Sign Out</s>
    <s>Your Information</s>
    <s>(Name is required. Email address will not be displayed with the comment.)</s>
    <s>Name is required to post a comment</s>
    <s>Please enter a valid email address</s>
    <s>Invalid URL</s>
    <s>Email address:</s>
  </text>
</page>
