<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>en</lang>  <url>http://mikeg.typepad.com/perceptions/2011/01/enterprise-20-conference-call-for-papers-community-voting-process.html</url>
  <title>Enterprise 2.0 Conference: Call For Papers Community, Voting ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Jan 10, 2011 For the upcoming Enterprise 2.0 conference in Boston this year, I have submitted three sessions that I hope the community finds helpful and </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Collaborative Thinking</s>
    <s>Perceptions on collaboration and social networking by Mike Gotta. The opinions expressed in this blog are my own views and not those of Cisco.</s>
    <s>« Drawing Parallels &amp; Making Connections Between Youth &amp; Employee Learning | Main | Thoughts On Salesforce &amp; DimDim »</s>
    <s>January 10, 2011</s>
    <s>Enterprise 2.0 Conference: Call For Papers Community, Voting Process</s>
    <s>For the upcoming Enterprise 2.0 conference in Boston this year, I have submitted three sessions that I hope the community finds helpful and relevant. If you find them valuable, I hope you take the time to participate in the community process and vote for these proposals. Thanks!</s>
    <s>Session Descriptions:</s>
    <s>In this session, I want to objectively look at the use case scenarios that HR and their support teams in IT should examine when they consider the social networking aspects of E2.0. It is definitely not specific to any one vendor. The session will connect the process, cultural, and tooling aspects of profiles, social graphs, etc. in the context of talent, learning, and community. There are interesting areas of how the combination of participation and tools enable employees to establish an identity different than the one assigned to them by the enterprise, and take on social roles (wiki gardener, idea person, answer person, expert) that augment formal structures used to identify talent. Employees can also leverage the participatory culture of E2.0 to create their own informal learning environments.</s>
    <s>&gt; From Hire To Retire: The Role Of Social Networking</s>
    <s>&gt; Whether you are a new or seasoned employee, our ability to leverage personal and professional networks helps us transition and excel in new roles, relationships, and collaborative work. This session will help HR and IT teams learn how social networking improves the effectiveness of strategic talent, learning, and community-building initiatives.</s>
    <s>&gt; Attendee Benefit</s>
    <s>&gt; Attendees will walk away with common use case scenarios that they can use within their own organization to help: create a business case, identify potential solutions, or define criteria for selection of social networking tools.</s>
    <s>In the session below, I wanted to bring together some pragmatic thought leaders to debate the different sides of how Enterprise 2.0 influences business and organizational strategies. Sara Roberts is very active in the area of transformation and Dan just finished a book (Management by Design). I will add at least one more panelist but this session looks at E2.0 through the lens of the multi-generational workforce - not just GenY but the implications of boomers (retirees, alumni). The discussion is non-technological - and more about topcis related to leadership, communication, dealing with change, and the synergies or tensions you might expect as different generations have different expectations and values.</s>
    <s>&gt; The Multi-generational Workforce: Navigating Culture, Behavior, &amp; Change</s>
    <s>&gt; Leadership teams face a multi-generational workforce with different expectations, values, and work styles. E2.0 efforts can help improve employee engagement, collaboration, and knowledge sharing. This session will debate the shifts that lay ahead and what organizations need to do about them: social networking, talent, learning, and changing notions of public/private.</s>
    <s>&gt; Moderator: Mike Gotta</s>
    <s>&gt; Panelists: Sara Roberts, Dan Rasmus, others TBD</s>
    <s>&gt; Attendee Benefit</s>
    <s>&gt; Attendees will understand key trends in the market related to HR (attract/retain employees, talent), innovation (employee-led ideation), career development (learning, expertise), and the implications of a growing digital lifestyle on the workplace (mobility, social networking).</s>
    <s>This last session deals with risk. We have to balance the sometimes irrational exuberance with &quot;all things social&quot; with the need to mitigate risks. That does not mean &quot;saying no&quot; - it does mean understanding the use case scenarios, identifying the potential vulnerabilities, and defining the policies, practices, and tools needed to mitigate those risks to an acceptable level. For this session, I am &quot;getting the band back together&quot; by inviting some colleagues of mine. We should end up with 3-4 people on this panel. The goal is to raise awareness and offer practical advice.</s>
    <s>&gt; Social Media &amp; Social Networking: A Cautionary Tale</s>
    <s>&gt; Social media (Twitter, LinkedIn) and enterprise social networking solutions (profiles, activity streams, social analytics) can deliver compelling business value. However, benefits do not come without risks. This panel discussion with experts and practitioners will provide insight as to the policy, governance, and security issues warranted to mitigate risks.</s>
    <s>&gt; Moderator: Mike Gotta</s>
    <s>&gt; Panelists: Doug Cornelius, Alice Wang</s>
    <s>&gt; Attendee Benefit</s>
    <s>&gt; Attendees will gain an understanding of potential risk factors associated with social media and social networking and options available that can help mitigate risks within their organization.</s>
    <s>January 10, 2011 in Enterprise 2.0 | Permalink</s>
    <s>TrackBack URL for this entry:</s>
    <s>Listed below are links to weblogs that reference Enterprise 2.0 Conference: Call For Papers Community, Voting Process</s>
    <s>You can follow this conversation by subscribing to the comment feed for this post.</s>
    <s>Verify your Comment</s>
    <s>Previewing your Comment</s>
    <s>Posted by: |</s>
    <s>This is only a preview. Your comment has not yet been posted.</s>
    <s>Your comment could not be posted. Error type:</s>
    <s>Your comment has been saved. Comments are moderated and will not appear until approved by the author. Post another comment</s>
    <s>The letters and numbers you entered did not match the image. Please try again.</s>
    <s>As a final step before posting your comment, enter the letters and numbers you see in the image below. This prevents automated programs from posting comments.</s>
    <s>Having trouble reading this image? View an alternate.</s>
    <s>Post a comment</s>
    <s>Comments are moderated, and will not appear until the author has approved them.</s>
    <s>Comment below or sign in with TypePad Facebook Twitter and more </s>
    <s>You are currently signed in as (nobody). Sign Out</s>
    <s>(URLs automatically linked.)</s>
    <s>Your Information</s>
    <s>(Name and email address are required. Email address will not be displayed with the comment.)</s>
    <s>Name is required to post a comment</s>
    <s>Please enter a valid email address</s>
    <s>Invalid URL</s>
    <s>Email address:</s>
    <s>Become a Fan</s>
    <s>Twitter Updates</s>
    <s>follow me on Twitter</s>
    <s>Subscribe to Collaborative Thinking</s>
    <s>Recent Posts</s>
    <s>Abstract: Modern Social Imaginaries</s>
    <s>Abstract: Tweet Tweet Retweet: Conversational Aspects of Retweeting on Twitter.</s>
    <s>Enterprise 2.0 Workshop: Organization Next (Screencast Overview)</s>
    <s>Enterprise 2.0 Five Years Later: From Tools To Platforms To Ecosystems</s>
    <s>Driving Organizational Change with Social &amp; Collaborative Technologies</s>
    <s>Leveraging Use Case Scenarios To Illustrate Social Media &amp; Social Networking Risks</s>
    <s>The Human Network: Adding Social Context To Enterprise Architecture</s>
    <s>Adding Social Context To Enterprise Architecture</s>
    <s>Organization Next: Managing the Networked Workspace</s>
    <s>Participation Models: Observations On The Future Of Civic Engagement</s>
    <s>Attention Management</s>
    <s>Business IT Alignment</s>
    <s>Enterprise 2.0</s>
    <s>future technology</s>
    <s>Gov 2.0</s>
    <s>In The News</s>
    <s>Instant Messaging</s>
    <s>Knowledge Management</s>
    <s>Media Studies MA Class</s>
    <s>Open Source</s>
    <s>Prediction Markets</s>
    <s>Quick Take</s>
    <s>Social Networking &amp; Collaboration</s>
    <s>Social Software</s>
    <s>social media</s>
    <s>social responsibility</s>
    <s>Unified Communications</s>
    <s>Web Conferencing</s>
    <s>XML Syndication</s>
    <s>Subscribe to this blog's feed</s>
    <s>Add me to your TypePad People list</s>
    <s>October 2011</s>
    <s>June 2011</s>
    <s>April 2011</s>
    <s>March 2011</s>
    <s>February 2011</s>
    <s>January 2011</s>
    <s>November 2010</s>
    <s>October 2010</s>
    <s>September 2010</s>
    <s>August 2010</s>
    <s>Visitor Map</s>
    <s>See how we're connected</s>
    <s>October 2011</s>
    <s>Sun Mon Tue Wed Thu Fri Sat</s>
    <s>Book Roll</s>
    <s>Robert L. Cross: The Hidden Power of Social Networks: Understanding How Work Really Gets Done in Organizations</s>
    <s>David Knoke: Social Network Analysis (Quantitative Applications in the Social Sciences)</s>
    <s>John P Scott: Social Network Analysis: A Handbook</s>
    <s>Martin Kilduff: Social Networks and Organizations</s>
    <s>Linton C. Freeman: The Development of Social Network Analysis: A Study in the Sociology of Science</s>
    <s>Wouter de Nooy: Exploratory Social Network Analysis with Pajek (Structural Analysis in the Social Sciences)</s>
    <s>James Surowiecki: The Wisdom of Crowds</s>
    <s>Malcolm Gladwell: The Tipping Point: How Little Things Can Make a Big Difference</s>
    <s>Malcolm Gladwell: Blink : The Power of Thinking Without Thinking</s>
    <s>George S. Day: Peripheral Vision: Detecting the Weak Signals That Will Make or Break Your Company</s>
    <s>Collaborative Thinking</s>
    <s>Powered by TypePad</s>
  </text>
</page>
