<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <query keywords="conférence appel à soumissions" position="8" lang="fr" date="2011-10-12"/>
  <url>http://girlsactionfoundation.ca/en/events/appel-de-soumissions-pour-etudes-en-action-2011-une-conference-qui-relie-les-etudiant-e-s-avec-l-engagement-communautaire</url>
  <title>Appel de soumissions pour Études en Action 2011: Une conférence ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Jan 17, 2011 Appel de soumissions pour Études en Action 2011: Une conférence qui relie les étudiant-e-s avec l&#39;engagement communautaire/ Call for </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Why girls</s>
    <s>Light a spark</s>
    <s>Get Involved</s>
    <s>Appel de soumissions pour Études en Action 2011: Une conférence qui relie les étudiant-e-s avec l’engagement communautaire/ Call for submissions: Study in Action 2011: An undergraduate conference linking students with community activism</s>
    <s>Submitted by Eliane on Mon, 2011-01-17 16:58</s>
    <s>APPEL DE SOUMISSIONS!!!</s>
    <s>ÉTUDES EN ACTION 2011: Une conference qui relie les etudiant-e-s avec l'engagement communautaire</s>
    <s>DATE DE TOMBÉE POUR LES PROPOSITIONS: 21 janvier 2011.</s>
    <s>Études en action est une conference qui porte sur la justice sociale et environnementale et a ete creee pour relier les etudiant-e-s au premier cycle et l'engagement communautaire. La conference est un espace ou les etudiant-e-s peuvent presenter leur recherche et developper une plus grande connaissance des enjeux sociaux et environnementaux et de creer des liens avec des organismes communautaires.</s>
    <s>Cette annee, la conference aura lieu du 11 au 13 mars 2011 sur le campus de Concordia au centre-ville.</s>
    <s>La conference Études en Action accepte des soumissions en français et en anglais. Prenez note que vous n'avez pas a soumettre une presentation ou un travail complete pour la date limite du 21 janvier, mais seulement une proposition (details ci-dessous) accompagnee d'une breve introduction qui explique en quoi votre projet est relie au mandat de justice sociale et environnementale d'Études en Action.</s>
    <s>Études en action croise non seulement les lignes disciplinaires, mais transcende les frontieres entre les connaissances academiques et populaires. Nous invitons les soumissions a presenter cette realite de la façon la plus innovatrice possible.</s>
    <s>SOUMETTRE UN PROJET EN TANT QU'ORGANISME COMMUNAUTAIRE:</s>
    <s>Veuillez presenter un resume de 250 mots de votre projet ou atelier, incluant le temps requis, le nombre maximum de participants et toutes specifications en ce qui a trait a l'espace ou au materiel requis. Votre participation a la conference peut prendre la forme de:</s>
    <s>a) un atelier interactif de 1 a 2 heures (les ateliers pourront aussi etre consideres comme faisant partie de panels, avec une duree de 15 a 20 minutes)</s>
    <s>b) une presentation audio-visuelle</s>
    <s>c) un conferencier ou un groupe de presentateurs.</s>
    <s>Certains ateliers presentes a la conference de l'annee passee incluaient:</s>
    <s>&quot;Subverting Higher Education&quot;: developper un cours sur la justice environnementale</s>
    <s>&quot;Beyond Shorter Showers&quot;: une introduction a l'ecologie radicale</s>
    <s>&quot;Your Radio is a Bomb&quot;: le pouvoir explosif des medias independants.</s>
    <s>SOUMETTRE EN TANT QU'ARTISTE:</s>
    <s>Veuillez presenter une description de votre oeuvre d'art en 250 mots, precisant comment celle-ci s'inscrit dans le mandat de la conference, ainsi que les dimensions et les parametres d'installation. Si possible, incluez des photos. Des exemples d'oeuvres presentees au cours de la conference de l'an dernier se trouvent dans Convergence, le journal de recherche produit par QPIRG Concordia a l'ete 2010. Venez chercher une copie au bureau des maintenant!</s>
    <s>Veuillez envoyer vos propositions a studyinaction@gmail.com AVANT LE 21 JANVIER 2011.</s>
    <s>Info: qpirgconcordia.org/studyinactionstudyinaction@qpirgconcordia.org514 848 7585</s>
    <s>CALL FOR SUBMISSIONS!</s>
    <s>STUDY IN ACTION 2011: An undergraduate conference linking students with community activism</s>
    <s>DEADLINE FOR PROPOSAL SUBMISSIONS: January 21, 2011</s>
    <s>Study in Action is an undergraduate student conference on social and environmental justice designed to link students and community activism. The conference is a space for students to present research and develop greater knowledge of social and environmental issues and build ties with community organizations.</s>
    <s>This year's conference will take place from March 11-13, 2011 on the downtown Concordia campus.</s>
    <s>The Study in Action conference will accept submissions in English and French. Please note you do not have to submit a completed paper or presentation by our January 21st deadline, but only a proposal (details below) and a brief introduction that explains how your submission relates to Study In Action's mandate of social and environmental justice.</s>
    <s>Study In Action not only crosses disciplinary lines, but also transcends the borders between academic and popular knowledge. We invite submissions to interpret our mandate as innovatively as possible.</s>
    <s>SUBMITTING AS A COMMUNITY ORGANIZATION:</s>
    <s>Please provide a 250-word summary of your proposed presentation of workshop, including estimates of how much time will be required, a maximum number of attendees, and any other specifications relating to space or supplies that you will need. Your conference presentation may be:</s>
    <s>a) a 1-2 hour interactive workshop (please note: workshop presentations may also be considered as part of panels, in a 15-20 minute format).</s>
    <s>b) an audio-visual presentation?</s>
    <s>c) a speaker or panel event co-presented with the conference</s>
    <s>Some workshops that were presented at last year's conference included:</s>
    <s>Subverting Higher Education: developing an environmental justice course</s>
    <s>Beyond Shorter Showers: an introduction to Radical Ecology</s>
    <s>Your Radio is a Bomb: the explosive power and potential of independent media</s>
    <s>SUBMITTING AS AN ARTIST:</s>
    <s>Please provide a 250 word description of the artwork being submitted, including how it relates to the mandate, as well as size and installation parameters. Please provide pictures or samples if possible. Some examples of art that was included in last year's conference can be seen in Convergence, the undergraduate journal produced by QPIRG Concordia in Summer 2010. Pick up your copy at our office anytime</s>
    <s>Please send all submissions to studyinaction@gmail.com BY JANUARY 21, 2011</s>
    <s>Info: qpirgconcordia.org/studyinactionstudyinaction@qpirgconcordia.org514 848 7585</s>
    <s>Event date:</s>
    <s>2011-01-17 - 2011-01-21</s>
    <s>Post new comment</s>
    <s>Comment: *</s>
    <s>This question is for testing whether you are a human visitor and to prevent automated spam submissions.</s>
    <s>!Image CAPTCHA</s>
    <s>What code is in the image?: *</s>
    <s>Enter the characters shown in the image.</s>
    <s>Light a Spark</s>
    <s>Join the MovementBuild a powerful network of women and girls across the country.</s>
    <s>Learning centre</s>
    <s>The tools you need to make a differenceDownload our FREE publications</s>
    <s>National Network</s>
    <s>Harness the power in numbersBecome a member and view the members’ directory</s>
    <s>Young women speak upJoin our blogging community</s>
    <s>Get email updates</s>
    <s>Signup for our newsletter</s>
    <s>Galleries &amp; Videos</s>
    <s>ABOUT US</s>
    <s>GIRLS ACTION FOUNDATION is a non-profit organization dedicated to supporting girls and young women to overcome barriers and reach their true potential.</s>
    <s>We operate on a national scale with a local impact reaching over 60,000 girls and young women annually. Together with our network of over 240 community partners, we deliver cutting-edge programs that provide girls with empowerment, leadership and community action opportunities.</s>
    <s>Find out more about our programs and projects</s>
    <s>Find out about the LIGHT A SPARK campaign</s>
    <s>(C) 2003-10 Girls Action Foundation/Fondation Filles d'Action</s>
    <s>Our mandate</s>
    <s>What we do</s>
    <s>Our Story</s>
    <s>Our Team</s>
    <s>Funders and Supporters</s>
    <s>Impact Stories</s>
    <s>Girls' Programs</s>
    <s>About ELLE</s>
    <s>Leadership Training</s>
    <s>National Retreat</s>
    <s>National Day of Action</s>
    <s>Regional Gatherings</s>
    <s>Special Projects</s>
    <s>Why girls</s>
    <s>Light a spark</s>
    <s>About the campaign</s>
    <s>Girls in Canada Today</s>
    <s>Take action</s>
    <s>Honour your spark</s>
    <s>Sparks Profiles</s>
    <s>Press Room</s>
    <s>Your stories</s>
    <s>Get Involved</s>
    <s>Support Girls Action</s>
    <s>Start Your Own Girls' Program</s>
    <s>Become an intern or a volunteer</s>
    <s>Join our dream team</s>
  </text>
</page>
