<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <query keywords="conférence appel à soumissions" position="2" lang="fr" date="2011-10-12"/>
  <url>http://www.iacl-aidc.org/%3Fcat%3D4</url>
  <title>www.IACL-AIDC.org » Appel de soumissions</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>April 21st, 2010 | Category: Appel de soumissions, Call for papers, Congrès mondial Mexico, Mexico World Congress | Comments are closed </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>The International Association of Constitutional Law | l'Association Internationale de Droit Constitutionnel</s>
    <s>Home | Page d'acceuil</s>
    <s>Events | Activités</s>
    <s>Research groups | Groupes de recherche</s>
    <s>Constitutionalism and Secularism in an Age of Religious Revival: The Challenge of Global and Local Fundamentalisms</s>
    <s>Constitutional responses to terrorism</s>
    <s>Constitutions in context</s>
    <s>Cross-Judicial Fertilization - the Use of Foreign precedents by Constitutional Judges</s>
    <s>Democratic Control of State Resources</s>
    <s>European Constitutional Law</s>
    <s>Subnational Constitutions in Federal and Quasi-Federal Constitutional States</s>
    <s>Teaching Constitutional Law</s>
    <s>Constitutional Studies of Free Trade and Political Economy</s>
    <s>Membership and fees | Adhésion et cotisation</s>
    <s>Adhésion et cotisation</s>
    <s>A propos l'AIDC</s>
    <s>L'AIDC est une association mondiale de constitutionnalistes et de juristes faisant face aux défis sans précédent d'un nouvel ordre mondial.</s>
    <s>Prochaines activités</s>
    <s>Table ronde La mondialisation et constitutionnalisme au 21e siècle Séoul, 19-21 novembre 2009 Un programme sera disponible bientôt. . télécharger le programme ici site web VIIIe Congrès Mondial La question de principe Mexico, 6-10 décembre 2010 Un programme sera disponible bientôt. .télécharger le programme ici site web</s>
    <s>Call for papers: Symposium on Religious Rights and Freedoms, Johannesburg 15-16 September 2011</s>
    <s>By IACL secretariat, on April 6th, 2011</s>
    <s>SAIFAC (a centre of the University of Johannesburg) together with the Faculty of Law, University of the Free State and Jutas are delighted to announce a call for papers for a Symposium on Religious  Rights and Freedoms.    </s>
    <s>Full details are included in this document &gt;&gt;&gt;</s>
    <s>Abstracts must be submitted by 3 May 2011. The conference will be held between 15-16 September </s>
    <s>April 6th, 2011 | Category: Affiliates, Appel de soumissions, Call for papers | Comments are closed</s>
    <s>Call for papers: African Network of Constitutional Lawyers | Appel à Contributions: Réseau Africain de Droit Constitutionnel</s>
    <s>By IACL secretariat, on October 6th, 2010</s>
    <s>The African Network of Constitutional Lawyers (ANCL) will hold its Annual Conference in Rabat, Morocco on 2-5 February 2011.  The theme of the conference is 'The internationalisation of Constitutional Law'.</s>
    <s>Call for papers &gt;&gt;&gt;</s>
    <s>La conférence annuelle du Réseau africain de droit constitutionnel (RADC) se tiendra sa à Rabat, au Maroc les 2-5 Février 2011. Le thème de </s>
    <s>October 6th, 2010 | Category: Affiliates, Appel de soumissions | Comments are closed</s>
    <s>Call for Papers: Tracking Progress in the Protection of Socio-economic rights in Africa | Appel de soumissions: Suivi des progrès réalisés dans la protection des droits socio-économiques en Afrique</s>
    <s>By IACL secretariat, on July 31st, 2010</s>
    <s>The African Network of Constitutional Lawyers' (ANCL) Working Group on Social and Economic Rights in Africa (SERIA) will be hosting a one-day conference on Wednesday 8 September 2010 in Cape Town focussing on tracking progress in the protection of socio-economic rights in Africa. The aim of the conference is to promote discourse on the effective </s>
    <s>July 31st, 2010 | Category: Affiliates, Appel de soumissions, Call for papers | Comments are closed</s>
    <s>Call for papers — World Congress workshop 15 ‘The impact of international law on constitutional principles’ | Appel de communications — congrès mondial atelier 15 « L’impact du droit international sur les principes constitutionnels »</s>
    <s>By IACL secretariat, on April 21st, 2010</s>
    <s>Workshop 15</s>
    <s>This workshop will examine the trend toward the increasing incorporation of rules and principles of international law into domestic constitutions. The trend is most pronounced in the field of human rights and international humanitarian law, though the workshop certainly welcomes studies in other areas of international law as well. We will construe the workshop </s>
    <s>April 21st, 2010 | Category: Appel de soumissions, Call for papers, Congrès mondial Mexico, Mexico World Congress | Comments are closed</s>
    <s>Call for papers — World Congress workshop 1 ‘Electoral systems and constitutional principles’ | Appel de communications — congrès mondial atelier 1 « Les systèmes électoraux et les principes constitutionnels »</s>
    <s>By IACL secretariat, on April 11th, 2010</s>
    <s>World Congress workshop 1</s>
    <s>Electoral systems and constitutional principles</s>
    <s>Elections are an essential element of a democratic system. But electoral systems are not neutral. They reflect and reinforce many of the principles and values that underlie the constitutional order. Sometimes the influence of the electoral system on the constitutional order is obvious and deliberate. Sometimes it is </s>
    <s>April 11th, 2010 | Category: Appel de soumissions, Call for papers, Congrès mondial Mexico, Mexico World Congress | Comments are closed</s>
    <s>Call for papers — World Congress workshop 10 ‘The indivisibility of human rights’ | Appel de communications — congrès mondial atelier 10 « L'indivisibilité des droits de l'homme »</s>
    <s>By IACL secretariat, on April 11th, 2010</s>
    <s>WORKSHOP 10</s>
    <s>THE INDIVISIBILITY OF HUMAN RIGHTS</s>
    <s> Constitutional scholars generally distinguish among three major categories of human rights – classical liberties (status negativus), political rights (status activus) and rights to state benefits (status positivus). However, the position of each of these categories in the national constitutions and in international documents is not identical. Accordingly, classical liberties and </s>
    <s>April 11th, 2010 | Category: Appel de soumissions, Call for papers, Congrès mondial Mexico, Groupes de recherche, Mexico World Congress | Comments are closed</s>
    <s>Appel de communications — congrès mondial atelier 5 « Les constitutions infranationales » | Call for papers — World Congress workshop 5 ‘Subnational constitutions’</s>
    <s>By IACL secretariat, on April 11th, 2010</s>
    <s>Workshop 5</s>
    <s>Subnational Constitutions</s>
    <s>Workshop 5 will provide a forum for the analytical and comparative study of existing and developing subnational constitutions and constitution-like documents in component units. Emerging questions include:</s>
    <s>what counts as a “constitution”;</s>
    <s>how such constitutions differ from federal constitutions and each other;</s>
    <s>how federal constitutions define the space allocated for subnational constitutions (constitutional competency) </s>
    <s>April 11th, 2010 | Category: Appel de soumissions, Call for papers, Congrès mondial Mexico, Mexico World Congress | Comments are closed</s>
    <s>Appel de communications — congrès mondial atelier 13 « Droit contitutionnel latino-américain » | Call for papers — World Congress workshop 13 ‘Latin-American constitutional law’</s>
    <s>By IACL secretariat, on March 29th, 2010</s>
    <s>Atelier 13</s>
    <s>Nouvelles tendances dans le droit constitutionnel latino-américain</s>
    <s>L'Amérique latine a vu un fort développement des principes constitutionnels qui caractérisent les démocraties libérales. De nouvelles constitutions ont été décrétées et les courts suprêmes et constitutionnelles ont renforcé leur rôle comme gardiens de la constitution. La cour interaméricaine des droits de l'homme a accru son autorité </s>
    <s>March 29th, 2010 | Category: Appel de soumissions, Call for papers, Congrès mondial Mexico, Mexico World Congress | Comments are closed</s>
    <s>Call for papers — World Congress workshop 6 ‘Terrorism' | Appel de communications — congrès mondial atelier 6 « Le terrorisme »</s>
    <s>By IACL secretariat, on March 28th, 2010</s>
    <s>World Congress workshop 6</s>
    <s>The rule of law in the age of terrorism</s>
    <s>This workshop is convened upon the initiative by an IACL research group that was established in the Athens World Congress.  Between the Congresses, the research group convened, in November 2009, a two-day workshop where it discussed the particular constitutional challenges that relate to the </s>
    <s>March 28th, 2010 | Category: Appel de soumissions, Call for papers, Congrès mondial Mexico, Groupes de recherche, Mexico World Congress | Comments are closed</s>
    <s>Appel de communications — congrès mondial atelier 8 « Le fédéralisme’ » | Call for papers — World Congress workshop 8 ‘Federalism’</s>
    <s>By IACL secretariat, on March 10th, 2010</s>
    <s>Atelier 8</s>
    <s>Es-ce que le  fédéralisme est un principe constitutionnel?</s>
    <s>Cet atelier est ouvert à tout article traitant d'une large série de questions à propos du fédéralisme et des systèmes fédéraux, centré sur, ou relié d'une certaine manière à, la question générale du principe constitutionnel. Parmi des exemples de questions figurent les suivantes :</s>
    <s>Est-ce que le fédéralisme  </s>
    <s>March 10th, 2010 | Category: Appel de soumissions, Call for papers, Congrès mondial Mexico, Mexico World Congress | Comments are closed</s>
    <s>Older Entries »</s>
    <s>News | Nouvelles</s>
    <s>Constitutional responses to terrorism: Milan workshop December 1-2, 2011</s>
    <s>Provisional programme of the IACL round table, Xi'an, 23 to 27 October 2011</s>
    <s>Call for papers: Symposium on Religious Rights and Freedoms, Johannesburg 15-16 September 2011</s>
    <s>New IACL research group launched: Constitutional studies of free trade and political economy</s>
    <s>Executive Committee of the IACL 2011-2014 | Comité exécutif de l’AIDC 2011-2014</s>
    <s>Events | Activités</s>
    <s>Membership and fees | Adhésion et cotisation</s>
    <s>Adhésion et cotisation</s>
    <s>Organs of the IACL | Organes de l'AIDC</s>
    <s>Research groups | Groupes de recherche</s>
    <s>Constitutional responses to terrorism</s>
    <s>Constitutional Studies of Free Trade and Political Economy</s>
    <s>Constitutionalism and Secularism in an Age of Religious Revival: The Challenge of Global and Local Fundamentalisms</s>
    <s>Constitutions in context</s>
    <s>Cross-Judicial Fertilization - the Use of Foreign precedents by Constitutional Judges</s>
    <s>Democratic Control of State Resources</s>
    <s>European Constitutional Law</s>
    <s>Subnational Constitutions in Federal and Quasi-Federal Constitutional States</s>
    <s>Teaching Constitutional Law</s>
    <s>Statute of the IACL | Les statuts de l'AIDC</s>
    <s>African Network of Constitutional Lawyers | Reseau Africain de Droit Constitutionel</s>
    <s>Asociacion Argentina de Derecho Constitucional</s>
    <s>Asociación de Constitucionalistas de España</s>
    <s>Asociación Peruana de Derecho Constitucional</s>
    <s>Associaçao brasileira dos Constitucionalistas</s>
    <s>Association canadienne des professeurs de droit | Canadian Association of Law Teachers</s>
    <s>Association francaise de droit constitutionnel</s>
    <s>Association Malienne de Droit Constitutionnel</s>
    <s>Associazione Italiana dei Costituzionalisti</s>
    <s>Australasian Association of Constitutional Law</s>
    <s>China Law Society</s>
    <s>Constitutional Law Group (United Kingdom)</s>
    <s>Constitutions repository</s>
    <s>Gesellschaft für Rechtsvergleichung</s>
    <s>Institute of Federalism</s>
    <s>Institute of Law and Public Policy, Moscow</s>
    <s>Institute of Law, Chinese Academy of Social Sciences</s>
    <s>Instituto de Investigaciones Jurídicas de la UNAM</s>
    <s>Reseau Africain de Droit Constitutionel | African Network of Constitutional Lawyers</s>
    <s>Sacher Institute, Hebrew University Jerusalem</s>
    <s>SIPE -- Societas Iuris Publici Europaei</s>
    <s>Venice Commission | Commission de Venise</s>
    <s>Copyright (C) 2011 www.IACL-AIDC.org - All Rights Reserved</s>
    <s>Powered by WordPressAtahualpa Theme by BytesForAll</s>
  </text>
</page>
