<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>fr</lang>  <url>http://culturevisuelle.org/valeur/archives/54</url>
  <title>Colloque Travail et Création Artistique à l&#39;Ere Numérique : Appel à ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>25 oct. 2010 Colloque Travail et Création Artistique à l&#39;Ere Numérique : Appel à areas in which there were very few contributions focussing on the </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>La valeur de l'art Carnet de recherche, par Dominique Sagot-Duvauroux</s>
    <s>À propos</s>
    <s>Colloque Travail et Création Artistique à l'Ere Numérique : Appel à communication</s>
    <s>Lundi 25 octobre 2010</s>
    <s>Par Dominique Sagot-Duvauroux</s>
    <s>International Research Conference</s>
    <s>University of Avignon and the Vaucluse</s>
    <s>Université d’Avignon et des Pays du Vaucluse</s>
    <s>24-27 May 2011</s>
    <s>Organised by Centre Norbert Elias (EHESS, CNRS, UAPV), the Georges Friedmann research laboratory (Paris 1-CNRS), the LHIVIC (EHESS) and the GRANEM (University of Angers)</s>
    <s>with the support of the ANR programme “Forms of communication and their developments”</s>
    <s>Artistic work and creativity in the digital era:</s>
    <s>Images and Sounds</s>
    <s>I/ Conference topic:</s>
    <s>Developments having been induced by digital technologies (notably by the internet and mobile telephony) are today fuelling an abundance of publications. Those that examine the field of culture focus primarily on the reorganisation of the industrial sector and the adoption of new economic models on the one hand; and entirely new ways for audiences to receive and use digital content – audiences who are led to assume traditionally unrelated roles, such as those of producers, prescribers, broadcasters, consumers – on the other hand. Research led in this domain has notably focussed attention on the stakes represented by the digital era in the organisation of various sectors, as well as primary stakeholders, on the distribution of value and methods of remuneration – with the crucial issue of developments in royalties -, on new promotion and distribution strategies, and on the structural particularities of each sector concerned (musical, cinematographic, photography, publishing, etc.). Existing research also covers the economic characteristics of demand for cultural goods and determinants of consumption, notably highlighting the relationship between the digital revolution and piracy as recently illustrated by the Hadopi Act. All of this has naturally led researchers – and stakeholders in the sectors concerned – to ask questions as to the effects, and also the opportunities presented by digital technologies in terms of the diversification of commercialisation methods for music, cinema, etc., in addition to the ways of resisting or, concurrently, adapting to such developments.</s>
    <s>In comparison, the question of just how artists and cultural producers themselves actually adopt these new technological tools constitutes a research area left largely unexplored, as demonstrated by existing research into the ethnography of artistic works, and into new economic models in the cultural industries, areas in which there were very few contributions focussing on the relationship between producers and digital technology. In the field of photography, research undertaken by art historians has admittedly enabled issues such as the emergence of “new amateurs” or even buzz phenomena, etc. be discussed. But once more, there is a whole area left unexplored in terms of the disappearance or reduced status of certain professions (printers, iconographers, etc.), or the diversity of behaviours in the face of technological innovations. And this exploration of artistic works in the midst of the digital era seems all the more pertinent since the digital universe itself instigates particularly effective myths or beliefs which can confuse their sociological explanation: the notion of direct competition between amateurs and professionals in the photography sector, and new modes of apotheosis by social networks in the musical sector are particularly pertinent illustrations of the confusion which can arise following the “ambitious claims about digitisation” induced by digital technologies and the true scope of technological innovations.When all is said and done, focussing on the manner in which digital technologies impact artistic work involves asking questions as to the identification of different postures of artistic professions confronted with innovation, falling ticket prices for events which the internet can supposedly offer, the ability to bypass traditional gatekeepers, the democratisation of creative practices, the emergence of new collaborative organisation via networks, the surge in the emergence of entirely new aesthetic forms, the resistance to change, new methods of gaining a reputation or of creating added-value, and the redefinition of “professionalism”, etc.</s>
    <s>II/ Topics for discussion:</s>
    <s>This international research conference aims to focus on the panoply of issues relating to artistic creation in the digital era, focussing notably on the photography, cinema, audiovisual and musical sectors. The areas proposed for discussion and analysis are as follows:</s>
    <s>1)  The evolution of professions in sectors related to image and sound</s>
    <s>How have artistic professions experienced the digital revolution in terms of their identity, practices and revenues? How have they adopted digital technologies? How have they evolved? Which professions have disappeared as a result, and which others have emerged? How have the required professional skills developed? Have the methods of cooperation between the core professions forming a single sector evolved and are we witnessing a new distribution of responsibilities? Is the digital era leading to new forms of professional regulation?</s>
    <s>2) Technological innovations, standards and aesthetic conventions</s>
    <s>How have technological innovations affected aesthetic standards? How do artistic creators adopt or withstand new technologies? How are criteria used in appreciating quality and the hierarchical organisation of talents and creative works changing? What interactions are taking place between the emergence of technological standards and aesthetical standards?</s>
    <s>3) New profiles of amateurs?</s>
    <s>Is digital technology blurring/redefining the traditional boundaries between amateurs and professionals, and between consumers and producers? Is digital technology democratising artistic creation, notably via the reduction of costs for purchasing material and equipment, the cost of learning instruments, the cost of broadcasting creations? What are amateurs seeking when broadcasting works via the internet: artistic recognition, commitment towards collaborative projects claiming authorship, access to a particular professional status, etc.?</s>
    <s>4) Transformation of economic and organisational models</s>
    <s>Is digital technology inducing new economic models? What sort of reorganisation of the markets are we experiencing: a horizontal concentration versus a niche marketing strategy, long-tail versus block buster, vertical integration versus outsourcing of the production sector, the appearance of new market leaders? What effects are resulting from new methods of payment, and notably from the widespread presence of free supply? What are the new strategies being adopted for reaching audiences (viral marketing, buzz, etc.)?</s>
    <s>5) Myths and ideologies of the digital era</s>
    <s>Each major technological development is accompanied by ambitious claims about digitisation which may or may not be true: for example, a weakened position of major commercial actors on the market favouring independents and even favouring a world of free supply as led by creative individuals, a triumph of the distribution of creative work free of copyright, cultural diversity via sharing networks, etc. What is the mythological, ideological and strategic dimension of the discourses conveyed regarding digital technologies? How did such discourses emerge? How are they related? What effect do they have on a social level? Do they have any power to lead to self-creation in themselves?</s>
    <s>III/ Call for papers: requirements and schedule</s>
    <s>This multidisciplinary and international research conference will be held at the University of Avignon between 24 and 27 May 2011.</s>
    <s>Proposals for papers should be sent to the selection committee prior to 20 November 2010 at the very latest. All proposals, in French or in English, should be saved as RTF and sent to:</s>
    <s>      leguern@aol.com (Philippe Le Guern, Professor, University of Avignon)</s>
    <s>            claire.gauzente@sciencespo-rennes.fr  (Claire Gauzente, Professor, IEP Rennes)</s>
    <s>Proposals must include the following information: name of author and institution, email address, title and an abstract not exceeding one page. Notification of acceptance of papers shall be issued by 30 November 2010, along with all useful information regarding the conference, reception and accommodation for participants.</s>
    <s>All final versions of selected papers should be sent to the steering committee by 30 April 2011.</s>
    <s>Oral presentations may be given either in French or in English; however, so as to facilitate communication between researchers from different countries, conference speakers are requested to provide a power point presentation along with their paper outlining the major points discussed during the presentation (in English for French-speaking presenters and in French for English-speaking presenters).</s>
    <s>Colloque International</s>
    <s>Université d’Avignon et des Pays du Vaucluse</s>
    <s>24-27 mai 2011</s>
    <s>Organisé par le Centre Norbert Elias (EHESS, CNRS, UAPV), Le laboratoire Georges Friedmann (Paris 1-CNRS), le LHIVIC (EHESS) et le GRANEM (U. d’Angers)</s>
    <s>avec le soutien du programme ANR « Formes et mutations de la communication »</s>
    <s>Responsable du comité d’organisation :</s>
    <s>Philippe Le Guern</s>
    <s>(Professeur, UAPV et Centre Norbert Elias)</s>
    <s>Travail et création artistique en régime numérique :</s>
    <s>Images et Sons</s>
    <s>I/ Thématique du colloque :</s>
    <s>Les mutations induites par les technologies numériques (en particulier internet et la téléphonie mobile) nourrissent aujourd’hui une abondante littérature : s’agissant du champ culturel, ces travaux portent essentiellement sur la réorganisation du secteur industriel et l’adoption de nouveaux modèles économiques d’une part, et sur les formes inédites de réception et d’usage des contenus numériques par des publics amenés à endosser les rôles - traditionnellement dissociés - de producteurs, prescripteurs, diffuseurs, consommateurs, d’autre part. Ces recherches se sont notamment centrées sur l’enjeu que représentait le numérique pour l’organisation des filières et ses principaux acteurs, sur la répartition de la valeur et les modes de rémunération – avec la question cruciale des évolutions du droit d’auteur -, sur les nouvelles stratégies de promotion et de distribution, sur les spécificités structurelles de chaque secteur (musique, cinéma, photographie, livre…). Elles ont ainsi pris en compte les caractéristiques économiques de la demande de biens culturels et des déterminants de la consommation, insistant en particulier sur la question du lien entre révolution numérique et piratage qu’a illustrée récemment l’adoption de la loi Hadopi. Cet ensemble d’analyses a naturellement conduit les chercheurs – et les acteurs des filières concernées - à s’interroger sur les effets mais aussi les opportunités du numérique sur la diversification des modes de commercialisation de la musique, du cinéma, etc., et sur les formes de résistance ou à l’inverse d’adaptation au changement.</s>
    <s>Par comparaison, la question de savoir comment les artistes et producteurs culturels eux-mêmes s’approprient ces nouveaux outils constitue un chantier qui reste largement à explorer, comme en attestent une série de travaux sur l’ethnographie du travail artistique, sur les nouveaux modèles économiques dans les industries culturelles, dans lesquels les contributions centrées sur le lien entre producteurs et numérique faisaient significativement figure de parent pauvre. Dans le champ de la photographie, les travaux des historiens de l’art ont certes permis d’aborder des questions telles que l’émergence des « nouveaux amateurs » ou encore les phénomènes de buzz, etc… Mais tout un pan demande là aussi à être exploré en ce qui concerne la disparition ou le déclassement de certains métiers (les tireurs, les iconographes…), ou la diversité des comportements face à l’innovation. Et cette exploration du travail artistique en régime numérique nous semble d’autant plus importante à mener que les univers numériques secrètent eux-mêmes des mythologies ou des croyances particulièrement efficaces qui peuvent en brouiller la lecture sociale : L’idée d’une concurrence frontale des professionnels par les amateurs dans le secteur de la photographie, de nouveaux modes de consécration par les réseaux sociaux dans le domaine de la musique  illustrent de manière exemplaire la confusion qui peut s’installer entre les « grands récits » du numérique et la portée véritable de l’innovation technologique.</s>
    <s>En définitive, s’intéresser à la façon dont le numérique impacte le travail artistique, c’est se poser des questions telles que l’identification des différentes postures des professions artistiques face à l’innovation, l’abaissement des droits d’entrée qu’est réputé offrir internet, la capacité de court-circuitage des gate keepers traditionnels, la démocratisation de la pratique créative, l’apparition de nouvelles configurations collaboratives en réseaux, le surgissement de formes esthétiques inédites, la résistance au changement, les nouvelles formes de construction de la réputation ou de la valeur, la redéfinition du « professionnalisme », etc.</s>
    <s>II/ Questions abordées :</s>
    <s>C’est à l’ensemble des questions soulevées par le travail artistique en régime numérique que souhaite se confronter ce colloque international, en privilégiant le cas de la photographie, du cinéma, de l’audiovisuel et de la musique. Les axes thématiques sont les suivants :</s>
    <s>1)  Mutation des professions dans les secteurs de l’image et du son</s>
    <s>Comment les professions artistiques ont vécu le passage au numérique en terme d’identité, de pratiques et de revenus ? Comment se sont-elles appropriées les technologies numériques ? Comment se sont-elles formées ? Quels métiers ont disparu, quels autres sont apparus ? Comment les compétences requises ont évolué ? Les modes de coopération entre les cœurs de métiers à l’intérieur d’une même filière ont –ils évolué et assiste-t-on à de nouvelles formes de division des tâches ? Le numérique favorise t-il de nouvelles formes de régulation professionnelles ?</s>
    <s>2) Innovations technologiques, normes et conventions esthétiques</s>
    <s>Comment les innovations technologiques affectent les normes esthétiques ? Comment les créateurs s’approprient ou résistent aux nouvelles technologies ? Comment changent les critères d’appréciation de la qualité  et de hiérarchisation des talents et des oeuvres ? Quelles sont les interactions entre l’émergence de standards technologiques et de standards esthétiques ?</s>
    <s>3) Nouvelles figures de l’amateur ?</s>
    <s>Le numérique brouille-t-il /redéfinit-il les frontières traditionnelles entre amateurs et professionnels, entre le consommateur et le producteur ? Le numérique démocratise-t-il la création artistique, notamment par la réduction  des coûts d’acquisition du matériel, coût d’apprentissage, coût de diffusion ?  Que recherche l’amateur quand il diffuse ses œuvres sur internet : notoriété artistique, engagement dans des dispositifs collaboratifs revendication de la paternité de l’œuvre, accès à un statut  professionnel…. ?</s>
    <s>4) Transformation des modèles économiques  et organisationnels</s>
    <s>Le numérique engendre t-il de nouveaux business models ? A quelles restructurations des marchés assiste-t-on : concentration horizontale versus marchés de niches, longue traine versus block buster , intégration verticale versus externalisation de la filière de production, apparition de nouveaux leaders ? Quels rôles jouent les modes de tarification et notamment l’omniprésence d’une offre gratuite ? Quelles sont les nouvelles stratégies de captation des audiences (marketing viral, buzz…) ?</s>
    <s>5) Mythologies et idéologies du numérique</s>
    <s>Chaque mutation technologique s’accompagne de grands récits : par exemple affaiblissement des majors au profit des indépendants et même d’un monde de la gratuité porté par des citoyens créateurs, triomphe de la circulation d’œuvres libre de droits, diversité culturelle garantie par les réseaux de partage  etc…Quelles est la dimension mythologique, idéologique et stratégique des discours véhiculés autour du numérique ? Comment ces discours émergent ? Comment sont-il relayés ? Quelle est leur efficacité sociale ? Ont-ils un pouvoir autoréalisateur ?</s>
    <s>III/ Modalités de réponse à l’appel à communication et calendrier :</s>
    <s>Le colloque, pluridisciplinaire et international, se tiendra à l’Université d’Avignon du 24 au 27 mai 2011.</s>
    <s>Les réponses à cet appel à communication devront être adressées au comité de sélection avant le 20 novembre dernier délai. Les propositions, rédigées en français ou en anglais, seront transmises en fichier RTF aux deux adresses suivantes :</s>
    <s>-        leguern@aol.com (Philippe Le Guern, Professeur, Université d'Avignon)</s>
    <s>-        clairE.gauzente@sciencespo-rennes.fr (Claire Gauzente, Professeur, IEP Rennes)</s>
    <s>Elles contiendront obligatoirement le nom de leur auteur et la mention de son rattachement institutionnel, son adresse mail, un titre et un résumé d’une page maximum. La notification d’acceptation de la contribution sera communiquée le 30 novembre 2010, ainsi que l’ensemble des informations pratiques relatives au colloque, à l’accueil et à l’hébergement des participants.</s>
    <s>Les textes retenus devront être adressés dans leur version finale aux organisateurs le 30 avril 2011.</s>
    <s>Les exposés oraux pourront être donnés au choix en français ou en anglais : cependant, afin de faciliter la communication entre chercheurs issus de différentes aires linguistiques, il sera demandé aux contributeurs d’accompagner leur communication orale d’une présentation power point mettant en évidence les points saillants de leur exposé (en anglais pour les francophones et en anglais pour les francophones).</s>
    <s>Tags: création, métiers artistiques, numérique</s>
    <s>Cet article a ete ecrit le Lundi 25 octobre 2010 a 16:54 et est classe dans Agenda. Vous pouvez suivre toutes les reactions par le flux RSS 2.0.</s>
    <s>Les commentaires sont fermés</s>
    <s>octobre 2010</s>
    <s>septembre 2010</s>
    <s>juin 2010</s>
    <s>économie art création culture métiers artistiques marché numérique photo photographie contemporaine</s>
    <s>(C) 2011 La valeur de l'art.</s>
    <s>Hebergement Culture Visuelle, Lhivic/EHESS. Developpement 22mars.</s>
    <s>Propulse par Wordpress et Buddypress</s>
    <s>Culture Visuelle</s>
    <s>Auteurs du blog</s>
    <s>Membre au hasard</s>
    <s>Groupe au hasard</s>
    <s>Blog au hasard</s>
  </text>
</page>
