<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>fr</lang>  <url>http://www.u-paris10.fr/1297418870382/0/fiche___actualite/%26RH%3D1277902795330</url>
  <title>(appel à communications) Memory and city conference</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Feb 9, 2011 (appel à communications) Memory and city conference. Recherche / Appels à projets, Conférence / Rencontre. le 31 mars 2011. Johannesburg </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Acces direct au contenu</s>
    <s>Service des Relations Internationales</s>
    <s>Actualitet appels d'offre</s>
    <s>Mobilites diants</s>
    <s>Mobilites enseignants</s>
    <s>Bourses de mobilita&gt;</s>
    <s>[Institut Confucius</s>
    <s>Organisation des des</s>
    <s>Liens utiles</s>
    <s>Organisation des des</s>
    <s>Offre de formation</s>
    <s>Formation istance</s>
    <s>Formations 'anger</s>
    <s>Formation continue</s>
    <s>Prration aux concours</s>
    <s>Prration aux mers de l'enseignement</s>
    <s>Dulement des examens</s>
    <s>Actualite la recherche</s>
    <s>Ecoles doctorales</s>
    <s>Unitet raux de recherche</s>
    <s>SAR : Service d'Administration de la Recherche</s>
    <s>Valorisation de la recherche</s>
    <s>Presses de Paris Ouest</s>
    <s>Services aux enseignants-chercheurs</s>
    <s>Services aux doctorants</s>
    <s>Action sociale diant</s>
    <s>Action sociale personnel</s>
    <s>Campus Vert</s>
    <s>Nanterre Sport Campus</s>
    <s>Service handicap</s>
    <s>Service mcal</s>
    <s>Newsletters Culture Campus</s>
    <s>Horaires et acc/a&gt;</s>
    <s>[Services aux usagers</s>
    <s>Formation a recherche documentaire</s>
    <s>Enqu BU</s>
    <s>Recherche simple</s>
    <s>-recherche avanc/a&gt;</s>
    <s>L'ED 395 MCSPP</s>
    <s>Centres de recherche</s>
    <s>Faire sa th 'ED 395</s>
    <s>La page des doctorants</s>
    <s>Les ths de l'ED 395</s>
    <s>Aides financis ponctuelles</s>
    <s>Sites des composantes ou serv &gt; Ecole doctorale MCSPP &gt; Archives</s>
    <s>(appel ommunications) Memory and city conference</s>
    <s>Recherche / Appels rojets, Confnce / Rencontre</s>
    <s>le 31 mars 2011</s>
    <s>Johannesburg, 14-16th of September 2011</s>
    <s>With a few exceptions (for example some cities on the Swahili coast, see Abungu 1998), the issue of heritage in Africa remains, in academic literature as well as among institutions in charge of the economic valorisation of heritage, very much attached to rural areas and societies. African cities, still widely considered alien in the landscape of a continent essentialized as rural ever since colonisation (Coquery-Vidrovitch 1993, Freund 2007), are nonetheless important spaces for the construction of memory and heritage (which are not necessarily interchangeable terms). The topic of urban memory and its meaning in the making of neighbourhood identities and development strategies (linked to tangible and intangible heritage) produced by local and municipal governments and international donors, has only recently come under investigation by researchers in Africa. What image of these neighbourhoods is promoted and for what purpose? What selections and processes operate, as far as representations of these neighbourhoods are concerned, so that they acquire, in the long run, distinctive traits and stereotypes?</s>
    <s>In cities experiencing rapid transformation, often connected to new patterns of migration and mobility, what is the role of memory and nostalgia in the making of local identities? To what extent does this nostalgia serve the purpose of regeneration/gentrification policies - a phenomenon that has been particularly prevalent in Johannesburg?</s>
    <s>In South Africa, memorial efforts since the democratic transition have mainly focused on the evocation of the (mostly urban) battlegrounds of the struggle : emblematic areas and neighbourhoods wiped out during the forced removals and resettlement policies led by the Apartheid regime (such as Red Location, Sophiatown, District 6), are today the object of memory enterprises which are, arguably, intended to contribute to the construction of a national identity rooted in memories of violent abuses committed under Apartheid (Saunders &amp; Kros 2004, Didier et al. 2007). The question of the link between these memorialised neighbourhoods and the population currently living in them has, however, not yet been explored in depth. Above all, not only do these evocations of memory tend to occlude contradictory voices (Nieftagodien 2009) but little space is left for ordinary memories (as described by Hayden 1995). What space do ordinary, everyday or unspectacular memories have in the making of territorial identities? How do they articulate with grand memorial narratives promoted for the sake of national identity?</s>
    <s>The event will consist of a two day colloquium, organized at the University of Witwaterstrand (Wits) and University of Johannesburg (UJ); one day of site visits to some of emblematic neighbourhoods of Johannesburg as far as the subject of urban memory in South Africa is concerned; and a film screening and debate at the Alliance Francaise in Johannesburg. It is anticipated that the academic fields represented will range from urban history, geography, anthropology, heritage studies and urban sociology. The intention is to go beyond the frame of African studies and to connect experiments and reflections from all corners of what is now a global issue: for instance, the recent progress of French memory collection works in the Paris suburbs, under the impetus of the DIV (Inter-ministerial Delegation for the City) since 2005, reflects the relevance of the theme even for cities that would appear to have come to terms with the issue of memory a long time ago. This would allow us to put into perspective the specificities of research work on memory in African cities. We hope to initiate a real dialogue between researchers on this topic.</s>
    <s>Please send via email a 500-1000 word abstract in any language to Mr Thibault Hatton (research.comm@ifas.org.za), mentioning your name and affiliation, and specifying in the subject of the email Memory and City proposal, YOUR NAME before March 31st.</s>
    <s>The language of the conference will be English, but we might organize sessions in French provided we have enough proposals in this language.</s>
    <s>Circulation of the call: Feb 9th - March 31st</s>
    <s>Selection of the papers: April 2011</s>
    <s>Feedback to the authors: late April 2011</s>
    <s>Organization committee:</s>
    <s>Dr. Sophie DIDIER, French Institute of South Africa (Research Director)</s>
    <s>Prof. Natasha ERLANK, University of Johannesburg (Department of History)</s>
    <s>Naomi ROUX, University of the Witwatersrand (School of Arts)</s>
    <s>Dr. Mfaniseni SIHLONGONYANE, University of the Witwatersrand (School of Architecture and Planning)</s>
    <s>Voir dils dans document joint.</s>
    <s>Informations pratiques</s>
    <s>Fichier joint :</s>
    <s>MEMORY AND CITY - Call for papers - 9th Feb 2011.pdf 163 Ko</s>
    <s>Recherche d'une actualite</s>
    <s>Recherche d'une actualite</s>
    <s>Mois Tous 01 02 03 04 05 06 07 08 09 10 11 12</s>
    <s>Type d'nement Tous Appel d'offreAppels rojetsAtelierBoursesBureauColloqueCommissionsConfnce / RencontreConseil d'administration Conseil d'administrationConseil des Etudes et de Conseil scientifique (CS)ConseilExpositionFestivalForumInscriptionsJournd'deParutionPortes ouvertesPrixRion d'informationSalonSoirdianteSoutenance de thStageSnaireections</s>
    <s>Structure Toutes bdicdirection grale des servicesed 138ed 139ed 395ed 396ed sjped sportenseignementipaglabos de languesmaeproduction sonrech. documentairerecherchesites personnelsufr dspufr lceufr philliaufr segmiufr sitecufr spseufr ssaufr stapsuniversitaris ouest nanterre la dnsev.d'avray / st-cloud</s>
    <s>!imprimer !haut de la page</s>
  </text>
</page>
