<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>fr</lang>  <url>http://iccrom.org/fra/news_fr/2011_fr/field_fr/misc_fr.shtml</url>
  <title>ICCROM - manifestations et emplois en dehors de l&#39;ICCROM ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Appel à communications : Munich Conference, “Climate for Collections: Standards and Uncertainties” 7 – 12 novembre 2012, Munich, Allemagne Date limite de </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>recherche sur le site | plan du site | nous contacter</s>
    <s>ropos de</s>
    <s>ts membres</s>
    <s>&gt; facebook</s>
    <s>accueil &gt; archive des infos &gt; nouvelles et emplois</s>
    <s>english version</s>
    <s>Infos octobre 2011 :</s>
    <s>Manifestations, emplois, bourses, sites internet, etc.</s>
    <s>!linea news</s>
    <s>Bourses, stages, financements, benevolat</s>
    <s>21 septembre. Collection Care department, British Library, Royaume-Uni</s>
    <s>Benevolat : Preventive Conservation Voluntary Work Opportunity</s>
    <s>Date limite d'envoi des candidatures : 21 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>22 aout. International Federation of Landscape Architects (IFLA)</s>
    <s>Bourse : IFLA Sir Geoffrey Jellicoe International Fellowship, Residency at the Bristish School at Rome</s>
    <s>Date limite d'envoi des candidatures : 15 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>19 juillet. Getty Conservation Institute, Etats-Unis</s>
    <s>Bourses : Conservation Guest Scholars and Postdoctoral Fellowships</s>
    <s>Date limite d'envoi des candidatures : 1 novembre 2011</s>
    <s>20 June. Centre of African Studies, University of Cambridge, Royaume-Uni</s>
    <s>Bourses: Cambridge/Africa Collaborative Research Programme</s>
    <s>Date limite d'envoi des candidatures : 1 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>!linea news02</s>
    <s>5 octobre. Dutch National Museum of Ethnology (Museum Volkenkunde), Pays-Bas</s>
    <s>Objects / Mixed Materials Conservator</s>
    <s>Date limite d'envoi des candidatures : 21 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>21 septembre. Centre for Sustainable Heritage, University College London, Royaume-Uni</s>
    <s>Forum Coordinator (National Heritage Science Forum)</s>
    <s>Date limite d'envoi des candidatures : 4 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>!linea news02</s>
    <s>Evenements et manifestations</s>
    <s>Calendrier des manifestations compile par l'ICCROM</s>
    <s>Evenements ce mois-ci</s>
    <s>5 octobre. Musee du Louvre and Centre de recherche et de restauration des musees de France</s>
    <s>Appel a communications : French Bronzes: history, materials and techniques of bronze sculpture in France (16th - 18th C.), 9 - 12 juin 2012, Paris, France</s>
    <s>Date limite de soumission des resumes : 1 novembre 2011</s>
    <s>5 octobre. Centre de recherche sur le savoir local, Mali; Freie Universtitat Berlin; Centre d'etudes superieures « Morphomata. Genesis, Dynamics and Mediality of Cultural Figurations », Universite de Cologne, Allemagne</s>
    <s>Appel a contributions : Les nouveaux lieux de negociation de l'histoire (et) de l'art dans les villes africaines, 14-17 mars 2012, Bamako, Mali</s>
    <s>Date limite : 31 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>5 octobre. International Council on Archives (ICA) and Ministry of Culture, Spain</s>
    <s>Evenement : International Conference of the Round Table on Archives (CITRA), 26 - 27 octobre 2011, Tolede, Espagne</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : 15 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>21 septembre. Institut national du patrimoine, France</s>
    <s>Colloque : La conservation et la restauration des jardins historiques, 6 - 7 octobre 2011, Paris, France</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : contacter les organisateurs</s>
    <s>21 septembre. Preventive conservation,maintenance and monitoring of monuments and sites (PRECOMOS)</s>
    <s>Conference : International Conference on Preventive Conservation of Architectural Heritage 29 - 30 octobre 2011, Nanjing, Chine</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : 15 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>22 aout. UNESCO Office in Venice</s>
    <s>Conference : The Future of Venice and its Lagoon in the Context of Global Change 13 - 15 novembre 2011, Venise, Italie</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : 31 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>22 aout. UNESCO Chair on Preventive Conservation, Monitoring and Maintenance of Monuments and Sites (PRECOMOS)</s>
    <s>Conference : International Conference on Preventive Conservation of Architectural Heritage 29-30 octobre 2011, Nanjing, Chine</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : 15 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>11 aout. Doerner Institute, Allemagne</s>
    <s>Appel a communications : Munich Conference, &quot;Climate for Collections: Standards and Uncertainties&quot; 7 - 12 novembre 2012, Munich, Allemagne</s>
    <s>Date limite de soumission des resumes : 1 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>4 aout. United Kingdom National Commission for UNESCO et des partenaires, Royaume-Uni</s>
    <s>Conference : &quot;I Know Where I'm Going&quot;: Remote Access to World Heritage Sites from St Kilda to Uluru, 23-24 novembre 2011, Edinburgh, Royaume-Uni</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : 11 novembre 2011</s>
    <s>3 aout. ICOMOS - Conseil International des Monuments et des Sites</s>
    <s>Evenement : 17e Assemblee generale de l'ICOMOS et Symposium scientifique &quot;Le patrimoine, moteur de developpement&quot;, 27 novembre - 2 decembre 2011, Paris, France</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : 27 aout 2011 (inscription a prix preferentiel)</s>
    <s>27 septembre 2011 (reservations post-tours)</s>
    <s>25 juillet. Historic Preservation Program, Columbia University, Etats-Unis</s>
    <s>Evenement : 12th International Conference on the Deterioration and Conservation of Stone, 4-8 juin 2012, New York City, Etats-Unis</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : contacter les organisateurs</s>
    <s>25 juillet. ICOM - Comite international pour la formation du personnel (ICTOP)</s>
    <s>Conference : ICTOP Annual Conference, 23-26 octobre 2011, Toronto, Canada</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : 15 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>13 juillet. Church of England, Church Building Council, Royaume-Uni</s>
    <s>Symposium : The challenges of the conservation of artworks in churches, 11 octobre 2011, Westminster Abbey, Londres, Royaume-Uni</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : contacter les organisateurs</s>
    <s>13 juillet. University of the Witwatersrand, Afrique du Sud</s>
    <s>Appel a communications : Developing Knowledge for Economic Advancement in Africa: 2nd International Conference on African Digital Libraries and Archives (ICADLA-2), Johannesburg, Afrique du Sud, 14 - 18 Novembre 2011</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : 31 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>28 juin. Preservation Advisory Centre, British Library, Royaume-Uni</s>
    <s>Future events</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : visiter le site internet</s>
    <s>23 juin. American University of Sharjah, Emirats Arabes Unis</s>
    <s>Evenement : International Conference on the Use of X-ray (and related) Techniques in Arts and Cultural Heritage, Sharjah, Emirats Arabes Unis, 7-8 decembre 2011</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : 2 novembre 2011 (pre-inscription)</s>
    <s>4 mai. Organizing Secretariat of Costume Colloquium, Florence, Italie</s>
    <s>Appel a communications : Costume Colloquium III: Past Dress - Future Fashion , 8-11 novembre 2012, Florence, Italie</s>
    <s>Date limite de soumission des resumes : 31 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>8 avril. Wallraf-Richartz-Museum and Foundation Corboud, Bayerische Staatsgemaldesammlungen, and the Doerner Institut, Allemagne</s>
    <s>Colloque : Let the Material Talk - Technology of Late Medieval Cologne Painting in Context, 24-26 novembre 2011, Cologne, Allemagne</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : contacter les organisateurs</s>
    <s>4 avril. British Museum et des partenaires, Londres, Royaume-Uni</s>
    <s>Conference : Pest Odyssey 2011: Ten Years Later, 26-28 octobre 2011, Londres, Royaume-Uni</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : 25 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>21 mars. United Kingdom National Commission for UNESCO et des partenaires, Royaume-Uni</s>
    <s>Appel a communications : &quot;I Know Where I'm Going&quot;: Remote Access to World Heritage Sites from St Kilda to Uluru, 23-24 novembre 2011, Edinburgh, Royaume-Uni</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : 11 novembre 2011</s>
    <s>14 decembre. Asian Academy for Heritage Management (AAHM)</s>
    <s>Conference : Asia-Pacific Regional Conference on Underwater Cultural Heritage, 8-12 novembre 2011, Manille, Philippines</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : visiter le site internet</s>
    <s>25 novembre. Asian Academy for Heritage Management (AAHM)</s>
    <s>Call for theme and session organizers: Inaugural Conference on Underwater Cultural Heritage (pdf), 8 - 12 novembre 2011, Manila, Philippines</s>
    <s>Date limite pour les soumissions : contacter les organisateurs</s>
    <s>19 octobre. Preservation Advisory Centre, British Library, Royaume-Uni</s>
    <s>Calendrier d'evenements</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : visiter le site internet</s>
    <s>22 avril. Life Beyond Tourism</s>
    <s>Calendrier d'evenements :</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : visiter le site internet</s>
    <s>!linea news02</s>
    <s>Formation et developpement</s>
    <s>20 septembre. Preservation Advisory Centre, British Library, Royaume-Uni</s>
    <s>Training Calendar</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : visiter le site internet</s>
    <s>22 aout. Hornemann Institute, Allemagne</s>
    <s>Cours en ligne :</s>
    <s>Microbic Infestation of Objects of Art and Cultural Heritage, 19 septembre to 13 novembre 2011</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : contacter les organisateurs</s>
    <s>29 juin. Libera Universita LUSPIO and Istituto Superiore per le Tecniche di Conservazione dei Beni Culturali e dell'Ambiente &quot;Antonino De Stefano&quot; (ISAD), Italie</s>
    <s>Cours : Master annuale di I livello Esperto in Conservazione e Restauro dei Beni culturali, 15 novembre 2011 - 15 decembre 2012, Rome, Italie</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : 10 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>31 mai. European Research Centre for Book and Paper Conservation-Restoration, Horn, Autriche</s>
    <s>Courses 2011</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : visiter le site internet</s>
    <s>15 avril. Institute of Continuing Education, University of Cambridge, Royaume-Uni</s>
    <s>Cours : MSt in Historic Environment, septembre 2012 to juillet 2014, Cambridge, Royaume-Uni</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : applications will be accepted from 1 September 2011 to 30 March 2012</s>
    <s>14 fevrier. Catedra Regional de Ciencias de la Conservacion Integral de los Bienes Culturales y Naturales para America Latina y el Caribe de la UNESCO (CRECI), Cuba</s>
    <s>Actividades de Superacion profesional, Año Academico 2011</s>
    <s>5 janvier. Escola SENAI Theobaldo de Nigris, Sao Paulo, Bresil</s>
    <s>Conteudos abordados nos cursos de Preservaçao 2011</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : contacter les organisateurs</s>
    <s>10 decembre. Erasmus Mundus Programme</s>
    <s>Advanced Masters in Structural Analysis of Monuments and Historical Constructions</s>
    <s>Date limite d'inscription : visiter le site internet</s>
    <s>!linea news02</s>
    <s>14 juillet. American Academy in Rome, Italy</s>
    <s>Rome Prize</s>
    <s>Date limite d'envoi des candidatures : 1 novembre 2011</s>
    <s>14 juillet. Euromed Heritage and Rehabimed</s>
    <s>International Digital Photography Award</s>
    <s>Date limite d'envoi des candidatures : 15 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>22 juin. Hands OnInternational (HOI) and European Museum Academy</s>
    <s>Children's Museum Award</s>
    <s>Date limite d'envoi des candidatures : 31 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>!linea news02</s>
    <s>25 aout. Revivifier les musees de sites du Patrimoine mondial au Cambodge, Laos et Viet Nam, UNESCO</s>
    <s>Ce projet du fonds-en-depot japonais aupres de l'UNESCO a ete conçu comme un projet pilote pour accompagner le processus de revitalisation des musees de site du patrimoine vivant et les centres d'interpretation dedies aux sites archeologiques des trois pays.</s>
    <s>!linea news02</s>
    <s>Publications, publications et periodiques en ligne</s>
    <s>5 octobre. Bulletin de l'ISPAN 28, Haiti</s>
    <s>5 octobre. La preservation des maisons de style gingerbread d'Haiti: Rapport de mission apres le seisme de 2010, par Langenbach, Randolph, et al. World Monuments Funds</s>
    <s>21 septembre. Gestion de colecciones, par Amelia Aguado de Costa</s>
    <s>21 septembre. Bulletin de l'ISPAN 27, Haiti</s>
    <s>21 septembre. Museum International No. 248, UNESCO</s>
    <s>Haiti, patrimoine culturel et refondation</s>
    <s>21 septembre. Twelve houses restored in Japan and Italy, par Marco Imperadori et al.</s>
    <s>21 septembre. IFLA Newsletter No. 94, International Federation of Landscape Architects</s>
    <s>21 septembre. Implementing the Incident Command System at the Institutional Level: A Handbook for Libraries, Archives, Museums, and Other Cultural Institutions, par David W. Charmicheal</s>
    <s>20 septembre. Lignes directrices pour la conservation des peintures murales exterieures, par Debra Daly Hartin, Institut canadien de conservation</s>
    <s>20 septembre. The Visible Past / Open Context Loosely Coupled Model for Digital Humanities Ubiquitous Collaboration and Publishing: Collaborating Across Print, Mobile, and Online Media, par Sorin Adam Matei, Eric Kansa, Nicholas Rauh</s>
    <s>The paper presents a platform for supporting academic collaboration and publishing created by flexibly linking Visible Past, a web collaboration and digital-print publishing with Open Context, a geo-historical data archiving and publishing service.</s>
    <s>20 septembre. E-Dialogos, Diadrasis</s>
    <s>Annual digital journal on research in Conservation and Cultural Heritage.</s>
    <s>20 septembre. Financiamento da Regeneraçao de Áreas Urbanas Patrimoniais na America Latina, par Silvio Zancheti</s>
    <s>O livro Financiamento da Regeneraçao de Áreas Urbanas Patrimoniais na America Latina , do professor Silvio Mendes Zancheti, apresenta um quadro sistematico do processo de financiamento da regeneraçao de areas urbanas patrimoniais (centros historicos e outros tipos de areas) na America Latina no periodo 1990 - 2005.</s>
    <s>!linea news02</s>
    <s>Sites Internet</s>
    <s>5 octobre. Heritage Portal</s>
    <s>This site has been developed under the EU-funded NET-HERITAGE programme to provide a platform accessible to a wide audience of Researchers, Practitioners, Funding Agencies, Policymakers and anyone with an interest in European cultural heritage. It enables users to connect, share their knowledge and work collaboratively.</s>
    <s>21 septembre. War Free World Heritage Listed Cities</s>
    <s>Promoting good governance for the protection of urban heritage in times of armed conflict.</s>
    <s>21 septembre. Smarthistory</s>
    <s>Smarthistory.org is a free and open, not-for-profit, art history textbook. We use multimedia to deliver unscripted conversations between art historians about the history of art. We are seeking contributors -- especially for canonical non-Western material and other survey topics not yet covered.</s>
    <s>21 septembre. Encyclopedia of Life</s>
    <s>Global access to knowledge about life on Earth</s>
    <s>20 septembre. Academia.edu</s>
    <s>Academia.edu is a place to share and follow research</s>
    <s>20 septembre.l'Archive Ouverte de l'ICOMOS</s>
    <s>l'Archive Ouverte de l'ICOMOS : e-publications sur le patrimoine culturel, une archive mondiale specialisee dans la conservation et la restauration des monuments, sites et paysages.</s>
    <s>!linea news02</s>
    <s>mise our : 05.10.2011</s>
    <s>Sites internet</s>
    <s>Archive des infos</s>
    <s>&lt; ropos de l'ICCROM &gt; | plan du site | recherche sur le site | nous contacter</s>
    <s>ICCROM 2005</s>
    <s>Via di San Michele 13, I-00153 Rome, Italie</s>
    <s>t: (+39) 06.585-531; fax: (+39) 06.585-53349</s>
    <s>URL: http://www.iccrom.org</s>
  </text>
</page>
