<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>fr</lang>  <url>http://blogs.univ-tlse2.fr/corpsetmedecine/2011/04/05/appel-a-contribution-graduate-conference-on-the-history-of-the-body/</url>
  <title>Corps et Médecine · Appel à contribution – Graduate Conference on ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Appel à contribution – Graduate Conference on the History of the Body. 5 avril 2011 dans Appels à contribution. Appel à contribution – Graduate Conference on </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>!Image de tête</s>
    <s>Corps et Médecine</s>
    <s>Recherches en sciences humaines et sociales</s>
    <s>A propos</s>
    <s>Liens utiles</s>
    <s>Comptes rendus</s>
    <s>Abonnement au fil RSS</s>
    <s>‹ Colloque - Vaccination, Society and Politics • Appel à projet - Fondation Internationale de Recherche Appliquée sur le Handicap ›</s>
    <s>Appel à contribution - Graduate Conference on the History of the Body</s>
    <s>5 avril 2011 dans Appels à contribution</s>
    <s>Appel à contribution - Graduate Conference on the History of the Body</s>
    <s>The Graduate History Association and the Department of History at Washington University in St. Louis are pleased to announce the inaugural Graduate Conference on the History of the Body, to be held October 20-21, 2011.</s>
    <s>In 2001, Roy Porter remarked that body history had become the « historiographical dish of the day. » Ten years on, histories of the body continue to flourish. Often working at the interstices of a number of methods and approaches, the field has produced innovative and compelling articulations of the body as a category of historical analysis. As thinking about bodies has occasioned ongoing encounters, clashes, and border-crossings between a variety of disciplines, this conference aims to promote conversations across scholarly divides by showcasing and reflecting on graduate-level scholarship on the history of the body, in all periods and regions, and from a variety of methodological approaches. We invite papers related to a broad number of thematic areas, including but not limited to:</s>
    <s>*normality and deviancy</s>
    <s>*medicine and disease</s>
    <s>*sexuality and reproduction</s>
    <s>*blood and race</s>
    <s>*physical space</s>
    <s>We're also pleased to announce Professor Mary Fissell, renowned historian of medicine at the Johns Hopkins University, as the conference keynote speaker. Professor Fissell's first book, Patients, Power and the Poor (Cambridge 1991), examined how patients' choices shaped a health-care system in the eighteenth century. Her more recent Vernacular Bodies (Oxford 2004) explored the politics of reproduction in early modern medicine. Professor Fissell's current project involves Aristotle's Masterpiece, for three centuries the best-selling book about sex and reproduction. Her address will be held in conjunction with the Washington University in St. Louis Department of History Colloquium Series.</s>
    <s>Graduate Students in any field of study are invited to submit proposals for individual research papers. Abstracts of approximately 250 words should be submitted online: http://history.artsci.wustl.edu/GHA/Conference. The deadline for submissions is June 1, 2011.</s>
    <s>Tags: Histoire</s>
    <s>Pour publier une annonce, envoyez un mail à : corpsetmedecine@gmail.com</s>
    <s>Appels à contribution</s>
    <s>Appels d'offres</s>
    <s>Journées d'études et Séminaires</s>
    <s>Prix et bourses</s>
    <s>Anthropologie Arts Economie Ethnologie Etudes des sciences Etudes Genre Géographie Histoire Histoire de l'art Littérature Philosophie Psychologie Sociologie</s>
    <s>Rechercher dans ce site</s>
    <s>Approches de la médecine chinoise</s>
    <s>Biomedicine on Display</s>
    <s>Brought to Life (Science Museum)</s>
    <s>Centre Alexandre Koyré</s>
    <s>Centre Ethique Clinique</s>
    <s>Centre François Viète</s>
    <s>Centre George Canguilhem</s>
    <s>Cultures of health</s>
    <s>Doctorants LLA</s>
    <s>Doctorants Santé et Société</s>
    <s>Doctorants Santé et société</s>
    <s>Ethique médicale Fondation Chassot et Guex</s>
    <s>Histoire des sciences de l'homme</s>
    <s>Institut d'éthique biomédicale</s>
    <s>Institut de recherche Robert-Sauvé (IRSST)</s>
    <s>Le Prisme</s>
    <s>LHSP - Archives Henri Poincaré</s>
    <s>Medical Anthropology</s>
    <s>Medical Historical Library</s>
    <s>Observatoire des Transidentités</s>
    <s>Observatoire du sida et des sexualités</s>
    <s>Philosophie et Médecine (CERSES)</s>
    <s>Politiques de l'imagination - transformation contemporaine des corps</s>
    <s>Portail Michel Foucault</s>
    <s>Savoir(s) en commun</s>
    <s>SFTG Sciences humaines et sociales</s>
    <s>Terrain Blog</s>
    <s>The quack doctors</s>
    <s>Wellcome Library</s>
    <s>octobre 2011</s>
    <s>septembre 2011</s>
    <s>août 2011</s>
    <s>juillet 2011</s>
    <s>juin 2011</s>
    <s>mai 2011</s>
    <s>avril 2011</s>
    <s>mars 2011</s>
    <s>février 2011</s>
    <s>janvier 2011</s>
    <s>décembre 2010</s>
    <s>novembre 2010</s>
    <s>octobre 2010</s>
    <s>septembre 2010</s>
    <s>août 2010</s>
    <s>juillet 2010</s>
    <s>juin 2010</s>
    <s>mai 2010</s>
    <s>avril 2010</s>
    <s>mars 2010</s>
    <s>Pour publier une annonce : corpsetmedecine@gmail.com</s>
    <s>Abonnement au fil RSS</s>
    <s>Construit grace a WordPress et Tarski | Sous l'egide de blogs.univ-tlse2.fr</s>
  </text>
</page>
