<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>fr</lang>  <url>http://cema-northafrica.org/activites.php%3Fshow%3DAC%26id%3D464</url>
  <title>Appel à communications - 5th Annual International Conference on</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Délai : 14 aout 2011. Appel à communications - BISKRA ARCHITECTURE AND SUSTAINABILITY INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE&#39; 2011. Délai : 15 août 2011 </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Presentation / Missions</s>
    <s>Non Maghrebin</s>
    <s>Fonds documentaires</s>
    <s>Recherche au CEMA</s>
    <s>Recherche en Algerie</s>
    <s>Liens gouvernementaux</s>
    <s>Centres de Recherche</s>
    <s>Recherche au Maghr/a&gt;</s>
    <s>Arriver en Algerie</s>
    <s>[Visa / Carte de Sejour</s>
    <s>Banques et change</s>
    <s>Activites scientifiques</s>
    <s>Universite d'Oran- Es-senia</s>
    <s>Cite du Chercheur (ex-IAP)</s>
    <s>Horraires d'ouverture:</s>
    <s>Dim - Jeu : 8h30-16h30</s>
    <s>Ramadhan : 8h30-14h30</s>
    <s>Juillet : 8h30-14h30</s>
    <s>Ferme au mois d'Aout</s>
    <s>Activites scientifiques</s>
    <s>Appels a communications / Bourses :</s>
    <s>Appel ontributions - Revue Africaine des Livres</s>
    <s>Delai : Ouvert</s>
    <s>Appel ontribution - Journal of Shia Islamic Studies</s>
    <s>Delai : Ouvert</s>
    <s>Appel doffre - Agence Universitaire de la Francophonie: Organiser une manifestation scientifique</s>
    <s>Delai : Ouvert - six mois avant le dt de la manifestation</s>
    <s>Appel andidatures - CAORC - Multi-Country Research Fellowship Program</s>
    <s>Delai : Ouvert</s>
    <s>Appel ontributions - Encyclopedia of Women and Islamic Cultures</s>
    <s>Delai : Ouvert</s>
    <s>Appel a communications- Islamic Cities in the Eyes of European Travelers</s>
    <s>Delai : 1 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel à contributions - New Middle Eastern Studies (NMES)</s>
    <s>Delai : ouvert</s>
    <s>Appel ontributions - Revue de l\'Enseignement Supeur en Afrique</s>
    <s>Delai : ouvert</s>
    <s>Appel andidatures</s>
    <s>Delai : 1 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel andidatures</s>
    <s>Delai : 15 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel andidatures- Institute for Advanced Study</s>
    <s>Delai : 1 novembre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel ropositions - Jewish Studies and Medieval Islam</s>
    <s>Delai : Ouvert</s>
    <s>Appel ontributions-Journal of Sufi Studies</s>
    <s>Delai : ouvert</s>
    <s>Appel ontributions - Limpact des rlutions en Afrique du Nord sur lAfrique sub-saharienne</s>
    <s>Delai : 31 juillet 2011</s>
    <s>Appel andidatures - Atelier modologique sous-ronal sur les sciences sociales en Afrique</s>
    <s>Delai : 05 ao11</s>
    <s>Appel ommunications - Les effets de la mondialisation sur le management des organisations</s>
    <s>Delai : 10 ao11</s>
    <s>Appel ommunications - Transformation of the Islamic Countries in the Middle East</s>
    <s>Delai : 14 aout 2011</s>
    <s>Appel ommunications - BISKRA ARCHITECTURE AND SUSTAINABILITY INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE 2011</s>
    <s>Delai : 15 ao11</s>
    <s>Appel andidatures - Session inaugurale de l\'Institut d\'udes afro-arabes</s>
    <s>Delai : 17 ao11</s>
    <s>Appel andidatures - International Scholarship Programme for Students from Tunisia and Egypt</s>
    <s>Delai : 01 septembre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel ommunications - 5th Annual International Conference on Mediterranean Studies</s>
    <s>Delai : 05 septembre 2011</s>
    <s>Date : 04/04/2012 - 05/04/2012</s>
    <s>« 5th Annual International Conference on Mediterranean Studies »</s>
    <s>&gt; 5th Annual International Conference on Mediterranean Studies, 4-7 April 2012, Athens, Greece</s>
    <s>Call for Papers and Participation</s>
    <s>The Athens Institute for Education and Research (ATINER) organizes its 5th Annual International Conference on Mediterranean Studies in Athens, Greece, 4-7 April 2012. The conference website is: www.atiner.gr/mediterranean.htm. Please submit an abstract (email only) to: atiner@atiner.gr, using the abstract submission form available at http://www.atiner.gr/docs/2012FORM-MDT.doc by the 5th of September 2011 to: Dr. Gregory A. Katsas, Academic Member of ATINER and Associate Professor, The American College of Greece-Deree College, Greece. Abstracts should include the following: Title of Paper, Full Name (s), Affiliation, Current Position, an email address, and at least 3 keywords that best describe the subject of your submission. Decisions are reached within 4 weeks. If you want to participate without presenting a paper, i.e. chair a session, review papers to be included in the conference proceedings or books, contribute to the editing of a book, or any other contribution, please send an email to Dr. Gregory T. Papanikos, Director, ATINER (gtp@atiner.gr).</s>
    <s>The aim of the conference is to bring together scholars, researchers and students from all areas of Mediterranean Studies, such as history, arts, archaeology, philosophy, culture, sociology, politics, international relations, economics, business, sports, etc. Panel organizers are encouraged to submit their proposals by inviting other scholars that do research in the same area. Specific sessions will be organized on (a) country studies for both the European and non-European countries of the Mediterranean Basin, (b) the environmental, ecological and biological issues of the Mediterranean Sea, and (c) the Mediterranean islands (history, arts, culture, and all aspects of development) such as Cyprus, Malta, Sicily, Sardinia, Corsica, Crete, Euboea, Majorca, Rhodes, Cyclades, Ionian, Dodecanese, etc. The registration fee is 250 euro, covering access to all sessions, two lunches, coffee breaks, and conference materials. Special arrangements will be made with a local luxury hotel for a limited number of rooms at a special conference rate. In addition, a number of special social events will be organized: an official dinner with Greek night of entertainment with dinner, an educational excursion to Delphi, a special one-day educational cruise to the Greek islands, and a half-day tour around the wider area of Athens (Attica), which includes the Acropolis Hill and Parthenon.</s>
    <s>The Athens Institute for Education and Research (ATINER) was established in 1995 as an independent academic organization, with the mission to become a forum, where academics and researchers - from all over the world - could meet in Athens to exchange ideas on their research and discuss the future developments of their discipline. Since 1995, ATINER has organized more than 150 international conferences and has published over 100 books. Academically, the Institute consists of four research divisions and nineteen research units. Each research unit organizes at least an annual conference and undertakes various small and large research projects.</s>
    <s>Appel ontributions - Ouvrage collectif sur la question des indépendances au Maghreb</s>
    <s>Delai : 10 septembre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel ommunications - Energy Resources: Europe and Its Former Colonies</s>
    <s>Delai : 15 septembre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel andidatures - Bourse Getty</s>
    <s>Delai : 23 septembre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel ommunications - Religious Architectural Heritage across the Mediterranean</s>
    <s>Delai : 30 septembre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel ommunications - Islamic Cities in the Eyes of European Travellers</s>
    <s>Delai : 01 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel andidatures - Franklin Research Grants</s>
    <s>Delai : 03 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel ommunications - Laten socis majoritairement musulmanes et musulmans</s>
    <s>Delai : 15 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel ommunications - Les langues dans lespace familial algen</s>
    <s>Delai : 15 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel andidatures -Research Fellowship on the History of Islamic Religions</s>
    <s>Delai : 15 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel ommunications - Les outils dapprentissage et lhabitude de lire et dire lamazigh</s>
    <s>Delai : 20 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel ommunications - Colloque annuel de AIMS</s>
    <s>Delai : 31 octobre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel andidatures -Graduate/Posdoc Fellowship, Cornell University</s>
    <s>Delai : 01 novembre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel andidatures - Campbell Fellowship for Women Scholar-Practitioners from Developing Nations</s>
    <s>Delai : 01 novembre 2011</s>
    <s>Appel ommunications - 5th Annual International Conference on Mediterranean Studies</s>
    <s>Delai : 31 dmbre 2011</s>
    <s>Activites scientifiques :</s>
    <s>Mai 2007</s>
    <s>Juin 2007</s>
    <s>Octobre 2007</s>
    <s>Novembre 2007</s>
    <s>Dmbre 2007</s>
    <s>Fier 2008</s>
    <s>Mars 2008</s>
    <s>Mai 2008</s>
    <s>Juin 2008</s>
    <s>Juillet 2008</s>
    <s>Octobre 2008</s>
    <s>Novembre 2008</s>
    <s>Dmbre 2008</s>
    <s>Janvier 2009</s>
    <s>Fier 2009</s>
    <s>Avril 2009</s>
    <s>Mai 2009</s>
    <s>Juillet 2009</s>
    <s>Octobre 2009</s>
    <s>Novembre 2009</s>
    <s>Janvier 2010</s>
    <s>Fier 2010</s>
    <s>Mars 2010</s>
    <s>Avril 2010</s>
    <s>Mai 2010</s>
    <s>Juin 2010</s>
    <s>Septembre 2010</s>
    <s>Novembre 2010</s>
    <s>Dmbre 2010</s>
    <s>Janvier 2011</s>
    <s>Fier 2011</s>
    <s>Mars 2011</s>
    <s>Avril 2011</s>
    <s>Mai 2011</s>
    <s>Juin 2011</s>
    <s>Juillet 2011</s>
    <s>Septembre 2011</s>
    <s>Octobre 2011</s>
    <s>Copyright CEMA (C) 2007</s>
    <s>Design By Nomade Solutions</s>
  </text>
</page>
