<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>fr</lang>  <url>http://www.ancl-radc.org.za/call-papers-lome</url>
  <title>Call for Papers: Lome Conference ** Appel à contribution Colloque ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Call for Papers: Lome Conference ** Appel à contribution Colloque International de Lomé ** Chamada de trabalhos Simpósio Internacional de Lomé </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Primary links</s>
    <s>About Us/Apropos</s>
    <s>Objectives/Les objectifs/Objectivos</s>
    <s>Organisational structure</s>
    <s>Join/Nous rejoindre</s>
    <s>Search for a member/rechercher un membre</s>
    <s>Working groups</s>
    <s>Access to Information</s>
    <s>Working group members</s>
    <s>Socio-economic rights in Africa</s>
    <s>Working group members</s>
    <s>Teaching Constitutional Law</s>
    <s>Working group members</s>
    <s>Women, equality and the Constitution</s>
    <s>Working group members</s>
    <s>Constitutional Judges</s>
    <s>Working group members</s>
    <s>Legal Clinicians</s>
    <s>African Constitutions</s>
    <s>Constitutional reviews</s>
    <s>Kenyan Constitutional Review</s>
    <s>Nigerian Constitutional Review</s>
    <s>African National courts</s>
    <s>General databases</s>
    <s>Courts' websites/sites des tribunaux</s>
    <s>African International courts and tribunals</s>
    <s>Online Journals/ Revues électroniques</s>
    <s>Case Law/Jurisprudence</s>
    <s>Teaching Constitutional Law</s>
    <s>News Archive</s>
    <s>Calls for papers/Appels à contributions</s>
    <s>Upcoming events/eventements venir</s>
    <s>Past events/evenements passes</s>
    <s>Search this site:</s>
    <s>Call for Papers: Lome Conference Appel à contribution Colloque International de Lomé Chamada de trabalhos Simpósio Internacional de Lomé</s>
    <s>News archive</s>
    <s>!lome.jpg Appel a communications: Colloque International de Lome les 13 et 14 Juin, 2011 «Le tabou du constitutionnalisme en Afrique» par le Centre pour le droit public (CDP) de l'Universite de Lome et CERDRADI - Universite Montesquieu GRECCAP - Bordeaux IV. Date limite: 31 Octobre 2010. Les propositions et les documents doivent etre en français seulement.</s>
    <s>Call for Papers : International Symposium Lome 13 and June 14, 2011 &quot;The Taboo of Constitutionalism in Africa&quot; by the Centre for Public Law (CDP) of the University of Lome and CERDRADI - GRECCAP University Montesquieu - Bordeaux IV. Deadline: 31 October 2010. Proposals and papers must be in French only.</s>
    <s>Call for Papers: Simposio Internacional de Lome, 13 e 14 de Junho de 2011 &quot;O Tabu do Constitucionalismo na África&quot; do Centro de Direito Publico (CDP) da Universidade de Lome e CERDRADI - GRECCAP Universidade Montesquieu - Bordeaux IV. Prazo: 31 de outubro de 2010. As propostas e os documentos devem estar em frances.</s>
    <s>International Symposium Lome 13 and June 14, 2011</s>
    <s>&quot;The taboo of constitutionalism in Africa&quot; Call for Papers Symposium organized by the Centre for Public Law (CDP) of the University of Lome and CERDRADI - GRECCAP University Montesquieu - Bordeaux IV. Scientific background: CDP and CERDRADI held on 16 and 17 June 2010 a symposium on &quot;Africa and the internationalization of constitutionalism: actress or spectator.&quot; This conference was an opportunity to make a first point on the African continent's place in the phenomenon of internationalization as values that mechanisms of constitutionalism.</s>
    <s>The papers and discussions that followed showed the limits in terms of effectiveness of constitutionalism inspired deemed essentially Western. It appeared that the current African constitutionalism was locked in a number of &quot;taboos&quot; that could partly or wholly explain the difficulties of its application to the African context.</s>
    <s>For information on the arguments that emerged, to inform your proposals, please download the Call for Papers in your home language below.</s>
    <s>You are invited to submit proposals for papers in French stating the title, issue, and not exceeding one page (approximately 300 words). These proposals will be sent before October 31, 2010 at the following addresses: adamakpodar@gmail.com, matthieu.fau-Nougaret@u-bordeaux4.fr, dodzikokoroko@gmail.com, alioune badara fall1@yahoo.fr Responses will be communicated to authors no later than December 1, 2010 and the complete text of the written submissions should be sent before May 15, 2010. The conference proceedings will be published</s>
    <s>Colloque international de Lome les 13 et 14 Juin, 2011 « Le tabou du constitutionnalisme en Afrique&quot; Appel a communications Colloque organise par le Centre de droit public (CDP) de l'Universite de Lome et CERDRADI - GRECCAP Universite Montesquieu - Bordeaux IV. Contexte scientifique: CDP et CERDRADI tenue les 16 et 17 Juin 2010, un colloque sur &quot;L'Afrique et l'internationalisation du constitutionnalisme:. Actrice ou un spectateur&quot; Cette conference a ete l'occasion de faire un premier point sur la place du continent africain dans le phenomene de l'internationalisation en tant que valeurs que les mecanismes du constitutionnalisme.</s>
    <s>Les documents et les discussions qui ont suivi ont montre les limites en termes d'efficacite du constitutionnalisme inspire consideres comme essentiellement occidentale. Il est apparu que le constitutionnalisme africain actuel a ete enferme dans un certain nombre de &quot;tabous&quot; qui pourraient expliquer partiellement ou totalement les difficultes de son application au contexte africain.</s>
    <s>Pour plus d'informations sur les arguments qui ont emerge, d'informer vos propositions, s'il vous plait telecharger l'appel a communications dans votre langue d'origine ci-dessous.</s>
    <s>Vous etes invites a soumettre des propositions de communications en français mentionnant le titre, l'emission, et ne depassant pas une page (environ 300 mots). Ces propositions seront envoyees avant Octobre 31, 2010 a l'adresse suivante: adamakpodar@gmail.com, matthieu.fau-Nougaret@u-bordeaux4.fr, dodzikokoroko@gmail.com, alioune badara fall1@yahoo.fr.</s>
    <s>Les reponses seront communiquees aux auteurs au plus tard le 1 Decembre 2010 et le texte complet des observations ecrites doivent etre envoyees avant le 15 mai 2010.</s>
    <s>Les actes du colloque seront publies</s>
    <s>Simposio Internacional de Lome, 13 e 14 junho de 2011 &quot;O tabu do constitucionalismo em África&quot; Call for Papers Coloquio organizado pelo Centro de Direito Publico (CDP) da Universidade de Lome e CERDRADI - GRECCAP Universidade Montesquieu - Bordeaux IV. Background cientifico: CDP e CERDRADI realizada em 16 e 17 de Junho de 2010, um simposio sobre &quot;África e da internacionalizaçao do constitucionalismo:. atriz ou espectador&quot; Esta conferencia foi uma oportunidade de fazer um primeiro ponto no lugar do continente Africano no fenomeno da internacionalizaçao como os valores que os mecanismos do constitucionalismo.</s>
    <s>Os artigos e discussoes que se seguiram mostraram os limites em termos de eficacia do constitucionalismo inspirado considerada essencialmente ocidental. Parecia que o constitucionalismo atual Africano foi trancado em uma serie de &quot;tabus&quot; que poderia explicar, em parte ou totalmente as dificuldades da sua aplicaçao ao contexto Africano.</s>
    <s>Para obter informaçoes sobre os argumentos que surgiram, para informar as suas propostas, faça o download do Call for Papers na sua lingua materna abaixo.</s>
    <s>Voce esta convidado a apresentar propostas para trabalhos em frances dizendo o titulo, assunto, e nao superior a uma pagina (aproximadamente 300 palavras). Nos convidamos os advogados, mas tambem antropologos, filosofos, sociologos e historiadores do direito de lance. Estas propostas serao enviadas ate 31 outubro de 2010, nos seguintes endereços: adamakpodar@gmail.com, alioune badara fall1@yahoo.fr matthieu.fau-Nougaret@u-bordeaux4.fr, dodzikokoroko@gmail.com.</s>
    <s>As respostas serao comunicados aos autores ate 01 de dezembro de 2010 eo texto completo dos documentos apresentados por escrito deverao ser enviados ate 15 de maio de 2010.</s>
    <s>As actas da conferencia serao publicadas</s>
    <s>!application/msword iconcall for papers international symposium lome 13 and june 14.doc</s>
    <s>!application/msword iconcall for papers simposio internacional de lome.doc</s>
    <s>!application/msword iconappel a contribution colloque international de lome 13 et 14 juin 20112.doc</s>
    <s>Copyright © 2011, ANCL-RADC. All Rights Reserved.</s>
  </text>
</page>
