<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>fr</lang>  <url>http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/iel5/9754/30804/01426040.pdf%3Farnumber%3D1426040</url>
  <title>“Illuminer notre avenir” APPEL DE COMMUNICATIONS</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>APPEL DE COMMUNICATIONS. Université de Regina. Secrétaire général. La Conférence Canadienne de génie électrique et informatique 2005 de l&#39;IEEE offre </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>Skip to MainContent</s>
    <s>IEEE.org | IEEE Xplore Digital Library | IEEE Standards Association | Spectrum Online | More IEEE Sites</s>
    <s>Delivering full text access to the world's highest quality technical literature in engineering and technology</s>
    <s>Journals &amp; Magazines</s>
    <s>Conference Proceedings</s>
    <s>Educational Courses</s>
    <s>My Settings</s>
    <s>Purchase History</s>
    <s>Saved Searches</s>
    <s>Sign In</s>
    <s>What can I access?</s>
    <s>About IEEE Xplore | Terms of Use | FeedbackHelp</s>
    <s>Sign In</s>
    <s>Here you can sign in to your guest, member or subscriber accounts.</s>
    <s>Sign In</s>
    <s>Forgot Password?</s>
    <s>Register for an IEEE Account</s>
    <s>!border top</s>
    <s>You have been redirected to this page for one of the following reasons:</s>
    <s>1. Either cookies are not enabled on your browser</s>
    <s>2. Your network configuration is causing cookies to be lost or not function properly.</s>
    <s>IEEE Xplore requires cookies to maintain sessions and to access licensed content. Cookies are used temporarily to maintain sessions in IEEE Xplore and for no other purpose. The cookies will not persist after a session ends.</s>
    <s>Please change your browser settings to accept cookies before you access IEEE Xplore . Here are some directions to enable cookies for a few commonly used browsers:</s>
    <s>Internet Explorer 6, 7, or 8</s>
    <s>Click Tools menu.</s>
    <s>Select Internet Options.</s>
    <s>Select Privacy tab.</s>
    <s>Click the Default button or slide the bar down to 'Medium'.</s>
    <s>Click Ok.</s>
    <s>For additional information, please refer to Microsoft Help and Support.</s>
    <s>Firefox 2 or 3</s>
    <s>Click Tools menu.</s>
    <s>Select Internet Options.</s>
    <s>Select Privacy tab.</s>
    <s>Select Use custom settings for history in the 'Firefox will:' dropdown v3.5 only</s>
    <s>Select the 'Accept cookies from sites' checkbox.</s>
    <s>Click Ok.</s>
    <s>For additional information, please refer to the Mozilla Firefox Knowledge Base.</s>
    <s>If you are accessing IEEE Xplore from a network that is not configured to accept cookies, please contact your network administrator. Proxy servers and other network appliances must be configured to accept cookies from the *ieee.org domain in order for you to use IEEE Xplore .</s>
    <s>Once you have enabled cookies, you may return to the previous page.</s>
    <s>If you have any questions, please contact onlinesupport@ieee.org.</s>
    <s>Contact Technical Support.</s>
    <s>!border top</s>
    <s>!Indexed by Inspec</s>
    <s>About IEEE Xplore | Help | Contact Us | Privacy &amp; Security | Site Map | IEEE.org | Nondiscrimination Policy | Terms of Use</s>
    <s>(C) Copyright 2011 IEEE - All Rights Reserved</s>
  </text>
</page>
