<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>fr</lang>  <url>http://complit.ca/ccla-2011-call-for-papers-appel-a-communications/</url>
  <title>Congress 2011 CALL FOR PAPERS / APPEL A COMMUNICATIONS</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>29 sept. 2010 Congress 2011 CALL FOR PAPERS / APPEL A COMMUNICATIONS. Comparative Literature from Coast to Coast / La littérature comparée </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>comité exécutif 2011-2013</s>
    <s>comité exécutif 2009-2011</s>
    <s>adhésion / membership</s>
    <s>links / liens</s>
    <s>mailing list subscription</s>
    <s>Congress 2011 CALL FOR PAPERS / APPEL A COMMUNICATIONS</s>
    <s>Comparative Literature from Coast to Coast / La littérature comparée d’une rive à l’autre</s>
    <s>On estime que plus de 70% du globe est recouvert par les océans, et pourtant c’est bien sa masse terrestre avec ses continents, nations et autres entités géopolitiques qui a été essentielle à la création de structures organisatrices pour l’étude des formes culturelles telles que la littérature, le cinéma et les arts.</s>
    <s>Pour cette conférence qui se déroulera sur le flanc Est canadien, nous invitons les comparatistes à repenser les principes fondateurs territoriaux de leur discipline. Afin de naviguer sur les mers houleuses en cette période de restructuration universitaire, les comparatistes sont encouragés à sonder en profondeur les multiples approches théoriques à leur disposition afin de reconfigurer la littérature comparée le long des lignes côtières.</s>
    <s>Les propositions en études comparées ainsi que les panels pré-organisés (regroupant 3 ou 4 panélistes) sont les bienvenus. Les sessions jointes avec une autre association sont également les bienvenues, mais devraient être organisées dès que possible.</s>
    <s>Merci de soumettre vos propositions de 250-300 mots (présentations de 20 minutes) à Susan Ingram, Présidente du comité organisateur (vp@complit.ca) avant le 15 décembre 2010.</s>
    <s>Veuillez noter que les conférenciers doivent être membres de l’ACLC à la date du Congrès. Les informations sur les modalités d¹adhésion à l¹association sont disponibles sur notre site:</s>
    <s>En 2011, le Congrès des Sciences Humaines “Rivages et continents: exploration des peuples et des lieux” se tiendra à Fredericton du 28 mai au 4 juin. Pour plus d’informations, visiter:http://www.fedcan.ca/congress2011/</s>
    <s>Over 70% of the world’s surface may be covered by water, but it is its land mass, divided into continents, nations, and other geopolitical entities, that has proven determinative in providing the organizing structures for the study of cultural forms like literature, film, and the arts.</s>
    <s>For this conference on Canada’s eastern seaboard, we invite Comparatists to rethink their discipline’s founding territorial principles. In order to navigate the turbulent seas ensuing from the current period of academic restructuring, Comparatists are encouraged to plumb the depths of the myriad theoretical approaches at their disposal and reconfigure Comparative Literature along coastal lines.</s>
    <s>Comparative papers on all topics are welcome, as are pre-arranged panels (of 3 or 4 panelists), roundtables and innovative formats. Joint sessions with other associations are also welcome but should be arranged as soon as possible.</s>
    <s>Please submit 250 – 300 word abstracts for 20-minute presentations to Program Chair Susan Ingram (vp@complit.ca) by December 15, 2010.</s>
    <s>*Please note that presenters must be members of the CCLA by the time of Congress. Information about membership is available at: http://complit.ca/adhesion-membership.</s>
    <s>In 2011, the Congress of the Humanities and Social Sciences “Coasts and Continents: Exploring Peoples and Places” will take place in Fredericton from 28 May to 4 June. For more information please visit: http://www.fedcan.ca/congress2011/.</s>
    <s>CfP: Philosophy and Kafka</s>
    <s>Tenure-stream appointment: European Studies: Twentieth Century Continental Thought</s>
    <s>Post Details</s>
    <s>September 29th, 2010</s>
    <s>Call for Papers, Congress, General</s>
    <s>Post Tags</s>
    <s>Copyright (C) 2011 CCLA | ACLC.</s>
  </text>
</page>
