<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "page.dtd">
<page>
  <lang>pt</lang>  <url>http://osdir.com/ml/debian-www-debian/2010-12/msg00117.html</url>
  <title>debian-www-debian - CISTI&#39;2011 - Chamada de Artigos / Llamada ...</title>
  <snippet>
    <s>Subject: CISTI&#39;2011 - Chamada de Artigos / Llamada de artículos - msg#00117 trabalhos à CISTI&#39;2011 (6ª Conferência Ibérica de Sistemas e Tecnologias de </s>
  </snippet>
  <text>
    <s>mailing list archive F.A.Q. -since 2001!</s>
    <s>Subject: CISTI'2011 - Chamada de Artigos / Llamada de</s>
    <s>articulos - msg00117</s>
    <s>List: debian-www-debian</s>
    <s>Mail Archive Navigation:</s>
    <s>by Date: Prev Next Date Index by Thread: Prev Next Thread Index</s>
    <s>PORTUGUÊS / ESPANHOL</s>
    <s>CISTI'2011 *</s>
    <s>6ª Conferencia Iberica de Sistemas e Tecnologias de Informaçao</s>
    <s>15 - 18 de Junho de 2011, Chaves, Portugal</s>
    <s>É com satisfaçao que convidamos a comunidade academica e empresarial a submeter</s>
    <s>trabalhos a CISTI'2011 (6ª Conferencia Iberica de Sistemas e Tecnologias de</s>
    <s>Informaçao: http://www.aisti.eu/cisti2011), a realizar em Chaves, entre 15 e 18</s>
    <s>de Junho de 2011. Os autores poderao submeter artigos cientificos originais</s>
    <s>abordando revisoes do estado da arte e novas perspectivas de investigaçao,</s>
    <s>ideias e/ou arquitecturas inovadoras, soluçoes e/ou aplicaçoes para problemas</s>
    <s>reais, trabalhos empiricos e/ou de avaliaçao, estudos de caso, etc., que se</s>
    <s>enquadrem nas tematicas da conferencia.</s>
    <s>Poderao ser submetidos tres tipos de artigos:</s>
    <s>Artigo (Full paper): Trabalhos concluidos ou consolidados sobre I&amp;D</s>
    <s>realizada numa das tematicas da conferencia. Estes artigos terao um limite</s>
    <s>maximo de 6 paginas.</s>
    <s>Artigo Curto (Short Paper): Trabalhos em curso, mas com resultados</s>
    <s>preliminares relevantes a serem discutidos. Estes artigos terao um limite</s>
    <s>maximo de 4 paginas.</s>
    <s>Poster: Trabalhos iniciais, mas com ideias relevantes a serem discutidas.</s>
    <s>Estes artigos terao o limite maximo de 2 paginas.</s>
    <s>No texto do artigo para avaliaçao pela Comissao Cientifica nao deverao ser</s>
    <s>incluidas informaçoes que possibilitem a identificaçao dos autores. Assim,</s>
    <s>nomes, afiliaçoes e referencias bibliograficas dos mesmos nao deverao aparecer</s>
    <s>na versao inicial. Essas informaçoes deverao ser incluidas somente na versao</s>
    <s>final do artigo.</s>
    <s>Os artigos submetidos nao devem estar publicados nem sob revisao para nenhuma</s>
    <s>outra conferencia ou publicaçao nacional ou internacional.</s>
    <s>Todos os artigos devem seguir as normas de formataçao</s>
    <s>(http://www.aisti.eu/cisti2011/papersformat.dot), estar gravados no formato</s>
    <s>PDF, e escritos em portugues, espanhol ou ingles.</s>
    <s>Todos os artigos serao objecto de ?blind review? por, pelo menos, dois</s>
    <s>elementos da Comissao Cientifica.</s>
    <s>Alguns dos artigos (full papers) poderao vir a ser aceites somente como artigos</s>
    <s>curtos (short papers) ou posters. Similarmente, alguns dos artigos curtos</s>
    <s>(short papers) poderao vir a ser aceites somente como posters. Nestes casos os</s>
    <s>artigos poderao manter para publicaçao nas actas o numero de paginas inicial.</s>
    <s>Os autores de artigos aceites como poster devem preparar e imprimir um poster</s>
    <s>para exposiçao na conferencia. O poster devera ter orientaçao vertical e</s>
    <s>tamanho A1 ou A2. A conferencia dispoe de sessoes de trabalho para apresentaçao</s>
    <s>e discusao oral dos posters.</s>
    <s>Os artigos a submeter deverao enquadrar-se nas grandes tematicas propostas:</s>
    <s>A) Organizational Models and Information Systems</s>
    <s>(Modelos Organizacionais e Sistemas de Informaçao)</s>
    <s>B) Knowledge Management and Decision Support Systems</s>
    <s>(Gestao de Conhecimento e Sistemas de Suporte a Decisao)</s>
    <s>C) Software Systems, Architectures, Applications and Tools</s>
    <s>(Sistemas, Arquitecturas, Aplicaçoes e Ferramentas de Software)</s>
    <s>D) Computer Networks, Mobility and Pervasive Systems</s>
    <s>(Redes de Computadores, Mobilidade e Sistemas Ubiquos)</s>
    <s>E) Human Centered Computing</s>
    <s>(Informatica Centrada no Utilizador)</s>
    <s>F) Health Informatics</s>
    <s>(Informatica de Saude)</s>
    <s>G) Information Technologies in Education</s>
    <s>(Tecnologias da Informaçao na Educaçao)</s>
    <s>Publicaçao e Indexaçao:</s>
    <s>Para garantir a publicaçao de um artigo (artigo, artigo curto ou poster) nas</s>
    <s>actas, pelo menos um dos autores tera de se inscrever na conferencia ate 8 de</s>
    <s>Abril e o artigo respeitar o formato sugerido e nao exceder o numero maximo de</s>
    <s>paginas previsto. Adicionalmente, os autores de trabalhos que recebam</s>
    <s>recomendaçoes de alteraçao do artigo, deverao seguir as mesmas, antes do envio</s>
    <s>da versao final.</s>
    <s>Por cada inscriçao nao sera publicado mais do que um artigo nas actas. Para</s>
    <s>publicaçao de artigos adicionais sera necessario o pagamento de uma taxa extra</s>
    <s>por cada artigo.</s>
    <s>Os artigos (full papers) serao publicados em livro e em CD com ISBN. Os artigos</s>
    <s>curtos (short papers) e os posters serao publicados somente em CD com ISBN.</s>
    <s>Os artigos (full papers) publicados serao enviados para o ISI, XPlore do IEEE e</s>
    <s>EBSCO. Os artigos curtos (short papers) publicados serao enviados para a XPlore</s>
    <s>do IEEE e para a EBSCO. Os artigos poster serao enviados somente para a EBSCO.</s>
    <s>Os autores dos melhores artigos seleccionados serao convidados a estende-los</s>
    <s>para publicaçao na RISTI (Revista Iberica de Sistemas e Tecnologias de</s>
    <s>Informaçao) e noutras publicaçoes do espaço iberico que venham a</s>
    <s>disponibilizar-se para isso.</s>
    <s>Contamos consigo. Faça-nos chegar o seu contributo.</s>
    <s>6ª Conferencia Iberica de Sistemas y Tecnologias de Informacion</s>
    <s>15 - 18 de Junio de 2011, Chaves, Portugal</s>
    <s>Nos satisface invitar a la comunidad academica y empresarial a presentar</s>
    <s>trabajos a la CISTI'2011 (6ª Conferencia Iberica de Sistemas y Tecnologias de</s>
    <s>Informacion: http://www.aisti.eu/cisti2011), a celebrar en Chaves, Portugal,</s>
    <s>entre el 15 y 18 de Junio de 2011, enviando articulos cientificos originales</s>
    <s>sobre ideas innovadoras, soluciones desarrolladas que aborden problemas reales,</s>
    <s>trabajos empiricos, estudios de caso, etc., en el dominio de los sistemas y</s>
    <s>tecnologias de la informacion, que se encuadren en las tematicas de la</s>
    <s>Podran ser enviados tres tipos de articulos:</s>
    <s>Articulo: Trabajos concluidos o consolidados sobre I+D encuadrados en una</s>
    <s>de las tematicas de la conferencia. Estos articulos tendran un limite maximo de</s>
    <s>6 paginas.</s>
    <s>Articulo Corto: Trabajos en curso, pero con resultados preliminares</s>
    <s>relevantes para ser discutidos. Estos articulos tendran un limite maximo de 4</s>
    <s>Poster: Trabajos iniciados pero con ideas relevantes para ser discutidas.</s>
    <s>Estos trabajos tendran un limite maximo de 2 paginas.</s>
    <s>En el texto del articulo para evaluacion por la Comision Cientifica no deberan</s>
    <s>incluirse informacion que posibilite la identificacion de los autores. De este</s>
    <s>modo, sus filiaciones y referencias bibliograficas no deberan aparecer en el</s>
    <s>version inicial. Esta informacion solamente se incluira en la version final del</s>
    <s>Los articulos enviados no deben estar publicados ni sobre revision en ninguna</s>
    <s>otra conferencia o publicacion nacional o internacional.</s>
    <s>Todos los articulos deben seguir las normas de formato</s>
    <s>(http://www.aisti.eu/cisti2011/papersformat.dot), estar guardados en formato</s>
    <s>PDF, y escritos en portugues, español o ingles.</s>
    <s>Todos los articulos seran objeto de ?blind review? por lo menos por dos</s>
    <s>miembros de la comision cientifica.</s>
    <s>Algunos de los articulos (full papers) pueden ser aceptados como articulos</s>
    <s>cortos (short papers) o posters. Del mismo modo, algunos de los articulos</s>
    <s>cortos (short papers) pueden ser aceptados como posters. En estos casos, los</s>
    <s>articulos podran mantener, para su publicacion en las actas, el numero de</s>
    <s>paginas iniciales.</s>
    <s>Los autores de trabajos aceptados como poster deben preparar e imprimir un</s>
    <s>poster para su exhibicion en la conferencia. El poster debe tener una</s>
    <s>orientacion vertical y tamaño A1 o A2. La conferencia ofrece sesiones de</s>
    <s>trabajo para la presentacion y discusion oral de posters.</s>
    <s>Los articulos enviados deberan encuadrarse en las grandes tematicas propuestas:</s>
    <s>A) Organizational Models and Information Systems</s>
    <s>(Modelos Organizacionales y Sistemas de Informacion)</s>
    <s>B) Knowledge Management and Decision Support Systems</s>
    <s>(Gestion de Conocimiento y Sistemas de Apoyo a la Decision).</s>
    <s>C) Software Systems, Architectures, Applications and Tools</s>
    <s>(Sistemas, Arquitecturas, Aplicaciones y Herramientas de Software)</s>
    <s>D) Computer Networks, Mobility and Pervasive Systems</s>
    <s>(Redes de Computadores, Movilidad y Sistemas Ubicuos)</s>
    <s>E) Human Centered Computing</s>
    <s>(Informatica Centrada em Usuario)</s>
    <s>F) Health Informatics</s>
    <s>(Informatica en la Salud)</s>
    <s>G) Information Technologies in Education</s>
    <s>(Tecnologia de la Informacion en la Educacion)</s>
    <s>Publicacion y Indexacion:</s>
    <s>Para garantizar la publicacion de un articulo (articulo, articulo corto o</s>
    <s>poster) en las actas, por lo menos un autor debe inscribirse en la conferencia</s>
    <s>hasta el 08 de Abril y que el articulo respete el formato sugerido y no exceda</s>
    <s>el numero maximo de paginas previsto. Adicionalmente, los autores de trabajos</s>
    <s>que reciban recomendaciones de alteracion del articulo, deberan seguir las</s>
    <s>mismas antes del envio de la version final.</s>
    <s>Para cada inscripcion no se publica mas de un articulo en las actas. Para la</s>
    <s>publicacion de articulos adicionales el autor debera pagar un suplemento por</s>
    <s>cada articulo.</s>
    <s>Los articulos (full papers) seran publicados en libro y en CD con ISBN. Los</s>
    <s>articulos cortos (short papers) y los posters se publicaran unicamente en CD</s>
    <s>con ISBN.</s>
    <s>Los articulos (full papers) publicados seran enviados a el ISI, XPlore del IEEE</s>
    <s>y EBSCO. Los articulos cortos (short papers) publicados seran enviados a la</s>
    <s>Xplore del IEEE y EBSCO. Los posters seran enviados unicamente a la EBSCO.</s>
    <s>Los autores de los mejores articulos seleccionados seran invitados a extender</s>
    <s>su articulo para su publicacion en la RISTI (Revista Iberica de Sistemas y</s>
    <s>Tecnologias de la Informacion) y en otras publicaciones del espacio iberico que</s>
    <s>esten dispuestas a ello.</s>
    <s>Contamos con usted. Haganos llegar su contribucion.</s>
    <s>Regards / Saludos / Saudaçoes,</s>
    <s>-- Si no desea recibir mensajes de la CISTI o de la AISTI, por favor vaya a</s>
    <s>http://www.aisti.eu, ponga su direccion de correo electronico en el Newsletter</s>
    <s>y elija Desuscribirse.</s>
    <s>-- Se nao pretender receber mais mensagens da CISTI ou da AISTI, por favor</s>
    <s>aceda a http://www.aisti.eu e na secçao Newsletter coloque o seu endereço de</s>
    <s>e-mail e escolha a opçao Cancelar.</s>
    <s>To UNSUBSCRIBE, email to debian-www-REQUEST@xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx</s>
    <s>with a subject of &quot;unsubscribe&quot;. Trouble? Contact listmaster@xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx</s>
    <s>Archive: http://lists.debian.org/20101221002902.939BD13A5A16@xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx</s>
    <s>Thread at a glance:</s>
    <s>Previous Message by Date:</s>
    <s>[rt.debian.org 2672 AutoReply CC: Debian RT : extending and merging {merchandise,events}@d.o]</s>
    <s>A new trouble ticket, a summary of which appears below the dashed line, regarding &quot;Debian RT : extending and merging {merchandise,events}@d.o&quot;, has been created and the Requestor set you as a CC, which is why you are receiving this autoreply-on-ticket-creation message. In case you reply to this mail, please include the following string in the subject line (excluding quotation marks): rt.debian.org 2672 ------------------------------------------------------------------------- Dear DSA, following a discussion who dates back to DebConf10 and which has been completed recently, I hereby ask you to add Luca Capello and Francesca Ciceri to the events@xxx mail alias. The complete list of recipients after the addition should look like: - Alexander Reichle-Schmehl &lt;alexander@xxxxxxxxxxxx&gt; - Francesca Ciceri &lt;madamezou@xxxxxxxx&gt; - Luca Capello &lt;gismo@xxxxxxxxxx&gt; - Martin Schulze &lt;joey@xxxxxxxxxx&gt; - Meike Richle &lt;meike@xxxxxxxxxx&gt; According to the same initiative, please also make merchandise@xxx point to events@xxx (and just for some sort of, hopefully temporary, backward compatibility). Once implemented, I'll check with the above people on board to update the corresponding documentation (at least /intro/organization and /misc/merchandise). Many thanks in advance, Cheers. -- Stefano Zacchiroli -o- PhD in Computer Science \ PostDoc @ Univ. Paris 7 zack@{upsilon.cc,pps.jussieu.fr,debian.org} -&lt;&gt;- http://upsilon.cc/zack/ Quando anche i santi ti voltano le spalle, | . |. I've fans everywhere ti resta John Fante -- V. Capossela .| ..: | . -- C. Adams -- To UNSUBSCRIBE, email to debian-www-REQUEST@xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx with a subject of &quot;unsubscribe&quot;. Trouble? Contact listmaster@xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx Archive: http://lists.debian.org/rt-3.8.8-26949-1292868983-1785.2672-17-0@xxxxxxxxxx</s>
    <s>Next Message by Date:</s>
    <s>Conferma cancellazione dalla lista Microbiologia (SIM)</s>
    <s>Salve debian-www@xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx , Ti sei cancellato dalla lista Microbiologia (SIM)Se vuoi reiscriverti</s>
    <s>Previous Message by Thread:</s>
    <s>Debian RT : extending and merging {merchandise,events}@d.o</s>
    <s>Dear DSA, following a discussion who dates back to DebConf10 and which has been completed recently, I hereby ask you to add Luca Capello and Francesca Ciceri to the events@xxx mail alias. The complete list of recipients after the addition should look like: - Alexander Reichle-Schmehl &lt;alexander@xxxxxxxxxxxx&gt; - Francesca Ciceri &lt;madamezou@xxxxxxxx&gt; - Luca Capello &lt;gismo@xxxxxxxxxx&gt; - Martin Schulze &lt;joey@xxxxxxxxxx&gt; - Meike Richle &lt;meike@xxxxxxxxxx&gt; According to the same initiative, please also make merchandise@xxx point to events@xxx (and just for some sort of, hopefully temporary, backward compatibility). Once implemented, I'll check with the above people on board to update the corresponding documentation (at least /intro/organization and /misc/merchandise). Many thanks in advance, Cheers. -- Stefano Zacchiroli -o- PhD in Computer Science \ PostDoc @ Univ. Paris 7 zack@{upsilon.cc,pps.jussieu.fr,debian.org} -&lt;&gt;- http://upsilon.cc/zack/ Quando anche i santi ti voltano le spalle, | . |. I've fans everywhere ti resta John Fante -- V. Capossela .| ..: | . -- C. Adams signature.asc Description: Digital signature</s>
    <s>Next Message by Thread:</s>
    <s>A Good Opportunity for You to Win China SSL Market</s>
    <s>The unique and the most influential international event in China:Green Lighting Shanghai is dedicated to developing the applications of new lighting technology including LED and the combination of new lighting technology and new energy With improvement of living standard in China, and people's higher awareness of energy saving and environment protection, Chinese government has put much efforts trying to reduce carbon emission; and because the lighting technology has got great breakthrough, China has now generated a big market for new luminaire, especially LED products with application of clean and sustainable energy. If you manufacture or distribute these products, no matter if you have a presence in China or simply observe the China Market, then Green Lighting Shanghai is definitely the right event to visit. Green Light Shanghai will provide you informative and effective first-hand knowledge of the China market. This will enhance business opportunities, set up new market orientation, introduce potential accounts, and brand your products in a huge, and growing, market. Green Lighting Shanghai is co-hosted by China Solid State Lighting Alliance (CSA) and Reed Exhibitions. Initiated in 2007, Green lighting Shanghai has been successfully organized for 4 years. AndGreen Lighting Shanghai 2011 will be held in Shanghai, China from May 11 to 13, 2011. Green Lighting Shanghai is an event consisting of both exhibition and forum. It is the unique and the most influential international event in China which is dedicated to developing the applications of new lighting technology including LED and the combination of new lighting technology and new energy. The forum is set to stimulate information exchange on practical technology and products of green lighting and renewable energy; and on the exhibition, Green Lighting Shanghai displays a variety of manufacturing equipment, materials, and products from all kinds of application fields from China and abroad. Green Lighting Shanghai 2010 successfully attracted 4,665 professional exhibition visitors and 787 forum participants from government departments, associations, universities, institutes and companies. Through 4 yeas' continuous efforts, Green Lighting Shanghai also gains active and close support and cooperation form world leading LED companies, such as AIXTRON, Veeco, Cree, Philips Lighting, Philips Lumileds, OSRAM, GE, Seoul Semiconductor, NICHIA, TOYODA GOSEI, Epistar, ASTRI,The Climate Group and so on. With the SSL industry expanding rapidly, now is a time of great opportunity to seize more market share. CSA calls for your support and cooperation to this event to benefit both of us as well as lighting industry. Note: registration for Green Lighting Shanghai 2011 by January 31, 2011 will get 30% discount. If you are interested in detailed information about Green Lighting Shanghai 2011, you are welcome to contact: Betty Xu, Jeff Chang, Tina Wu Tel: 86-10-51727115 Fax:86-10- 82512803 E-mailixuny@xxxxxxxxxxxxx changjj@xxxxxxxxxxxxx wuqian@xxxxxxxxxxxxx</s>
    <s>Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. blog comments powered by Disqus</s>
    <s>Home | News | Sitemap | FAQ | advertise | OSDir is an Inevitable website. GBiz &amp; git.net are too</s>
    <s>Recent Msgs:</s>
  </text>
</page>
